<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
<collection-meta collection-type="conf">
<conference content-type="conf-name"><conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name><conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym></conference>
<conference content-type="conf-other-meta"><conf-date content-type="start">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-date content-type="end">
<day>19</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-loc>Nevada, 
<country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc></conference></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
<title-group>
<title>VLSI-based SLMs</title>
<alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/></title-group></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
<title-group>
<title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title></title-group>
<volume-in-collection>
<volume-number>14</volume-number>
<volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title></volume-in-collection></collection-meta>
<book-meta>
<book-title-group>
<book-title>Spatial Light Modulators</book-title></book-title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Burdge</surname><given-names>Geoffrey</given-names></name></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>Sadik C.</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group>
<pub-date publication-format="electronic">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></pub-date></book-meta>
<book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
<book-part-meta>
<title-group>
<title>Large Format GaAs Based Spatial Light Modulators and Their use in Optical Correlation Applications</title></title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Trezza</surname><given-names>J. A.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Stack</surname><given-names>R. D.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Powell</surname><given-names>J. S.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<aff id="aff1">
<label>1</label>Electro-Optics Group Sanders, A Lockheed Martin Co.NHQ6-1551, 65 Spit Brook Road, Nashua, NH 03060</aff></contrib-group>
<elocation-id>11</elocation-id>
<permissions>
<copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
<copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
<copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
<license license-type="open-access">
<license-p>closed</license-p></license></permissions>
<abstract>
<p>Spatial light modulators using GaAs asymmetric Fabry-Perot vertical cavity modulators have been demonstrated in large format devices. The experimental devices have been extensively characterized. Simulations have been performed which examine both single pixel and array responses. Arrays with improved dynamic range and reduced operating voltages have been designed. The experimental devices have been used to perform optical correlation as well as other system applications. Additional uses for the pixels include detection, phase modulation. directional modulation, and light-emitting capability. Our latest designs allow high-speed gray-scale array implementation.</p></abstract>
<kwd-group kwd-group-type="OCIS">
<title>OCIS codes</title>
<kwd>Spatial Light Modulators</kwd>
<kwd>Quantum Well Devices</kwd>
<kwd>Electro-optical Devices</kwd>
<kwd>Optoelectronics</kwd></kwd-group>
<counts>
<book-page-count count="7"/></counts></book-part-meta>
<body>
<p>Introduction Spatial light modulators (SLMs) are the key component for real-time electro-optical signal processing, computing, optical memory storage, free-space optical interconnect, information processing, laser printing, and data conversion systems. We have used a proprietary process to develop the world's largest format, highest performance, close pixel (&gt;909r fill factor) GaAs quantum-well vertical cavity SLM arrays bump-bonded to silicon CMOS. The SLMs consist of a pixelated GaAs optical chip which is lip-chip indium bump-bonded to a Si driver chip, forming an integrated hybrid module. Each optical pixel receives independent data directly from the supporting pixelated driver chip. enabling display properties to change at any moment. Our flip-chip bonding technology has been used to connect pixelated GaAs devices to silicon drivers on chips over 2 square centimeters in size; which contain as many as 300.000 pixels with pixel yields of 99.987. We have used our SLM technology to develop several optical processing and data routing demonstration units, including beam steering units and optical correlators. Using interconnected SLM modules, correlations can be performed at a maximum rate of 1.200.000 128 x 128 binary two dimensional (2-D) correlations per second.</p>
<p>Vertical Cavity Modulators The optical portion of the SLM consists an array of vertical cavity modulator structures. These structures incorporate quantum wells in the cavity region of what forms an optical Fabry-Perot cavity. Electrically, the device is constructed as a p-i-n diode; 100A GaAs/ 50A AlGaAs quantum wells reside in the intrinsic region of this diode. The cavity employs top mirrors composed of quarter wave dielectric stacks and bottom mirrors which are either purely metallic or a combination of metallic and dielectric mirrors. If the diode is forward biased, current is injected into the quantum wells and the device emits light--i.e. it acts as an LED. Figure1 displays a 128 x 128 SLM operating in an LED mode at 860nm. Conversely, by reverse biasing the diode, the quantum well exciton absorptive and dispersive properties are altered at the Fabry-Perot resonance wavelength. This allows modulation and/or detection. In devices which use single, independent quantum wells, chanes in absorption and dispersion with reverse bias are mediated by the quantum confined Stark effect.&#x0005B;I&#x0005D; In more complicated quantum well structures, oscillator strength modulation &#x0005B;2&#x0005D; can be used. The latter is particularly useful for modulation below 3 volts. Figure 1. 128 x 128 SLM operating in LED mode (no incident laserlightispresent). As the quantum well changes its absorption/dispersion with bias, the modulators alter their reflected intensity, their reflected transmission, and/or their reflected phase. Devices which switch only reflected phases &#x0005B;3&#x0005D; are extremely useful for beamsteering applications&#x0005B;4,5&#x0005D;. Pixels which switch from primarily reflective to primarily transmissiveabsorbverylittlelightineitherstate. Such pixels (which are a subset of so called X-modulators) providethelowestpower, highestspeedoptoelectrome switching elements available&#x0005B;6&#x0005D;. The simplest and most widely used types of pixels, however, are ones that alter between highly reflective and highly absorptive states. Such pixels can simultaneously act as intensity modulators andasdetectors--makingthemidealpixelsforoptical transcievers as only one type of optical element need be used. Since the major economic bottleneck for optoelectronic systems which use hybridized GaAs and silicon wafers is the labor cost of bump bonding individual chips together and packaging the final chips with high yield. Such a combination device is extremely attractive as only one hybridization step is necessary. This advantage is potentially enhanced when the optical pixels can also be used as light emitting (LED) pixels. This combination pixel--one that with one structure can act as either modulator, detector, or LED-- is the one we have chosen to integrate with silicon CMOS to create large pixelated SLM arrays. The properties of each pixel at any given time are determined by the data sent to a CMOS driver chip. The GaAs modulators are currently operated at wavelengths of either 855 or 860 nm (or both) with single pixel reflectivity changes from 0.43eo 7 to 0.03e 2 at 860 nm and 0.4eo 2 to 0.04e 3 at 855 nm (thus our contrast ratio is 10:1). The optical chips operate optimally with a 9-V applied bias. Defect-free 256 x 256 arrays draw a total of about 3 mA. In arrays with two or three 'bad' pixels these pixels typically draw the majority of device current; this creates arrays with total current draw of 30 mA. (which still corresponds to far less than I microamp per pixel). In our typical devices, modulation occurs zer before appiedbitematchixelexhiitmaiumreflcthaity.ero the matching condition, meaning that with annlied hias, each nixel exhibits maximum reflectivity. &#x0005B;71</p>
<p>GaAs SLM Technology The GaAs optical and silicon driver chips are combined by placing indium bumps on the chips and then using these bumps as points of contact to both electrically and mechanically connect these chips. The hybrid chip is then sealed for further mechanical stability, wirebonded into a standard IC package, and epoxy potted to form a robust product. Pixelated, GaAs based spatial light modulators have beenmadebyLockheed-Martinforseveralyearsinboth 1-D and 2-D formats&#x0005B;8&#x0005D;. Recently, 2-D SLMs with as large as 256 x 256 close packed pixels (&gt;90&#x00025; fill factor) havebeencreatedanddemonstratedatSanders.These devices have maximum allowable input data rates of 10 gigabits/sec and maximum frame rates (all pixels updated) of 312,500 frames/sec using the current 40 MHz capable silicondrivers.Turnonandturnofftimesforthearrayare approximately200ns. The CMOS driver circuitry for these 2-D devices allows one of two voltages to be placed oneachpixelatanyparticulartime. Thusthesedevices fundamentally operate in a binary (black and white) mode. Withspeedsofover312,500frames/second,however, gray-scale operation can be obtained by time-slicing a frame intovarious time segments. Forexample, by switchinatourmaximumframerate,8bitgrayscale(256 level) frames can be produced at rates of 1,220 frames/second (1,220 = 312,500 / 256). We note that the optical pixels themselves are capable of speeds on the order of 10's ofGigahertz (limited by RC charging times) while the underlyingphysicalmechanismoftheoptical modulation occurs on time scales ofpicoseconds&#x0005B;9&#x0005D;. Thus current SLM speeds are CMOS speed limited; as CMOS technology improves, the GaAs chips will be able toeasilyaccommodatethesespeedimprovements. Figure 2. SLM operating in time-sliced Gray scale mode Nevertheless, time slicing is not the only method we employtoachievegrayscaleoperation. One-dimensional (1-D)SLMs,withamaximumof2048pixelshavebeen created. These SLMshavebeenmade with digital-to- aalo (D/A) cvts lae on the ith iel. To anlgDAcovresoatdnhiptoecpxl date, all of the 1-D SLMs created and demonstrated are capable of 6 bits of gray scale on each pixel. By integrating D/A converters to produce gray scale, instead of using time slicing, frame rates can be substantially higher. This is clear since the volume of data required for each pixel per frame is logN instead of N, where 'N' is the number of gray scale levels available. Because the devices are CMOS limited, by requiring less data to be loaded, frame rates can be higher. Device pixel pitch is currently 40 microns for the 2-D devices (38 microns pixel width) and 8 microns (6 micron width) for our lx2048 1-D devices. Fig. 3 shows an integrated 2-D SLM package, close up of the optical chip, and a photo of the module displaying data. Within the SLM. the electronic driver chip consists of a custom, &#x0201C;mixed signal&#x0201D; silicon ASIC. In the 2-D devices, all of the relevant drive circuitry for an individual pixel is located in the CMOS chip below that pixel. In the 1-D arrays, the driver and relevant D/A circuitry are located both below and beyond the edges of the optical part of the chip. Figure 3. 2-D SLM (a) hybridized/packaged module on circuit board with integrated PC interface and on-board memory. (b) Close up of bump-bonded chip, and (c) infrared image (860 nm) of SLM operation.</p>
<p>SLM Design Extensive simulations have been used to improve SLM designs. As shown in Fig. 4, the baseline experimental chips have a maximum change in reflectivity of around 40&#x00025;. However, with improved quantum well and Fabry- Perot cavity design in our next generation arrays, we can easily achieve large arrays with near 70&#x00025; reflectivity change. At the same time, we can reduce voltages from 9 to 3.3 V. Single pixels have been experimentally demonstrated with reflectivity changes over 90&#x00025;, contrast ratios over 100 (where contrast ratio is defined as Ro/Rff), and applied bias of 3 volts. The simulation software takes into account the complex refractive index (absorption and dispersion) of all epitaxial layers. In addition, it uses semi-empirical models to incorporate the complex refractive index of quantum- well excitons in the simulation. This program has been routinely used to design and accurately predict performance to within 1&#x00025;. In addition to reflectivity changes, we have been using the simulation tools to predict phase behavior of our devices. Such phase distortions during operation can have significant, adverse effects on coherent light optical signal processors such as correlators. Figure 4. Change in reflectivity vs. wavelength for (a) current experimental and (b) simulated improved array. In general, GaAs based SLM design must account for operating voltage, optical bandwidth, maximum on-state reflectivity, optical contrast ratio, and optical bandwidth (wavelength range over which modulation is achieved). By using our simulations, parameter space plots can be made for designs that use our various processing techniques. In this way, tradeoffs in device operation can be made when choosing a modulator design for a particular application. Fig. 5a shows a parameter space plot for a variety of modulator designs; all of which have a contrast ratio (on state reflectivity/off state reflectivity) of 10 or better. The plot then shows the different designs that could be accomplished--giving the tradeoffs in maximum on-state reflectivity and optical bandwidths for various required operating voltages. For example, this plot shows that using the 'standard' processing technique and 100 angstrom quantum wells at 860nm, a modulator could be made which require 5 volts to operate and which would provide a contrast ratio of 10, a maximum reflectivity of 50&#x00025; and an optical bandwidth of 5.6nm. Note that performance beyond that shown in these plots is possible with further design refinement. Recall that single pixel devices with reflectivity changes greater than 90&#x00025; have been achieved&#x0005B;10&#x0005D;. (a) Figure 5. Paramter space plot for devices with (a) contrast ratios &gt; 10and (b)slightlymodifiedcavityandcontrastratios&gt;5</p>
<p>Correlation, Modeling, and Relevant Setups To create a multi-SLM-based optical processor, we have developed modular external printed circuit board (PCB) control hardware that interfaces the SLMs to host computers for data input and control. This integrated module allows multiple SLMs to operate in system-level configurations. In such a setup, the master module provides the clock and control signals to the slave modules. This synchronizes the data loading of multiple SLMs and allows maximum integration time. The external control modules have sufficient on-board static random access memory (SRAM) for storing up to 1000 filter images. Once data are loaded locally into the module, through a PC for example, computer connections can be removed and the module can run and display SLM data independently. A picture of the experimental and a schematic ofthe correlator setup is shown in Fig. 6. C3 B cntherorm filters (of reference rretosarus. B we asecond SLM (SLM2), images) on are Fourier rates. The input images from SLMI by apositive lens (L3), and the reference images from SLM2 are placed at the focal plane of the lens L3. The inverse Fourier transforms of the products of these two images (Fourier transformed image and reference image) are performed by a positive lens (L4) and captured by a camera (CCD3). The cameras, CCDI and CCD2, display the images of SLMI and SLM2. respectively. High-speed correlation has been performed using either two 128 x 128 SLMs (which permits 300,000 128 x 128 correlations per second). By using one 256 x 256 image plane SLM (with four 128 x 128 images on it) and one 128 x 128 filter plane SLM, a maximum speed of 1,200.000 128 x 128 correlations per second is achievable. We note that the inherent switching speed of each pixel is in the gigahcrtz range. Thus. with further evolution in control electronics. we can accommodate several orders of magnitude increases in data rates. Figure 7. uiInputto SLNII and correlation output or SILIlatCd (Mheliopter and (c) airplane identification and. experimental (d) helicopter and (c) airplane identification. Excellent agreement is obtained. We have been working with a variety of images to analyze the performance of the correlator system. A simulation program we have developed is an extension of a program that we use to create files that can be put directly onto the SLMs. The correlator simulation prograrn takes the input images for what corresponds to SLM I and SLM2 of Fig. 6. The program can perform Fourier transforms on any of the frames and can multiply the two frames together. Thus pure products and correlations can he alculated. The program allows the user to input specific pixel characteristics, such as the maximum and minimum reflectivity and the maximum and minimum reflected phase change as a function of voltage. The program then can determine the change in correlation output that results from the non-ideality of the individual pixel response. Our agreement between simulated and experimental correlation is quite good. Fig. 7 depicts an identification scheme where a helicopter and an airplane are identified via the simulation program and the experimental correlator setup. In the correlator system. encoding the phase information of the target's Fourier transform onto the binary amplitude modulating SLM creates the Fourier filter planes. Such amplitude encoded binary phase only filters have been shown to have high optical efficiency, good target discrimination, and virtually no sidelobes&#x0005B;II&#x0005D;. As is shown in Fig. 7. changes in the target filter permit identification ofeither the helicopter or the airplane in this experiment. Furthermore, as the input image changes, the correlator can track the movement of the desired object. Using our current set of Fourier filters, peak to secondary efficiencies of 2.9:1 have been achieved in simulation while efficiencies of 2.:1 were obtained experimentally. This is sufficient for the military uses we are targeting. Fig. 8 shows some of these results. Figure S. Intensity mapping of helicopter identification for (a) simulated and (h) experimental demonstrations. The major correlation peaks is clearly distinguishable fromi the background.</p>
<p>2-D 8-bit Gray-Scale Capable SLMs Spatial light modulators (SLMs) realized with gray scale capability are key to the improvement of signal processing resolution over binary (on-off) devices--particularly because most image sensors generate pictures with gray scale levels. We currently have 2-D binary SLM devices that provide up to a 256 x 256 pixel format and input display data in a parallel row format (total number of data inputs is the square root of the total number of pixels for a given array). Gray scale capability can be simulated by time slicing, but only at the expense of significant decreases in frame rates. In order to develop high-speed 2-D gray-scale capability for our optical devices, there are several technical and mechanical factors pertaining to I/O and signal conversion. These factors need to be resolved by the drive electronics. First, for binary devices, each pixel is represented by one data bit (on or off); for gray-scale devices, data representation/pixel increases by a factor of 8 for 256 gray-scale levels. To maintain the same frame rate, the total number of data input pads would need to increase from 256 to 2048 for a 256 x 256 array. This would make SLMs more difficult, and hence more expensive, to manufacture. Second. the optical pixel spacing currently sets the maximum area allowable for the drive electronics for an individual pixel. For our future pixel sizes, designing and developing a Si driver chip that can house an individual digital to analog converter (DAC) within that available area is physically not possible. Figure 9. 2-D 8-bit gray-scale multi-flip-chip-module (MFCM) baseline design concept; quartz mother board supports a maximum of four Si diital-to-analog converter (DAC) chips hybrid .3.JA.TezJS.HriJ.&#x0201D;Cetoan Fig.9 depicts our approach for creating a c Z effective packaging technique to support large 2-D gray-scale arrays. This approach will leverage existing drive chip designs to reduce cost, maintain high frame rates for 2-D gray-scale devices (&gt;100,000 frames/sec.), and utilize bump-bond hybrid technology for ease in data routing. The logic frame motherboard will support one of four, 64-channel DAC circuits depending upon system configuration (hard coded by bond configuration), and a hybrid optical/signal interconnect chip that will be used in all configurations. The completed multi-flip-chip-module (MFCM) will reside on a printed circuit board (PCB) assembly that includes logic functions such as a host PC interface, local frame memory, and a master/slave control scheme for operating multiple SLM assemblies in synchronization.</p>
<p>Conclusion In conclusion, we are developing high-speed systems based upon our GaAs-based spatial light modulator arrays. Our intent is to maximize data and image throughputin systems, while taking advantage of the large reflectivity and low power switching afforded by GaAs Fabry-Perot modulators. Such modulators have a multitude of possible operating modes. The devices favored can operate as either modulator, LED, or detector. Detailed simulations allow both pixel designs to be improved and system level performance to be modeled. Our modules use local SRAM for high-speed data access and frame loading, while synchronizing frame updating through the use of a master-slave control network among several data independent SLM modules. Our modular approach allows very complex systems such as correlators to be developed, and we have demonstrated a very-high-speed correlator system. Advanced, multi-chip packaging techniques will allow us to enhance per-pixel functionality on larger format arrays.</p></body>
<back>
<ref-list>
<ref id="r1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Miller</surname><given-names>D.A.B.</given-names></name></person-group> &#x0201C;<article-title>Electric field dependence of optical absorption in quantum well structures: physics and applications</article-title>&#x0201D; <source>Proceedings of the SPIE - The International Society for Optical Engineering</source>, <volume>792</volume>,. <fpage>176</fpage>-<lpage>7</lpage>, (<year>1987</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1117/12.940838</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Trezza</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Larson</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Harris</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names><suffix>Jr</suffix></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Low-voltage, low-chirp, absorptively bistable transmission modulators using type-IIA and type-IIB In<sub>0.3</sub>Ga<sub>0.7</sub>As/Al<sub>0.33</sub>Ga<sub>0.67</sub>As/In<sub>0.15</sub>Ga<sub>0.85</sub> As asymmetric coupled quantum wells</article-title>.&#x0201D; <source>J Appl Phys</source>, <volume>74</volume>, <fpage>6495</fpage>-<lpage>6502</lpage>, (<year>1993</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.355138</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Trezza</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Harris</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names><suffix>Jr</suffix></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Creation and Optimization of Vertical Cavity Phase Flip Modulators</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>J Appl Phys</source> <volume>75</volume>, <fpage>4878</fpage>-<lpage>4884</lpage>, (<year>1994</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.355773</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Pezeshki</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Apte</surname><given-names>R.B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lord</surname><given-names>S.M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Harris</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names><suffix>Jr</suffix></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Quantum Well Modulators for Optical Beam Steering Applications</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>IEEE Phot Tech Lett</source> <volume>3</volume>, <fpage>790</fpage>-<lpage>792</lpage>, (<year>1991</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1109/68.84494</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Trezza</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Harris</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names><suffix>Jr</suffix></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Two-State Electrically controllable phase diffraction grating using arrays of vertical cavity phase flip modulators</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>IEEE Phot Tech Lett</source> <volume>8</volume>, <fpage>1211</fpage>-<lpage>1213</lpage>, (<year>1996</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1109/68.531839</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Trezza</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Morf</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Harris</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names><suffix>Jr</suffix></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Creation and optimization of vertical-cavity X-modulators</article-title>.,&#x0201D; <source>IEEE J Quant Elect</source> <volume>32</volume>, <fpage>53</fpage>-<lpage>60</lpage>, (<year>1996</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1109/3.481920</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r7"><label>7</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Trezza</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Larson</surname><given-names>M. C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Harris</surname><given-names>J. S.</given-names><suffix>Jr.</suffix></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Zero chirp quantum well asymmetric Fabry-Perot reflection modulators operating beyond the matching condition</article-title>.&#x0201D; <source>J of Appl Phys</source> <volume>74</volume>, <fpage>7061</fpage>-<lpage>7066</lpage>, (<year>1993</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.355020</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r8"><label>8</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Worchesky</surname><given-names>T.L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ritter</surname><given-names>K.J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Martin</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lane</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Large arrays of spatial light modulators hybridized to silicon integrated circuits</article-title>.&#x0201D; <source>Applied Optics</source> <volume>35</volume>, <fpage>1180</fpage>-<lpage>6</lpage>, (<year>1996</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/AO.35.001180</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r9"><label>9</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Schmitt-Rink</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chemla</surname><given-names>S. D. S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Miller</surname><given-names>D.A.B.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Linear and nonlinear optical properties of semiconductor quantum wells</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Advances in Physics</source> <volume>38</volume>, <fpage>89</fpage>-<lpage>108</lpage>, (<year>1989</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/00018738900101102</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r10"><label>10</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Trezza</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Pczeshki</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Larson</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lord</surname><given-names>S.M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Harris</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names><suffix>Jr</suffix></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>High contrast asymmetric Fabry-Perot electro-absorption modulator with zero phase change</article-title>.&#x0201D; <source>Applied Physics Letters</source> <volume>63</volume>, <fpage>452</fpage>-<lpage>4</lpage>, (<year>1993</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.110021</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r11"><label>11</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Flavin</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Horner</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></name></person-group> &#x0201C;<article-title>Amplitude Encoded Binary Phase-Only Filters</article-title>&#x0201D; <source>Proceedings of SPIE--The International Society for Optical Engineering</source>, <volume>938</volume>, <fpage>261</fpage>-<lpage>265</lpage>, (<year>1988</year>)</mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></book-part></book-part-wrapper>
