<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
<collection-meta collection-type="conf">
<conference content-type="conf-name"><conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name><conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym></conference>
<conference content-type="conf-other-meta"><conf-date content-type="start">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-date content-type="end">
<day>19</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-loc>Nevada, 
<country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc></conference></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
<title-group>
<title>VLSI-based SLMs</title>
<alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/></title-group></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
<title-group>
<title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title></title-group>
<volume-in-collection>
<volume-number>14</volume-number>
<volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title></volume-in-collection></collection-meta>
<book-meta>
<book-title-group>
<book-title>Spatial Light Modulators</book-title></book-title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Burdge</surname><given-names>Geoffrey</given-names></name></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>Sadik C.</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group>
<pub-date publication-format="electronic">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></pub-date></book-meta>
<book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
<book-part-meta>
<title-group>
<title>Hybrid Integration of Smart Pixel with Vertical-cavity Surface-emitting Laser Using Polyimide Bonding</title></title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Matsuo</surname><given-names>Shinji</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Nakahara</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff"><sup>2</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Tateno</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff"><sup>2</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Tsuda</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff"><sup>2</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Kurokawa</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff"><sup>2</sup></xref></contrib>
<aff id="aff1">
<label>1</label>NTT Network Service Systems Laboratories 3-9-11 Midori-cho, Musashino, Tokyo, 
<country country="JP">Japan</country></aff>
<aff id="aff2">
<label>2</label>NTT Opto-electronics Laboratories 3-1 Morinosato Wakamiya, Atsugi, Kanagawa, 
<country country="JP">Japan</country></aff></contrib-group>
<elocation-id>39</elocation-id>
<permissions>
<copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
<copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
<copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
<license license-type="open-access">
<license-p>closed</license-p></license></permissions>
<abstract>
<p>We have developed a new three-dimensional integration technology which involves hybrid integration of photonic and electronic circuits by means of polyimide bonding. To demonstrate this technology. a vertical-cavity surface-emitting laser (VCSEL) and metal-semiconductor-metal photodetector arrays were fabricated on a Si substrate. The photoresponsivity of the photodetector was 0.3 A/W. The threshold current of the VCSEL was 3.1 mA and the maximum output power was 2.45 mW for a 15-&#x003BC;m-diameter mesa at 20 &#x000B0;C<italic>. </italic>The VCSEL was not lasing above 90 &#x000B0;C. The calculation shows the thermal resistance for the proposed hybrid structure strongly depends on the polyimide thickness. The difference in active layer temperature between the hybrid and monolithic structures is within 10 K when the thickness of the polyimide is less than 0.1 &#x003BC;m and the electrical power consumption is 30 mW. We also calculated the power consumption and the maximum number of pixels per chip. A lower threshold current of the VCSELs and a lower bias voltage to the Si-CMOS circuit are desired to obtain a higher I/O throughput device.</p></abstract>
<kwd-group kwd-group-type="OCIS">
<title>OCIS codes</title>
<kwd>Vertical cavity surface emitting lasers</kwd>
<kwd>Integrated optoelectronic circuits</kwd>
<kwd>Optical interconnects</kwd>
<kwd>Smart pixels</kwd></kwd-group>
<counts>
<book-page-count count="8"/></counts></book-part-meta>
<body>
<p>INTRODUCTION The need to fabricate smart pixels that integrate a photonic circuit with an electronic circuit has recently been increasing. because the integration of an electronic circuit allows the implementation of many smart functions and a high bit-rate response. Flip-chip solder-bonding is one way to fabricate this kind of device. For example. the integration of GaAs-AlGaAs MQW modulators and detectors with a Si-CMOS circuit has been demonstrated in hybrid-SEED technologies &#x0005B;1.2. These devices have shown great potential for use in optical interconnections and photonic switching networks. The integration of vertical-cavity surface-emnitting lasers (VCSELs) with electronic circuits is also an important technology for fabricating smart pixels because they do not need a bias light. Furthermore. a VCSEL provides a good match with electronic circuits because it operates at a low voltage and a low current &#x0005B;3&#x0005D;. Thus. many smart pixels integrated with VCSEL have been demonstrated &#x0005B;4-7&#x0005D;. The integration of VCSELs and photodetectors with GaAs electronic circuit presents few difficulties to fabricate in monolithic structure &#x0005B;4&#x0005D;. and can also be done by means of hybrid integration using such techniques as flip-chip bonding. epitaxial lift-off with a transfer diaphragm &#x0005B;5&#x0005D;. or a thinned and drilled CMOS wafer &#x0005B;6&#x0005D;. However, it would be more difficult to integrate both VCSELs and photodetectors on Si electronic circuits. because the two elements have non-planar structures. Furthermore, these technologies require the alignment of VCSELs with Si-CMOS circuits. This also increases costs and lowers the yield. To overcome these problems. the technology for hybrid integration of Si electronic circuits and photonic circuits needs to satisfy the folloing conditions: i) low-temperature process. &lt;400 C. ii) integration with the uneven surface of Si electronic circuits. iii) precision alignment between Si electronic circuits and photonic circuits. iv) high-density integration of multiple devices. v) wafer-scale integration process. We propose a new integration technology for fabricating the smart pixels. consisting of VCSELs and photodetectors on a Si-CMOS circuit &#x0005B;7&#x0005D;. Photonic elements are bonded on the Si-CMOS circuit with a polvimide and electrically connected by the electroplated gold. The advantages of our new fabrication technology are as follows. The integration does not require any alignment before wafer bonding. This integration technology is a \vafer-scale fabrication process that produces multiple devices simultaneously. So. these features are good as regards high yield and low cost. The fabrication process for the photonic circuits is the same as that used for our monolithically integrated smart pixel &#x0005B;4&#x0005D;. The photolithography for fabricating the photonic circuit employs marks on the Si substrate. The accuracy of the positioning of the Si-CMOS circuit vith the photonic circuit is, therefore, determined by the accuracy of the photolithography. Using this technology, we have fabricated an array of metal-semiconductor-metal (MSM) photodetectors on a Si substrate. We obtained a photoresponsivity of 0.3 A/W. We have also fabricated the VCSEL array on a Si substrate. The threshold current of the VCSEL was 3.1 mA and the maximum output power was 2.45 mW for a 15-pm diameter mesa. We calculated the thermal resistance of our proposed hybrid structure. The temperature difference in the active layer of the VCSELs between the hybrid and monolithic structures was within 10 K when the polyimide thickness was less than 0.1 pm and the applied electrical power consumption was 30 mW. We also calculated the power consumption of the smart pixel. A low threshold current of the VCSEL and a low applied voltage of the CMOS circuit is important to obtain a high- density device with a high bit rate.</p>
<p>Device structure and fabrication process The structure of the proposed hybrid smart pixel is shown in Fig. 1. The VCSEL and the photodetector are bonded onto a Si-CMOS chip by using the polyimide. The InGaP etch-stop layer is used to obtain the clean and flat surface of the MSM photodetector. The vertical electrical interconnection between the electronic circuit and the photonic circuit is electroplated gold. The gold electrode under the VCSEL is for reducing the thermal resistance. The device fabrication process is shown in Fig. 2. A GaAs epitaxial wafer is spin-coated with polyimide and the bonding pads for three-dimensional contacts on the Si substrate are deposited. The GaAs and Si-CMOS wafers are pushed together and heat treated at 200 -C for I hour under pressure (Fig. 2(a)). Next. the GaAs substrate is removed by using a PA solution (H 0,:NH 2 30H). and etching is stopped at the Al0.6Gao 4As etch-stop layer. The Al0.6 Gao.4As etch-stop layer is removed by using H2 S0 4 :H202:H 20 solution, and the etching is stopped at the InGaP etch-stop layer. To obtain the clean and flat surface of the n-GaAs contact layer. the InGaP etch-stop layer is removed by using HCl:H 2 0 solution. As shown in Fig. 2(b). only the GaAs  Figurel. Structure of proposed hybrid smart pixel. epitaxial layers remain on the Si-CMOS wafer. Then, we divide the GaAs epitaxial layer into chip-size sections, typically 2 x 2 mm2. The photolithography for sectioning the wafer is done with an IR lamp and a camera so that we can see the marks on the Si-CMOS wafer through the GaAs epitaxial layers. The photolithography for fabricating the VCSELs and MSM photodetectors employs the marks on the Si-CMOS wafer. This is why the accuracy of the positioning between the photonic and electronic circuits is determined by the accuracy of the photolithography. Then, the wafer is heat treated at 350 OC for 5 hours. The next step is to fabricate the photonic devices, as shown in Fig. 2(c). The mesas are formed by ECR- reactive ion beam etching with Cl. Ni/Zn/Au p-contact and AuGe/Ni n-contact metals are evaporated. in turn. To get the ohmic contacts the wafer is annealed at 420 oC for 30 sec. Then the MSM photodetector is formed on the i-GaAs layer. The clean and flat surface of the i- GaAs layer is obtained by selective chemical wet etching using the InGaP layer. Then, reactive ion beam etching with 0 is used to remove the polyimide from the Si substrate except for the polyimide underneath the VCSEL mesas. Silicon nitride is deposited at 300 "C. and windows for the output light and three-dimensional contacts are opened by reactive ion beam etching with CF. We form three-dimensional contacts between the p-type contact of the VCSELs and the bonding pads on the Si-CMOS wafer with electroplated gold. Finally, we form the common contact both of the n- type contacts of VCSELs and the Schottky contact of the MSM photodetectors by using the polyimide and electroplated gold. as shown in Fig. 2(d). This method is. therefore, a wafer-scale fabrication (d) (b) Figure 2. Schematic diagrarn of the device fabrication processes: (a) Bonding ofGaAs wafer and Si substrate with polyinlide. (b) renoval of GaAs substrate with PA solution. (c) fabrication of photonic devices, and (dl fabrication of three-dimensional contacts. IL u M Im Of hyhrid MISM phOdCtLtct arraN.  Iicure4. IV characteristics of an MSM phoodetcctoi. process and produces multiple devices at the same time. Furthermore, this method provides good yield and has a low cost. To demonstrate this technology. we fabricated the MSM photodetector and VCSEL arrays on a Si substrate,</p>
<p>Experimental Results  The MSM photodetector and etch-stop layers were deposited by molecular beam epitaxy. The etch-stop layer contained a 0.5-pm-thick AloKGa 4 As layer and the absorption layer contained a 2-pm-thick i-GaAs laver. Figure 3 is an SEM image of a hybrid MSM photodetector array. Each device is separated by 250 pm. The GaAs mesa is 25 x 25 pm2 and the optical window is 20 x 20 pmn". The fingers are 1-pmn wide and the spacino is 2 pm. The gold electrodes were deposited on the polvimide and the silicon substrate. Schottky contacts 1piu c * n ikirndencc of MSM pholiixieiecior phiotorespofnsivity (n were formed by Ti/Pt/Au. The three-dimensional contacts between the Schottkv contacts of the photodetectors and the bondingpads on the Si substrate were electroplated gold. Figure 4 shows the I-V characteristics Of an MSM photodetector. The input power was 40 pW. The wavelength of the input light was 850 nm. The dark current was 0.35 pA at a bias voltage of 3 V. Figure 5 shows the dependence of the MSM photodetector photoresponsivity on input power. The photoresponsivity remained level at 0.3 A/W up to an input power of 300 pW, and then fell off. The deviation of the photoresponsivity was &#x000B1;13.8 c in a 4 x 4 array.</p>
<p>VCSEL array on Si substrate The VCSEL and etch-stop layers were deposited by metal organic chemical vapor deposition. The etch-stop layers contained a 0.5-pin-thick Alg 6 Gao. 4As layer and a 0.1-pm- thick InGaP layer. The VCSEL layers contained a Si-doped distributed Bragg reflector (DBR) consisting of 19.5 pairs of AllsGaioNAs/AAs layers and a C-doped DBR consisting of 35 pairs of Al 5sGa5 s5As/AlAs layers with a 10-nm-thick intermediate AloeGao4 As layer. The active layer consisted of six GaAs quantum Wells confined by a space laver of Ae Gao.7As. The total thickness of the\VCSEL layerswasabout8 pi An SEM image of a hybrid VCSEL array is shown in fig 6. Each VCSEL is separated by 250 pm. The upper-mesa diameter is 15 pm and the lower mesa is 50 x 50 ur. The electroplated gold on the polyimide layer was the common electrode for n-type contacts. The gold electrodes *on the Si substrate were used to control the bias voltagetotheVCSELs. Thethree-dimensionalcontacts between the p-contacts of the VCSFLs and the bonding Figure 6. SEM image of a hybrid VCSEL array.  pads on the Si substrate are electroplated gold. Figure 7 shows the I-L and I-V characteristics of a VCSEL which has a 15-pm diameter. The threshold current was 3.3 mA and the maximum output power was 2.38 mW. The wavelength was about 865 nm. The threshold voltage and resistance at the threshold were 2.2 V and 150 Q. This higher resistance was due to the contact resistance of the p-type contact on the p-DBR layer. To decrease a resistance, the p'-GaAs contact layer is required under the p-DBR layer. The I-L characteristics are shown in Fig. 8, as a function of device diameter. The threshold current increased from 2.7 mA to 7.9 as the diameter increased from 10 pm to 25. The maximum output power also increased from 1.05 mW to 5.4 with an increasing device diameter, Figure 9 shows the threshold current density dependence on the device diameter. The threshold current density was about 1.6 kA/cm 2 when the device diameterwasmorethan20pm. However,whenthe diameter was less than 15 pm, the threshold current density abruptly increased with a decreasing device . . . diameter. This abruptincrease in the threshold current Figure 8 1-L characteristics of VCSEI as a function of device diamneter. Diameter ofactive layer (pm) Figure 9. treshold current densit\ dependence on the device diameter. density is due to the increase of the electrical resistance and thermal resistance. The temperature dependence of 1-L characteristics is shown in Fig. 10 (a). The device diameter was 15 pm and the lasing wavelength was about 865 nm. The threshold current was 3.1 nA and the maximum output power was 2.45 mW at 20 'C. The output power decreased and the threshold current increased with the increasing temperature. The device was not lasing above 90 OC. Figure 10 (b) shows the temperature dependence of the threshold current and the maximum output power. The threshold current was maintained at 3.1 mA when the temperature was increased from 20 C to 40. Then, threshold current increased to 4.6 mA as the temperature increased to 80 oC. The maximum output power. however, was strongly dependent on the temperature: it decreased from 2.45 mW tod 0.18 when the temperature wasincreasedfrom20'Cto80. Thethermalresistance was about 1800 KIW and was estimated from the change (b) Figure 10. (a) Teiperature dependence of 1-1 characteristics, (h) temtperature dependence of the threshold current and the naximurn output power.  tn the lasing wavelength when the electrical power consumptionappliedtotheVCSELwaschanged. We used the value of 0.0068 nm/oC when we estimated the thermalresistance&#x0005B;8&#x0005D;. Thisvaluewas1.8tiesChigher than that of the VCSEL fabricated on the GaAs substrate. The dependence of the thermal resistance on the polyimide thickness is shown in Fig. I1. The thickness of the polyimide layer changed from 0.25 pm to 1.4 in the same chip. The lasing wavelengths of the measured VCSELs had almost the same value of 863 nm. The thermal resistance increased from 1600 K/W to 2900 with an increasing polyimide thickness. In the next section. we will calculate the thermal resistance. .c .</p>
<p>Discussion Calculation of Thermal Resistance  We calculated the thermal resistance using simple models, as shown in Fig. 12 &#x0005B;9&#x0005D;. Figure 12 (a) is for the hybrid structure. It consists of an active laver a DBR and GaAs Figure I 11ermal resistance depending on the polimide thickness. Figure 12. Calculation imodel of thermal resistance: (a) for the hybrid (b) for the monolithic structure. layers. a polvimide layer. a silicon wafer. an indium layer. and a heat sink. Figure 12(b) is for the monolithic structure. It consists of an active layer. a DBR layer. a GaAs substrate, an indiim layer. and a heat sink. For simplicity. we assume that heat was generated only in the active laver. We also assune that the thermal conductivity is 0.44 W/cm/K for the DBR and GaAs layers. 0.0018 for polyimide. 0.98 for the silicon substrate. 0.44 for the GaAs substrate. and 0.87 for indium. Figure 13 shows the dependence of the calculation results of the thermal resistance on the diameter of the active. layer. Thedashedlinesareforthehybridstrcture. It assumesthat the DBR andthe GaAs layers have a combined thickness of 5 pm. the silicon wafer. 500. and the indium layer, 10. The solid line is for a monolithic structreona200-pm-thickGaAsstbstrate. Ascanbe seen, the thermal resistance drops as the active layer gets wider. It's also greater for the hybrid structure. Figure 14 shows how the AT changes as the polyimide thickness increases. We defined AT as the difference in the active layer temperature between the hybrid and monolithic structures when the same electrical power was applied. For the calculations. we assumed that the diameter of a VCSEL was 15 pm. that the combined figure 13. Calculation results of the thermal resistance depending on the diameter of the active layer. 1lie dashed lines are for the hybrid structure. The solid line is for a monolithic structure ona20-pm- thick G~s subtrate.the thick GaAs substrate.  thickness of the DBR and GaAs layers was changed from 5 pm to 10, that the electrical power consumption was 30 mW.andthattheotherparameterswerethesameas before. TheAT and the dependence of the polyimide layer thickness in AT decreased with the increasing combined thickness of the DBR and GaAs lavers. The decrease in the dependence of the polvimide thickness for AT is important to obtain the good uniformity of the VCSEL characteristics. When the thickness of the polvimide layer is smaller than 0.1 pm. the temperature rise in the active layer is within 10 K of that for the monolithic structure. This shouldn't be a serious problem for VCSELs because the\ consume ver\ little electrical power.</p>
<p>Power Consumption and Packing Density  Finallywewilldiscussthedependenceofthepower consumption on the operating frequency of a smart pixel that uses a VCSEL. This is important because it limits the number of pixels per chip. . The power consumption of the smart pixel PC,,. is given by PC:,w e PC Ci t p = co PC/ p on + of PCD + PC The power . consumption of (1a VCSEL and a wherePCiis thepowerconsumptionoftheSi-CMOS circuit. PCLI is the power consumption of the VCSEL and MOS transistor which are connected in series with the VCSEL. and PCp is the power consumption of the photodetector.The power consumption of the Si-CMOS circuits is given by (2) PC, = oCVa;,,, where ot is the probability that a power-consuming transition occurs. f is the operation frequency. C is the loading capacitance which depends on the gate number of the CMOS circuit in one pixel. and Van is the voltage to the Si-CMOSc ircuits. When we assumed the 0.5-pin Iiure 14. Polvimide thickness dependence of AT. We defined AT as heiere4niethckessaerempertue beene i ad differececintthe acme lavertettteralurebhetween the hybrid and tonolithic structures when the same electrical power was applied. design rule for Si-CMOS circuits. the power consumption was proportional to 3 pW/MHz/gate at a supply voltage of 3volts. For a lower VCSEL power consumption. a lower bias current to the VCSEL is better. Thus. we assume that the bias current changes with the operation frequency. When the operation frequency is more than 100 MHz. the operation frequency is limited by the lasing delay time. The bias current to the VCSEL must be. therefore. increased with the increasing operation frequency. We assume that the lasing delay time tl is less than 0.1/f to obtain error-free operation &#x0005B;10&#x0005D;. Thelasingdelaytimeriisgivenby (3) p = r, In (lh&lt;'/lt/) 1, I where r, is the electron lifetime. 1, is the peak current to the VCSEL. 1/, is the bias current. and IrII is the threshold From (3). the bias Current to the VCSEL depending on the operation frequency is thus given by i,,=I - I,- 1,,,)e .(4) transistors. which connects to a VCSEL in series. is given by PC 11(1 - I ,, - 13rl, (1, 1 )1Vet, , (5) where V) is the bias voltage. / is the probability that a VCSEL is in the bright state. ils is the slope coefficient. and VLn ;N is the voltage across the VCSEL in the bright state. In this equation. the power converted to the light is subtracted because this power does not affect the thermal condition. The power consumption of the MSM photodetector is given by PC/) n ytie'7q1'14 I- i&gt;,)vMSM (6) Table I. Parameters used in calculations Where ;is the probability that the signal light is incident on an MSM photodctector, pPD is the photoresponsivity of the detector, q, is the coupling coefficient in the optical circuit between the VCSEL and the MSM photodetector, a s. ite o a t e ht. is total current is 5 and 4 mA for threshold currents of 2 and I nA. and Vs the voltage to the photodetector. Calculation conditions are listed in Table I. We assumed that one pixel contains 25 gates in the CMOS circuit, two VCSELs, and two photodtectors. The total current is 5 and 4 mA for threshold currents of 2 and I mA, respectively.Figure 15 shows power consumption versus clock frequency. For a threshold current of 2 mA, the power consumption of a VCSEL is constant when the operating frequency is under 90 MHz. For a threshold current of I mA. the operating frequency also constant under 170 MHz. So, a VCSEL consumes more power at higher operating frequencies because the bias current is larger. The power consumption of the CMOS circuit is proportional to the increase in the operating frequency and strongly depends on the bias voltage. As can be seen, at frqI ce.frequency lower frequencies, the main contribution to the total power consumption comes from the VCSELs. At higher frequencies, it comes from the CMOS circuit. Using these results, we can estimate the maximum number of pixels per chip for a 1-cm 2 area. Figure 16 shows the dependence of the maximum number of pixels in one chip on the operating frequency for two cases: i) a threshold current of 2 mA, a peak current of 5 mA. and a CMOS supply voltage of 3 volts. ii) the respective values are I mA,4 mAand I volt. We assumed that the cooling rate was 10 W/cm 2. When the operating frequency is under 100 MHz, the maximum number doesn't change because the power consumption is determined by the peak current to the VCSELs. Above that frequency. the number gradually drops. When we operate atthe frequency of I GHz, the maximum number of pixels is 270 for case i) and 900 for case ii). So, in order to obtain a high-density array. we need a low threshold current while maintaining the wall- plug efficiency of the VCSELs, and also a low CMOS supply voltage.</p>
<p>Summary Figure 15. The dependence of the power consumption of one pixel on the clock frequency. We assumed that one pixel contains 25 gates in the CMO S circuit, two VCSELs, and two photodetectors. The respectively. Figure 16. Maximum number of pixels varies with the operating for two cases i) a threshold current of 2 mA. a peak current of 5 mA. and a'CMOS supply voltage of 3 volts. iithe values are I mA. 4 mA. and I volt. We assumed that the cooling rate was 1( w emn. In summary, we proposed a smart pixel consisting of a hybrid structure of photonic circuits and Si-CMOS circuits, constructed by using polyimide bonding. To demonstrate this technology, we fabricated the MSM photodetector and VCSEL arrays on the Si substrate. The MSM photodctector shows the photoresponsivity of 0.3 AW. In the VCSEL anav, the threshold current was 3.1 mA and the maximum output power was 2.45 mW for a 15-pm- diameter mesa. These results show that hybrid integration technology using polyimide bonding is suitable for fabricating the VCSEL-based smart pixel. We calculated the thermal resistance compared With the hybrid structure and the monolithic structure. The thermal resistance strongly depends on the polyimide thickness. We also calculated the power consumption and the maximum number of pixels per chip. We found that a lower threshold current of the VCSELs and a lower bias voltage for the Si-CMOS circuit are desired to obtain a higher I/O throughput device.</p>
<p>Acknowledgments We would like to thank Hidetoshi Iwamura. Takashi Tadokoro. and Yoshitaka Ohiso for their stimulating discussions, and Toru Kodaira for the device fabrication.</p></body>
<back>
<ref-list>
<ref id="r1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Goossen</surname><given-names>K.W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Walker</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></name><name><surname>D&#x02019;Asaro</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hui</surname><given-names>S.P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Tseng</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Leibenguth</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kossives</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chirovsky</surname><given-names>L.M.F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lentine</surname><given-names>A.L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Miller</surname><given-names>D.A.B.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>GaAs MQW Modulators Integrated with Silicon CMOS</article-title>.,&#x0201D; <source>IEEE Photon Technol Lett</source>, <volume>7</volume>, <fpage>360</fpage>-<lpage>362</lpage>, (<year>1995</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1109/68.376802</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Lentine</surname><given-names>A.L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Goosen</surname><given-names>K.W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Walker</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chirovsky</surname><given-names>L.M.F.</given-names></name><name><surname>D&#x02019;Asaro</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hui</surname><given-names>S.P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Tseng</surname><given-names>B.T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Leibenguth</surname><given-names>R.E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kossives</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Dahringer</surname><given-names>D.W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bacon</surname><given-names>D.D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Woodward</surname><given-names>T.K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Miller</surname><given-names>D.A.B.</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>Arrays of Optoelectronic Switching Nodes Comprised of Flip-Chip-Bonded MQW Modulators and Detectors on Silicon CMOS Circuitry</article-title>, <source>IEEE Photon Technol Lett</source>, <volume>8</volume>, <fpage>221</fpage>-<lpage>223</lpage>, (<year>1995</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1109/68.484247</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Huffaker</surname><given-names>D.L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Shin</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Deppe</surname><given-names>D.G.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Lasing characteristics of low threshold microcavity lasers using half-wave spacer layers and lateral index confinement</article-title>.,&#x0201D; <source>Appl Phys Lett</source> <volume>66</volume>(<issue>14</issue>) <fpage>1723</fpage>-<lpage>1725</lpage>, (<year>1995</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.113346</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Matsuo</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Nakahara</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kohamna</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ohiso</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Fukushima</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kurokawa</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Monolithically Integrated Photonic Switching Device Using an MSM PD, MESFETs, and a VCSEL</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>IEEE Photon Technol Lett</source>, <volume>7</volume>(<issue>10</issue>) <fpage>1165</fpage>-<lpage>1167</lpage>, (<year>1995</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1109/68.466578</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Fike</surname><given-names>S.M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Buchanan</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jokerst</surname><given-names>N.M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Brooke</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Morris</surname><given-names>T.G.</given-names></name><name><surname>DeWeerth</surname><given-names>S.P.</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>8&#x000D7;8 Array of Thin-Film Photodetectors Vertically Electrically Interconnected to Silicon Circuitry</article-title>, <source>IEEE Photon Technol Lett</source>, <volume>7</volume>, <fpage>1168</fpage>-<lpage>1170</lpage>, (<year>1995</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1109/68.466579</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="confproc"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Jin</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ozguz</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name></person-group> "<article-title>Integration of Microlaser Arrays with Thinned and Drilled CMOS Silicon Driver Arrays</article-title>," <conf-name>Technical Digest of International Conference on Optical Computing (OC'96), SENDAI</conf-name>, <fpage content-type="conf-paper">OTuB7</fpage>, <fpage>68</fpage>-<lpage>69</lpage>, (<year>1996</year>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r7"><label>7</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Matsuo</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Nakahara</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Tateno</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kurokawa</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Novel Technology for Hybrid Integration of Photonic and Electronic Circuits</article-title>.&#x0201D; <source>IEEE Photon Technol Lett</source>, <volume>8</volume>(<issue>11</issue>) <fpage>1507</fpage>-<lpage>1509</lpage>, (<year>1996</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1109/68.541565</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r8"><label>8</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ohiso</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Tateno</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kohama</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wakatsuki</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Tsunetsugu</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kurokawa</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name></person-group>, "<article-title>Flip-Chip Bonded 0.85-&#x003BC;m Bottom-Emitting Vertical-Cavity Laser Array on an AlGaAs Substrate</article-title>&#x0201D;, <source>IEEE Photon Technol Lett</source>, <volume>8</volume>(<issue>9</issue>) <fpage>1115</fpage>-<lpage>1117</lpage>, (<year>1996</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1109/68.531807</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r9"><label>9</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Brook</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Smith</surname><given-names>J.G.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Spreading Resistance of Multiple-layer Cylindrical Structures</article-title>.&#x0201D; <source>Electron Lett</source> <volume>9</volume>(<issue>11</issue>) <fpage>253</fpage>-<lpage>254</lpage>, (<year>1973</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1049/el:19730183</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r10"><label>10</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Uomi</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>1.3-&#x003BC;m low threshold strained-MQW laser array for optical interconnection</article-title> <source>CLEO/Pacific Rim &#x02019;95, FC1</source> <fpage>169</fpage>, (<year>1995</year>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r11"><label>11</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yamamoto</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yamaguchi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hirabayashi</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Matsuo</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Amano</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Iwamura</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kohama</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kurokawa</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Koyabu</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>High-density digital free-space photonic switches using micro-beam optical interconnections</article-title>, <source>IEEE Photon Technol Lett</source>, <volume>8</volume>(<issue>3</issue>) <fpage>358</fpage>-<lpage>360</lpage>, (<year>1996</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1109/68.481116</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></book-part></book-part-wrapper>
