<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
<collection-meta collection-type="conf">
<conference content-type="conf-name"><conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name><conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym></conference>
<conference content-type="conf-other-meta"><conf-date content-type="start">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-date content-type="end">
<day>19</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-loc>Nevada, 
<country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc></conference></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
<title-group>
<title>SLM Applications</title>
<alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/></title-group></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
<title-group>
<title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title></title-group>
<volume-in-collection>
<volume-number>14</volume-number>
<volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title></volume-in-collection></collection-meta>
<book-meta>
<book-title-group>
<book-title>Spatial Light Modulators</book-title></book-title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Burdge</surname><given-names>Geoffrey</given-names></name></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>Sadik C.</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group>
<pub-date publication-format="electronic">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></pub-date></book-meta>
<book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
<book-part-meta>
<title-group>
<title>Detection and Classification of Structural Defects on Textured Surfaces</title></title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Schwarzer</surname><given-names>Heiko</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Teiwes</surname><given-names>Stephan</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<aff id="aff1">
<label>1</label>Berlin Institute of Optics Rudower Chaussee 6, 12484 Berlin, 
<country country="DE">Germany</country></aff></contrib-group>
<elocation-id>203</elocation-id>
<permissions>
<copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
<copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
<copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
<license license-type="open-access">
<license-p>closed</license-p></license></permissions>
<abstract>
<p>In many industrial fabrication processes high-speed automated vision systems are needed in order to control certain product properties. A typical case is the real-time inspection of textured materials. Here, the amount of generated data and the computational complexity of applicable algorithms are usually such that current digital image processing systems are not able to fulfill the speed requirements. Optical processors offer a promising alternative to overcome current speed limits.</p>
<p>The scope of this paper is a concept based on wavelet theory for the design of diffractive filter elements and their application in an optical 4<italic>f</italic>-processor in order to detect or classify certain structural deviations in textures. Critical points in this respect are the indeterministic natures of the "correct" textures themselves as well as of the occurring "defect structures", the fact that defect shapes and sizes are not among the a-priori knowledge, and the low energies, compared to the surrounding texture, that are contained in signals representing defects. These questions will be addressed using theoretical methods and computer simulations. Optical filtering experiments involving spatial light modulators will be presented.</p></abstract>
<kwd-group kwd-group-type="OCIS">
<title>OCIS codes</title>
<kwd>Optical correlators</kwd>
<kwd>pattern recognition and feature extraction</kwd>
<kwd>wavelets</kwd>
<kwd>visual inspection of technical objects</kwd></kwd-group>
<counts>
<book-page-count count="7"/></counts></book-part-meta>
<body>
<p>Introduction Industrial products are defined and characterized by certain properties such as size, shape, surface structure, etc. A major goal of an industrial fabrication process is to ensure the fast replication of these product prop- erties with sufficient accuracy. Visual inspection of the fabricated items is a powerful means to control the ac curacy and so gather information that can be used to determine necessary adjustments within the fabrication process. A widespread problem is the examination of struc tured surfaces of "endless" materials that are trans ported at high speeds, such as breadths of cloth, carpet, paper, plastic foil, or the like. These materials pos sess surface textures that are characterized by a certain global regularity but also by slight local variations of indeterministic nature. Fabrication errors can be iden tified as structures that violate the global regularity. Examples for common cloth textures carrying typical fabrication errors are depicted in figure 1. The examination procedure can be divided into the detection and the classification of defects. Whereas the primary objective of the detection is to localize all ir regularities, the latter part refers to the distinction of different defect types. Correlation filters &#x0005B;3&#x0005D; implemented by diffractive ele ments in a 4f-processor represent a powerful concept in image analysis. They have been proven useful for the recognition of objects in "low-noise" image scenes. Yet, their use for defect recognition in textured surroundings leads to poor results &#x0005B;8&#x0005D;. Because defects are not known beforehand, they can only be extracted from sample image data. Unfortunately, neither the error images nor the underlying textures are deterministic, which leads to a low recognition performance. In addition, signals representing defects are usually very weak compared to the background (i.e. the texture image). Wavelet filtering &#x0005B;2&#x0005D; is typically used to analyse im ages in space and frequency domain to obtain features for a subsequent classification process. Wavelet corre lation filters (WCFs) &#x0005B;6,8&#x0005D; combine the abilities of both filter types. So far, they have been used to enhance the discrimination abilities of correlation filters &#x0005B;6&#x0005D;. The application of wavelet filters and WCFs for detection purposes in textured images is novel and will be dis- cussed in the following paragraphs. Figure 1. Several cloth textures carrying fabrication errors. Images: courtesy of Fraunhofer Institut fuir Industrieanlagen und Produktionstechnik, Berlin, Germany Signal Analysis In principle, textures could be subject to arbitrary sta- tistical variations. Real-world materials and production conditions, though, justify the assumption that the rel- evant textures are characterized by a limited range of spatial frequencies and, in some cases, by a certain ori- entation. The same is valid for signals that typically indicate features that have to be classified as "defects". Due to this fact it is possible to extract textures from images by space-frequency analysis methods. We want to show that the wavelet transform is a suitable method in this case. The wavelet transform Vs of a two-dimensional signal s is defined by (Vv s)(b, a, )= - 2 s(Y) (Y) df. (1) a L Verbally, this means that the signal s(Z) is compared to shifted, scaled, and rotated versions R ) a = \- (.-a )(2) ( of the so-called mother wavelet V(1), and the results are displayed as a function of the respective affine oper- ations: translation by b, scalation by a, and rotation by 0. The definition of a wavelet requires that V)(Y) fulfils the admissibility condition JI(YO)(u)i&lt;00, 2 (3) R2 U| where Y indicates the Fourier transform. Thus, (Y) possesses a bandpass property. The crucial step towards an optical implementation is that, for fixed a and 0. equation (1) can be written in the form of 11 (W~O., )() -. S Y) - b) aR2 cX (S *W) (-4, (4) Figure 2. 4f-system with impulse response w(y) In order to provide a recognition functionality for certain features, the autocorrelation s. S s, can be produced if the original signal s is present in the input plane of the 4f-setup. In this case the impulse response has to be chosen as _ w )* s(-Y) * w(- . (5) Thecorrespondingfilterwiththetransmissionfunction W(G)S()W(G), (6) where the uppercase letters indicate the respective Fou- rier-transformed functions, is called wavelet matched filter (WMF) &#x0005B;6&#x0005D;. Let S(l) = A(9) exp(if(i)), with phase and ampli tude distribution 1(9) and A(9). In analogy to conven tional fractional power filters &#x0005B;3&#x0005D; the filter transmission function stated in (6) can be replaced by W(G)AP(G)exp(i4(G))W(G) (7) to define the wavelet fractional power filters (WFPFs). the wavelet phase-only filter (WPOF) and the wavelet inverse filter (WIF) are gciriled. respectivelY. Defect Detection According to the remarks of th prccling section, our first step in the design of a filter for a specific application is to select the mother wavelet. For all following considerations. the base fiiction will be the so-called M\Texicanv-Hat-wavelct ThE rotational-synunCtrcver-sion is defined bY '(r) = (1.- -) 2 r= (8) It "coliplites" the second derivative of the processed signal. which is a useful property. as will be demonstrated. and its bandpass characteristic is very smooth. Figure 3 shows the respective space and frequency do- mainrepresniitatiols of (r) Figure 3. Alexicai-Hat-wavelet. Upper row: space doiaini respresentation. Lower row: frequencY domain representa tion Since, in a first approach, isotropic (i.e. rotational- symmetric in the two-dimenstional case) wavelets are chosen. only an appropriate scale parameter a has to be determined. A systematic approach to do this is a multiresolution analysis (MRA). A finite set of impulse responses&lt;, is generated by varying a according to a dvadic series. The filter with the best suppression of the texture and best response to defects is selected for implementation. Figure 4 shows the results of a N1RA for the sample texture image from figure 1(b). The filter in row (c) can be used to letect the defects. Of course, it detects all defects of the same scale range, it does not distinguish between them. But for many applications, this is just the desired function. Figure 4. M\tultiresolution analysis of the texture image of figure 1(b) on a dyadic scale series. Left: filter transmis sions. Right: respective system outputs.</p>
<p>Defect Classification by Directional Information The only a-priori knowledge we have used so far is the frequency content of the underlying texture. If a dis tinction between different defect types is the goal, a more sophisticated approach is necessary: knowledge about the defects themselves must be considered. For the applications we are focused on, the examination of textile webs, this knowledge can have the form of direc tional information. Long horizontal structures, for ex ample, usually indicate threads that were not properly inserted. They are critical for the fabrication process. Other irregularities might be harmless. The MRA based on isotropic wavelets as described in the previous section partitions the Fourier spectrum without making use of this information. However, since frequency domain directions correspond with space domain directions, it is possible to separate defect classes by partitioning the spectrum with separable wavelets. Consider the mother wavelet a "one-dimensional, horizontal" Mexican-Hat-wavelet. The "vertical extent" a can be used to adjust its sensitivity to directional deviations in the examined features. The "wavelet direction" can be changed by rotating the (x, y)-coordinate-system. Figure 5 shows filter transmissions that partition the Fourier spectrum into the standard set &#x0005B;2&#x0005D; of a low-pass section and bandpass sec tions that correspond with horizontal (c), vertical (b), and diagonal (d) directions. Here, the scalation param- eter has been chosen as previously determined by the isotropic MRA in order to match the defect scales. The respective system outputs for the sample texture image are depicted in figure 6. Clearly, several possibilities to distinguish between different defect types are demon- strated. Figure 6.Defect classification: System outputs for thesam- ple texture imagefromfigure1(b)andthefiltersdisplayed in figure5.</p>
<p>Defect Classification by Shape Information Of course, the most important and most expressive kind of information that can be exploited in a recognition process is the shape of a potential defect. Suppose the task is to find a sling structure like the one in figure 7. Figure 5. Filter transmissions that partition the Fourier spectrum into a low-pass section and bandpass sections that correspond with (a) vertical, (b) horizontal, and (c) diagonal directions. Figure 7. Defect example for a shape-based recognition. For a number of reasons, it is not sensible to extract the displayed sling from the image and use it as a template for the design of a recognition filter. First of all, this sling is only one specimen for all sling-like features that are to be detected. Others may show minor deviations from this special shape that might influence the recognition process in a negative manner. Further more, the relevant image section contains information that is not important for the recognition, i.e. the un derlying texture. Finally, the energy contained in the defect signal is very low compared to the energy of the surrounding texture. Consequently, a conventional de-sign will result in a recognition filter that responds not only to the defect itself but also to the texture &#x0005B;8&#x0005D;. If the shape information cannot be generated from image samples, the only way is to make a model for the typical defect. Consider the constellation in figure 8. It contains the sample defect and a primitive model for a shape generalization on the left. The corresponding wavelet features produced by the isotropic wavelet filter from figure 4 are displayed on the right. The similarity between the filter responses is a promising hint that a correlation of the wavelet features will lead to a good result. The use of a WCF for this classification problem is the logical consequence. Figure 9.aveletphase-onlyfilter fect. Left: amplitude transmission. Right: phase transmnis- fect. Figure 8. Left: defect example and model. Right: respective responses of the isotropic wavelet filter from figure 4(c). On the basis of the isotropic Nlexican-Hat-wavelet ting in figure 4(c) a WPOF has been computed according to (7) using the sling model as a template. The continu ous filter amplitude and phase transmission is depicted in figure 9. Figure 10 shows the filtered sample texture image with a correlation peak at the correct position.</p>
<p>Filter Design It is well known that neither static nor dynamic diffrac- tive elements with a continuous complex transmission function as it would be necessary for the mentioned WPOF can be fabricated. In order to physically imple ment the filter a quantized amplitude or phase transmis- sion that realizes the same optical function is required. Figure 10. Sample texture image and corresponding response of the wavelet phase-only filter. Iterative encoding methods &#x0005B;4&#x0005D; could be used to find such a function with good performance. However, these methods partly sacrifice the space-bandwidth-product in order to realize the optical function correctly. Con sidering a filter implementation on SLMs with a finite number of pixels, we suggest a different solution. We have binarized the filter amplitude transmission using the Floyd-Steinherg algorithmu&#x0005B;1&#x0005D;. The WPOF psitributinbeenarippmdtofourevels. phase distribution has been hardclipped to four levels. A "sandwich" consisting of a binary amplitude-modula- and a phase-modulating SLNI can be used to implement the quantized transmission function. The Figures 11 and 12 display the new filter transmission and the result of the filter operation.</p>
<p>Optical Experiments The proper optical function of the described diffrac-tive elements can only be achieved in a coherent-optical regime. Spatial light modulators are required to per form the conversion of an incoherently illuminated real- world scene into a coherent image. We have examined two possibilities. The incoherent scene can be imaged directly onto the write side of an optically addressable SLM like the Figure 11. Quantized wavelet phase-only filter for the sling-shaped defect (magnified images). Left: amplitude trans- mission. Right: phase transmission. Figure 12. Sample texture iiage and corresponding response of the wavelet phase-only filter. one depicted in figure 13. A coherent plane wave that impinges on the read side is then modulated according to the write side distribution. Figure 14 shows several texture samples with fabrication errors, the images obtained by the incoherent-to-cohierent c Ionversion using tamdbythei the OASLM M ndheret-tofateren and the results nerimentuing of afilter experiment addressable SLM with that has an isotropic Mexican-Hat-wavelet that has been imple- mented on photographic film. The second possibility is to use a CCD camera in order to record the image scene and display it on an electrically addressable SLM which can be illuminated by coherent light. Our experiments have been carried out on a Sanyio EASLM. Figure 15 demonstrates the excellent quality of the filtered images.</p>
<p>Conclusion Focused on the automated visual inspection of textured materials, we have presented a signal analysis concept based on wavelet theory that can be implemented on an optical correlation processor. It has been demon- strated that space-frequency analysis methods are use ful for detection as well as for classification purposes in textured images. Different forms of spectrum par- Figure 13. Technical sketch and photograph of the optically coherent-conv.ersion. used for the incoherent-to- Manufacturer: Jenoptik Technologie GhrnHtGermany. titioning and the concept of wavelet correlation filters yield good results under practical conditions. Some re sults have been obtained by computer simulations only. However, we have implemented the wavelet filtering for defect recognition on an optical 4f-setup. The results show excellent coincidence with computer simulations.</p>
<p>Acknowledgments This work has been supported by the German min istry of education, science, research, and technology (BMBF). We would like to thank our colleagues Mario Kreif3and Sven Krfiger, and Hartmut Gruber and Gin- ther Wernicke, Humboldt-University, Berlin, for their support concerning the optical setup. Figure 14. Defect detection with OASLNI. Upper row: cloth samples carrying defects. Center row: coherent images oi the OASLM read side. Lower row: optically obtained wavelet filtered images. Figure 15. Defect detection with EASLM. Left column: cloth samples carrying defects. Right column: optically ob- tained wavelet filtered images.</p></body>
<back>
<ref-list>
<ref id="r1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Floyd</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Steinberg</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name></person-group>&#x0201D;<article-title>An adaptive algorithm for spatial grayscale</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Proc. Soc. Inf. Disp.</source> <volume>12</volume>, <fpage>55</fpage>, (<year>1976</year>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Mallat</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>A theory of multiresolution signal decomposition: The wavelet representation</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>IEEE Trans PAMI</source> <volume>11</volume>, <fpage>674</fpage>, (<year>1989</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1109/34.192463</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kumar</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hassebrook</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name></person-group>&#x0201D;<article-title>Performance measures for correlation filters</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Appl. Opt.</source> <volume>29</volume>, <fpage>2997</fpage>, (<year>1990</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/AO.29.002997</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wyrowski</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bryngdahl</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></name></person-group>&#x0201D;<article-title>Digital holography as part of diffractive optics</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Rep. Prog. Phys.</source> <volume>54</volume>, <fpage>1481</fpage>, (<year>1991</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1088/0034-4885/54/12/001</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Sheng</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Roberge</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Szu</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name></person-group>&#x0201D;<article-title>Optical wavelet transform</article-title>,&#x0201D;<source>Opt. Eng.</source> <volume>31</volume>, <fpage>1840</fpage>, (<year>1992</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1117/12.59916</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Roberge</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sheng</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name></person-group>&#x0201D;<article-title>Optical wavelet matched filter</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Appl. Opt.</source> <volume>33</volume>, <fpage>5287</fpage>, (<year>1994</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/AO.33.005287</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r7"><label>7</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Stollfuss</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Teiwes</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wyrowski</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name></person-group>&#x0201D;<article-title>Computer-generated optical multiwavelet filters for image classification systems</article-title>," <source>Appl. Opt.</source> <volume>34</volume>, <fpage>5179</fpage>, (<year>1995</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/AO.34.005179</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r8"><label>8</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Schwarzer</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Teiwes</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wyrowski</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201D;<article-title>Why is it sensible to use wavelets in matched filtering?</article-title>&#x0201D; <source>Proc SPIE</source> <volume>2969</volume>, <fpage>604</fpage>, (<year>1996</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1117/12.262627</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r9"><label>9</label><mixed-citation publication-type="thesis"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Teiwes</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name></person-group>&#x0201D;<article-title>Entwurf linearer optischer Prozessoren mit Anwendungen in der Informationsverarbeitung</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>PhD dissertation</source>, <publisher-name>Univ. Chemnitz</publisher-name>, <publisher-loc>Germany</publisher-loc> <year>1996</year></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></book-part></book-part-wrapper>
