<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
<collection-meta collection-type="conf">
<conference content-type="conf-name"><conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name><conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym></conference>
<conference content-type="conf-other-meta"><conf-date content-type="start">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-date content-type="end">
<day>19</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-loc>Nevada, 
<country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc></conference></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
<title-group>
<title>VLSI-based SLMs</title>
<alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/></title-group></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
<title-group>
<title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title></title-group>
<volume-in-collection>
<volume-number>14</volume-number>
<volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title></volume-in-collection></collection-meta>
<book-meta>
<book-title-group>
<book-title>Spatial Light Modulators</book-title></book-title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Burdge</surname><given-names>Geoffrey</given-names></name></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>Sadik C.</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group>
<pub-date publication-format="electronic">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></pub-date></book-meta>
<book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
<book-part-meta>
<title-group>
<title>Demultiplexing 2.48 Gb/s Optical Signals with a Lower-Speed Clocked-Sense-Amplifier-Based Hybrid CMOS/MQW Receiver Array</title></title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Woodward</surname><given-names>T. K.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>a</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Lentine</surname><given-names>A. L.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff"><sup>b</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Goossen</surname><given-names>K. W.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>a</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Walker</surname><given-names>J. A.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>a</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Tseng</surname><given-names>B. T.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff"><sup>c</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Hui</surname><given-names>S. P.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff"><sup>c</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Lothian</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff"><sup>c</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Leibenguth</surname><given-names>R. E.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff"><sup>c</sup></xref></contrib>
<aff id="aff1">
<label>a</label>Lucent Technologies, Bell Laboratories Holmdel. NJ 07733</aff>
<aff id="aff2">
<label>b</label>Lucent Technologies, Bell Laboratories Naperville, IL 60566</aff>
<aff id="aff3">
<label>c</label>Lucent Technologies, Bell Laboratories Murray Hill, NJ 07974</aff></contrib-group>
<elocation-id>47</elocation-id>
<permissions>
<copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
<copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
<copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
<license license-type="open-access">
<license-p>closed</license-p></license></permissions>
<abstract>
<p>Eight 311 Mb/s data streams are extracted from a 2.48 Gb/s optical signal with a lower-speed 0.35 <italic>&#x003BC;</italic>m CMOS receiver array. The array consists of 16 clocked-optical receivers based on clamped-bit-line sense amplifiers realized through a hybrid <italic>p &#x02013; i</italic>(<italic>MQW</italic>) &#x02013;<italic>n</italic>/CMOS process.</p></abstract>
<kwd-group kwd-group-type="OCIS">
<title>OCIS codes</title>
<kwd>detectors-arrays</kwd>
<kwd>optical receiver</kwd>
<kwd>smart pixel</kwd>
<kwd>demutltiplexing</kwd>
<kwd>optical communications</kwd>
<kwd>optical. Interconnects</kwd>
<kwd>integrated optoelectronics</kwd></kwd-group>
<counts>
<book-page-count count="4"/></counts></book-part-meta>
<body>
<p>The optoelectronic multiplexing and demultiplexing of data is a common operation on optical communica tion links, and one that is becoming more important as these links become increasingly prevalent. These op erations permit multiple electronic data streams to be combined onto and removed from a single optical link. taking advantage of the high link-bandwidth available. Demultiplexing places particularly stringent demands on optolectronic components. In this paper, we de- scribe a method for demultiplexing optical data that utilizes clocked-optical receivers. This method permits the extraction of signals without the need for optoelec- tronic circuits operating at the full multiplexed-data rate, provided synchronization and timing information are available. A conventional optoelectronic demultiplexer uses a high-speed-analog-optical receiver in combination with post-amplifier electronics used to convert the optical input data into an electrical signal at the same rate as the input data (i.e. the transport rate). These sig- nals are then supplied to digital latches clocked at the slower rate of the constituent bit streamls (i.e. the sig- nial rate). By properly phase delaying the clock sig- nals to the latches, the individual data streams are extracted. It is worth noting that once the data leaves the latches, the circuitry needed for further processing need only operate at the signal rate and not at the trans port rate. However. transport-rate electronic signals are aenerated and amplified to logic level in the pre ceding stages. This poses a cost and performance chal lenge for optoelectronic systems. Either all the process- circuitry is made entirely in potentially high-cost transport-rate electronics, or the task is separated into transport-rate and signal-rate chips. thereby adding to packaging, board-design. and power dissipation prob-leims. This dilenina is unavoidable if synchronization and timing information are unavailable, for they must then be recovered from the transport signal. However, if such information is available, a different approach is possible, using the concept of a clocked optical receiver. Such svnchronization information is available in loal- ized digital systems such as switches, multi-processor networks, or supercomputers. In our approach to opto electronic demultiplexing, multiple copies of the optical signal are generated, by use of a grating. a beanisplitter, or fiber couplers. These signals are imposed upon an ar- ray of clocked-optical receivers, as shown schematically in Fig.1. These receivers are each clocked at the signal rate, and need not operate at the full transport rate. One re quires a receiver that is only sensitive to input data that coincides with a clock transition. In other words, the receiver only 'sees7 those bits that come at the time of the clock transition. andignorestheotherbits. Since the receiver will hold its output state as long as the clock is held low, the output signals take on the peri- odicitv of the clock signal, and not the shorter period Figure 1: Schematic illustration of derultiplexing with clocked- optical receivers. of the input data. Phase delay between the clock sio_ nals applied to the array elements permits extraction of all the constituent signals. The plhase-delayed versions oftheclocksignalnmavbederivedinavarietyofways, We have used a single input clock signal in combination withavoltage-controlled-delay-line(VCDL).Atdiffer entpoints onthelinethesignalistappedandapplied to a receiver. thereby providing a tunable phase delay between the clock signals for each Z, array - element. We have previously introduced the concept of clocked- optical receivers based on clamped-bit-line sense ainpli- fiers(CBLSA).&#x0005B;12&#x0005D;Therewedescribedtheadvantages of optical receivers based on the CBLSA for compact, low-powerdissipationamplificationofopticalsignalsto CMOSlogiclevels. AschematicofaCBLSA-based photoreceiver is shown in Fig.2. The receiver oper- ates when by unbalancing two an unstable equilibrium established sense are whnthe tosides of the sneamiplifier to- aeshorted gether by Q7 and Q8. Photocurrent in one of the two detectors generates a current that biases one side of thereceiverwithrespecttotheother.Whentheclock signal drops to 0, positive feedback drives one side of the sense amplifier to Vdd while the other is forced to Vclomp, depending on the state of the input light. We have designed and fabricated a 16-element lin- Figure 2: CBLSA-based optical receiver schematic. ear array of CBLSA-based baeptocees photoreceivers whose out- circuits used to address nornial-incidence MQWm nodulators that were attached to the circuit using a hybrid solder-bonding process previously described.&#x0005B;3&#x0005D; This permitted ts to monitor the demultiplexed outputs optically. The optical detectors were provided in the same manner. The circuitswere fabricated in Lucent Technologies' 0.35pin linewidth CMOS process. For simplicity, a single set of optical test signals (input and output beams) was used, and these were translated from receiver to receiver to extract theindividual data streams and demonstrate thedemultilexingfunction. Onecanalsoextractall eight streams from a single receiver by varying the phase delayoftheclocksignalelectronically.Allthereceivers are switching on each clock cycle, regardless of whether an input is present. since all receivers are clocked. thereby providingapotentialsourceofinterference. Experimental data from the operation of the dleiul- tiplexer array is shown in Fig.3. which depicts an optical inputsignalfromthedirectlymodulatedsemiconduc- tor laser being used as the signal source in addition to eight plotsepicting theeightseparate outputmodula- tor signals being extracted from 8 independent receivers of the 16 present in the array. The input data is being supplied at 2.48 Gb/s, and the deniultiplexed output is at 311 Mb/s in an RZ format. A 32 bit word is repeti tively tivo- supplied to the circuit, and so a 4 bit 311 Mb/s word is repetitively output. The bias conditions were as follows: Vdd= 3.3, Vclanp= 1, Vdet= 5, Vnod= 9 V, and the current from the Vdd supply was about 5 mA, foratotalreceiverarraydissipationofjust11mW. Demultiplexingwaspossiblewithsingle-endedinputs at a detected current of about 75 pA, corresponding to an input optical energy of about 120 f, or a power of -8.2 dBm assuming a responsivity of 0.5 A/W. Since Figure 3: Demultiplexing-of 2.48 Gb/s optical input (bottom trace) into eight 311M'\b/s return-to-zero output signals. It is easiest to interpret the data if downward transitions of the output are taken as bit '1'. Since the receivers are clocked, outputs are phase delayed by at least one clock cycle with respect to the input. this sensitivitydidnotimprovemuchatlowerlbitrates. we believe that these receivers have an unintended im- balance that favors one state over another, resulting in both single-beam operation and unnecessary sensitivity degradation.&#x0005B;1&#x0005D; Interestingly, when driven as repeaters (clock rate = transport rate), individual circuits could operate with RZ format output up to roughly 350 M1b/s, indicating a repeater bandwidth of roughly 350 MHz. Nevertheless, satisfactory demultiplexing of 2.48 Gb/s data is possi- ble. This is because only certain parts of the circuit need to be able to follow the transport-rate signal. A sinmple-minded analysis of Fig.2 indicates that the relevant time constant is that associated with the inout capacitance in the shorted state. Test data from the CMOS process indicates the on-resistance of Q5-Q7 is roughly 300 0. Assuming an input capacitance of 150 fF (input diodes and FETs) this yields an RC time con stant ofabout 140 ps. more than sufficient to track the 403 ps bitlperiod of the 2.48 Gb/s signals. This work demonstrates one of the novel applica tions enabled by the use of clocked optical receivers. This opens the possibility to demultiplex fast optical signals with lower-speed electronics, broadening the po tential of OE/VLSI to include high-data-rate telecom munications applications.</p></body>
<back>
<ref-list>
<ref id="r1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Woodward</surname><given-names>T.K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Krishnamoorthy</surname><given-names>A.V.</given-names></name><name><surname>Goossen</surname><given-names>K.W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Walker</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Cunningham</surname><given-names>J.E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jan</surname><given-names>W.Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chirovsky</surname><given-names>L.N.F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hui</surname><given-names>S.P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Tseng</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kossives</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Dahringer</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bacon</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Leibenguth</surname><given-names>R.E.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Clocked-Sense-Amplifier-Based Smart-Pixel Optical Receivers</article-title>.&#x0201D; <source>IEEE Phot Tech Lett</source>, <volume>8</volume>, <fpage>1067</fpage>-<lpage>1069</lpage><month>Aug.</month> <year>1996</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1109/68.508740</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Blalock</surname><given-names>Travis N.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jaeger</surname><given-names>Richard C.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>A High-speed sensing scheme for IT dynamic RAM&#x02019;s utilizing the Clamped Bit-Line Sense Amplifier</article-title>&#x0201D;, <source>IEEE J Solid State Circuits</source> <volume>27</volume>, <fpage>618</fpage>-<lpage>625</lpage>, <month>April</month>, <year>1992</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1109/4.126552</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Goossen</surname><given-names>K.W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Walker</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></name><name><surname>D&#x02019;Asaro</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hui</surname><given-names>S.P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Tseng</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Leibenguth</surname><given-names>R.E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kossives</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bacon</surname><given-names>D.D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Dahringer</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chirovsky</surname><given-names>L.I.F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lentine</surname><given-names>A.L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Miller</surname><given-names>D.A.B.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>GaAs MQW Modulators Integrated with Silicon CMOS</article-title>.&#x0201D; <source>IEEE Phot Tech Lett</source> <volume>7</volume>, <fpage>360</fpage>-<lpage>362</lpage><month>April</month> <year>1995</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1109/68.376802</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></book-part></book-part-wrapper>
