<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
<collection-meta collection-type="conf">
<conference content-type="conf-name"><conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name><conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym></conference>
<conference content-type="conf-other-meta"><conf-date content-type="start">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-date content-type="end">
<day>19</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-loc>Nevada, 
<country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc></conference></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
<title-group>
<title>Integration and Packaging Techniques</title>
<alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/></title-group></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
<title-group>
<title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title></title-group>
<volume-in-collection>
<volume-number>14</volume-number>
<volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title></volume-in-collection></collection-meta>
<book-meta>
<book-title-group>
<book-title>Spatial Light Modulators</book-title></book-title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Burdge</surname><given-names>Geoffrey</given-names></name></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>Sadik C.</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group>
<pub-date publication-format="electronic">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></pub-date></book-meta>
<book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
<book-part-meta>
<title-group>
<title>Self Aligned Epitaxial Liftoff for Smart Pixels</title></title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Chang</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Yablonovitch</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Hansen</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>*</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Fan</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>*</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>S. C.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>*</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Efron</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff"><sup>**</sup></xref></contrib>
<aff id="aff1">
<label>*</label>UCSD, Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, La Jolla, CA 92093-0407</aff>
<aff id="aff2">
<label>**</label>Hughes Research Laboratories, Malibu, CA 90265</aff>
<aff id="aff3">
<label>1</label>UCLA, Electrical Engineering Department, Los Angeles, CA 90095-1594</aff></contrib-group>
<elocation-id>69</elocation-id>
<permissions>
<copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
<copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
<copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
<license license-type="open-access">
<license-p>closed</license-p></license></permissions>
<abstract>
<p>The need for increased processing speed in advanced computing systems is straining the limits of purely electronic systems. Opto-electronic systems may represent the future form of implementation of high throughput data processing systems. The components that are selected for Opto-Electronic data processing systems have to meet the requirements of both high speed and low power dissipation. GaAs/AlGaAs Multiple Quantum Well (MQW) Spatial Light Modulators (SLM) exhibit low switching power and very high speed. Moreover, they operate at voltages which are compatible with Si VLSI technology1. These make them attractive in high density optical information processing systems such as optical correlators. Thin film integration between Si integrated circuits and MQW modulators can be done by Epitaxial Lift-Off (ELO) technique. A major advantage of ELO is that Si circuitry and GaAs MQW modulators can be optimized individually and then integrated together resulting in improved yield and performance.</p></abstract>
<counts>
<book-page-count count="3"/></counts></book-part-meta>
<body>
<p>Introduction The need for increased processing speed in advanced computing systems is straining the limits of purely electronic systems. Opto-electronic systems may represent the future form of implementation of high throughput data processing systems. The components that are selected for Opto-Electronic data processing systems have to meet the requirements of both high speed and low power dissipation. GaAs/AlGaAs Multiple Quantum Well (MQW) Spatial Light Modulators (SLM) exhibit low switching power and very high speed. Moreover, they operate at voltages which are compatible with Si VLSI technology1. These make them attractive in high density optical information processing systems such as optical correlators. Thin film integration between Si integrated circuits and MQW modulators can be done by Epitaxial Lift-Off (ELO) technique. A major advantage of ELO is that Si circuitry and GaAs MQW modulators can be optimized individually and then integrated together resulting in improved yield and performance. In this paper we report a novel self-aligned ELO integration scheme for a 16xl6 reflective GaAs/AlGaAs MQW array on Si VLSI technology. The self-alignment of the MQW array on the Si driver circuitry was accomplished by controlling the respective aqueous surface tensions on lifted-off GaAs thin films and on the underlying bonding substrate surface.</p>
<p>Experiments Reflective (normally-off) GaAs MQW modulators which contain 60 periods of (90A)GaAs/(40A)Alo GaAs MQW's were fabricated. The drive voltage and operating wavelength were at 1OVolts and 840nm, respectively. Foundry fabricated Si circuits, (MOSIS), designed with 2pm CMOS design rules served as drivers to the MQW array. The active area of the array had an effective fill factor of 97.3&#x00025; and was composed of a 16xl6 array containing 188pmx88pm pixels spaced on a 193tm pitch. Most of the ELO processing procedures have been described in detail in other references. The form of integration in this experiment consists of the detachment of a fabricated array of GaAs MQW modulators from their substrate by under-cutting a thin sacrificial AlAs layer from between substrate and modulators. This thin film is then transferred onto the Si driver chip. The typical surface roughness on CMOS chips (MOSIS-2tm-technology) is about 1.8ptm. It is essential to planarize this circuit topography before marrying the MQW modulators to the CMOS substrate. A variety of planarization schemes have been discussed elsewhere 3. In this research work, a polymeric planarization coating which can reflow at 2000C and smooth out the surface was spun onto the Si chip prior to thin film bonding. The degree of surface roughness was reduced by a factor of 10 after this coating. A I500A Au film reflector was then patterned onto the driver circuit array. By controlling the respective aqueous surface tensions, of the planarization coating (hydrophobic, with wetting angle &gt; 900) and the Au mirror (hydrophilic, with wetting angle &lt; 100), the lifted-off film can be locked 4 onto the surface pattern formed by the Au mirror. The modulators array is then "Self-aligned" onto the Si driver circuit when its surface pattern is exactly matched to the Au reflector. The processing sequence is shown in Figure 1. The major advantage of this self-aligned ELO is that Si circuits and GaAs MQW modulators can be fabricated and tested separately before being brought together. The alignment of all the modulator array to the underlying driver circuitry can be done at the full array scale, or even at the wafer scale within photolithographic accuracy, as shown in Figure 2. After bonding the aligned lifted-off film onto the Au mirror, anti-reflection coatings and interconnection metallization were deposited. The availability of a self-aligned epitaxial lift-off and bonding process, for modulator arrays, on planarized Si driver circuitry, may be extremely valuable in future dense, high speed, optoelectronic data processing systems. A manufacturable ELO technique has recently been developed. Black wax is absent from the process which makes the bonding alignment procedure much easier. Epoxy is used as the bonding medium, which can not only self-planarize the surface during thin film bonding, but achieve accurate alignment. These advances will also be reported in the conference. Figure 1: Self-aligned epitaxial lift-off thin-film integration. (a) Defining modulator array by mesa etching to AlAs sacrificial layer and selectively wax covering; (b) Lifted-off modulator array is brought together with the Si driver chip. Notice that water only adheres to hydrophilic surfaces. (c) Surface tension of water locks the thin film with respect to the underlying Au reflector. (d) The modulator array is self-aligned and bonded on to the Si chip. Figure 2: A photograph shows the bonding accuracy of thin film GaAs MQW array on Si circuitry through ELO self-aligned bonding process.</p></body>
<back>
<ref-list>
<ref id="r1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Chemla</surname><given-names>D.S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Miller</surname><given-names>D.A.B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Smith</surname><given-names>P.W.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>Optical Engineering</source>, <volume>24</volume>(<issue>4</issue>) <fpage>556</fpage>, (<year>1985</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1117/12.7973529</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yablonovitch</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Gmitter</surname><given-names>T.J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Harbison</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bhat</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>Appl Phys Lett</source> <volume>51</volume>, <fpage>2222</fpage>, (<year>1987</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.98946</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ersen</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Schnitzer</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yablonovitch</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>Tom Gmitter</article-title> <source>Solid-State Electronics</source>, <volume>36</volume>(<issue>12</issue>) <fpage>1731</fpage>, (<year>1993</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/0038-1101(93)90220-K</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Pollentier</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></name><name><surname>Demeester</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Van Daele</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Rondi</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Glastre</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Enard</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Blondeau</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name></person-group> in <source>Proceedings of InP and Related Compounds</source>, <publisher-loc>Cardiff U. K</publisher-loc>, (<year>1991</year>)</mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></book-part></book-part-wrapper>
