<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
<collection-meta collection-type="conf">
<conference content-type="conf-name"><conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name><conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym></conference>
<conference content-type="conf-other-meta"><conf-date content-type="start">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-date content-type="end">
<day>19</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-loc>Nevada, 
<country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc></conference></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
<title-group>
<title>SLM Materials and Sructures</title>
<alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/></title-group></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
<title-group>
<title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title></title-group>
<volume-in-collection>
<volume-number>14</volume-number>
<volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title></volume-in-collection></collection-meta>
<book-meta>
<book-title-group>
<book-title>Spatial Light Modulators</book-title></book-title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Burdge</surname><given-names>Geoffrey</given-names></name></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>Sadik C.</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group>
<pub-date publication-format="electronic">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></pub-date></book-meta>
<book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
<book-part-meta>
<title-group>
<title>Investigation of novel structures on silicon backplane SLMs to improve the device performance</title></title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>O&#x02019;Hara</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Bodammer</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Vass</surname><given-names>D. G.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Stevenson</surname><given-names>J.T.M.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff"><sup>2</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Rankin</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff"><sup>2</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Burns</surname><given-names>D. C.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff"><sup>2</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Underwood</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff"><sup>2</sup></xref></contrib>
<aff id="aff1">
<label>1</label>Department of Physics, The University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, 
<country country="GB">UK</country>. EH9 3JL</aff>
<aff id="aff2">
<label>2</label>Department of Electrical Engineering, Edinburgh, 
<country country="GB">UK</country>. EH9 3JL</aff></contrib-group>
<elocation-id>111</elocation-id>
<permissions>
<copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
<copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
<copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
<license license-type="open-access">
<license-p>closed</license-p></license></permissions>
<abstract>
<p>Post-processing of commercially fabricated silicon backplanes for use in liquid crystal over silicon backplane spatial light modulators has improved their optical performance. This procedure entails the microfabrication of an additional metal layer which is optically optimised. Changes and additions to the post-processing procedure to enhance the pixel structure have been investigated to improve the silicon backplane for use as a spatial light modulator.</p></abstract>
<kwd-group kwd-group-type="OCIS">
<title>OCIS codes</title>
<kwd>Spatial light modulators</kwd>
<kwd>Silicon processing</kwd>
<kwd>Chemical mechanical polishing</kwd>
<kwd>Damascene processing</kwd></kwd-group>
<counts>
<book-page-count count="7"/></counts></book-part-meta>
<body>
<p>Introduction Post-processing of commercial silicon backplanes have resulted in improved optical perlonance ofliquid crystal (LC) over silicon spatial light modulators (SLMs). The use of chemical mechanical polishing (CMP) to planarise the walers eliminates the topographical effect ofthe underlying circuitry and allows the production of high optical quality pixel mirrors with large till factors | 11. Ilaying control ofthe top layer metal process penrits the optical optimi/ation ofthe SLM backplane and allows the investigation ofother interconnect structures to enhance the device. We are currently examining adaptions and additions to our post-processing procedure which will change the structure of the pixel and the die to irther enhance the perfonnance ofthe silicon backplane. The addition ofan extra metal layer to protect DRAM devices from photo-induced charge leakage is demonstrated. The extension ofthe process to include an additional patterned dielectric layer to act as a spacer layer is investigated. Also. a new processing technique. Damascene processing is introduced to fabricate the metal electrode/mirrors which results in a ne\\ pixel structure NNiti the potential to improve the LC alignment and the pixel mirror till factor.</p>
<p>DRAM protection from light induced charge leakage With single transistor DRAM SLMs light incidentonto the silicon substrate causes charge leakage from the pixel capacitor to the substrate. this in turn reduces the voltage on the nxulating electrxe which results in the IC switching from its intended state 121. This problem is compounded by the desire to use these devices \\ith large light intensities which increases the rate ofcharge leakage. Post-processing of SIM backplanes has increased the pixel mirror 1ill factor which reduces the amount of light reaching the substrate 131. reducing the etreet of the photo- induced charge leakage. We have now developed this process further reducing the gap between the mirrors and therefore reducing still further the light reaching the substrate. Iigure 1. Improvement in thei post-processiig procedulire leading to igher till factor pi\elI mirrors. Light can still reach the substrate throigI the gaps betxxn nthe mirror/electrodes. Current silicon backplanes no\\ emplo sihonCocSsin U.iinti mlti-eel metalliIation. Io and three leels of metal are no\ quite comnon. Ihese nuimerous metal laxers can be utilised to block lihit rcachling the underling silicon substrate. his techniquie as used in the design of'our 512 )RAM SIM device 141. lIe data and enable lines arearranged in a grid xith the mirror positioned xith the gaps betxweni the minors coinciding with the underlxing interonnect.Figure 2. There is still the possibilit oflight wxhich goes betxecn the 1 i\el mirrors scattering from the undriNing interconnect andr aching the silicon substrate. Figurec2. Schjematic ofthe 512I1)RAMNIStI~tpite~labou hlirclfor. \111ha\c also decelopcd thcpost-prcs in proceidure toapply two ctal lavers " litleh t intcrmidicI lai acting as a blockinglaxi IhCse metal laers ar dI ind 0to prodtIc aI argecovcrlap to reduce the iight rIansmi~soil a minimum. ligucre 3. I his tccliniquc \\as applied to our 1 1)RAM SI. ltiurc 4. Iig&#x0005B;ure3 Schematic diagiai of theli\el structrc itlhle inclusion oflan internediate blocki Ilaxci. Figure 4. Stages of the metallization process to inicrofabricate a light protected DRAM SLM. ( a ) Starting wafer. ( b ) the light blocking intermediate layer, ( c ) the top level metal. The effectiveness of these changes to the DRAM pixel structure were investigated using the 176 DRAM SLM. Wafers were fabricated creating dilerent pixel structures. The commercially fabricated wafer has one laer of metal and a low pixel mirror illl factor. One wafer was fabricated using the first generation ofpost-processing which resulted in mirrors with 3um gaps between them. The second generation post-processing pushed this down to 1.5um gaps between the mirrors. Finally a wafer was fabricated with the additional metal blocking layer. SL.Ms were fabricated using these diterent silicon backplanes which were then investigated for photo-induced charge leakage. The system to measure the photo-induced charge is described in more detail in the paper on the 512DRAM SLM in this issue 141. The times quoted for the full width half maximum (FWIIM). the time for the image to discharge by half. in table 1, are for devices illuminated with 0.5iW/cm2 Ile-Nc light. The 100&#x00025; fill factor refierred to when using the light blocking layer is to indicate the percentage of metal in the pixel area blocking light directly reaching the underlying silicon substrate. It can be seen that the post-processing ofthe silicon backplane improves the perornance with respect to the photo-induced charge leakage problem. This can be accounted for by the reduction in the amount of light reaching the underlying silicon substrate. The second generation improvement to the post-processing again enhances the device. Finally the blocking layer further reduces the light reaching the silicon substrate again improving the device's perfonnance with respect to the photo-induced charge leakage effect. The 512 DRAM SM has a photo-induced charge leakage of 1.16s 141.-100 times better than the equivalent planarised 176 DRAM SLM. This almost entirely due to the different pixel design which uses a pmos pass transistor in a n-well which has a very small leakage current. Table I Photo induced charge leakage for the differentI176DRAM pixel structures.</p>
<p>Spacer Layers Standard SIM construction relies on the use oflspacer balls to detenine the LC cell thickness. The cell thickness is therefore limited to the size of the spacer balls available. Also the use of spacer balls to construct the SLM cell results in the spacer balls on the active array seeding defIcts in the LC layer. We have developed a procedure to use iicroabrication techniques to construct a spacer layer as part of our post-processing procedure. The spacer layer thickness can then be tailored to suit the application of the device. The LC cell thickness can be optiised depending on the wavelength or range of wavelengths being used. Since this layer follows the metallization of the mirrors a low temperature deposition technique must be used so that the metal layer will not deteriorate. A lift-off technique is also required to maintain metal quality which would be attacked 3.ECROxidedeposition 4. Remove photoresist 2. Photolithography 1. Planarized wafer Figure 5. Schematic diagram of the lift-offtechnique used to microfabricate the spacer layer. during an etch process to pattern the spacer material. This places even stricter temperature requirements on the spacer material deposition as the photoresist used in the lift-off technique will only withstand temperatures up to approximately 140C. Also. since the ITO coating will be in direct contact with this spacer layer it must be constructed from a dielectric material to ensure no electrical shorts to the silicon substrate. Therelore. SiO2 deposited using electro-cyclotroii resonance plasma enhanced chemical vapour deposition (ECR-PECVD) is used as the spacer layermaterial. Usingthisteclniquethe SiO2 can be deposited at approximately room temperature. The lill-ofltechnique is described in figure 5. The starting point is a planarized silicon backplane wafer. Photolithography is perfonned to define the spacer layer. Prior to developing the wafer is soaked in chlorobenzenc which hardens the top surface of the photoresist so that when the wafer is developed an overhang is created at the edges of the patterns. This helps to ensure that the 1CR oxide film. which is deposited next- is not continuous over the photoresist. Finally the photoresist is removed taking with it the unwanted oxide leaving the patterned spacer layer. The thickness of the spacer layer is detennined by the ECR oxide deposition which is accurately controlled. Figure 6. Structures of the various spacer layers under investigation. Various spacer layer configurations have been designed and test structures fabricated. figure 6. The different structures are being used to investigate the effect on LC alignment of the LC cells can be fabricated with LC cell thicknesses set by the oxide deposition process. As this technique is applied to devices with larger active areas supporting pillars or walls may be required in the middle of the array. Although these structures will seed LC defctts. as they were mnicrofabricated, there is some control of their position which will at least have the defects in designated regions. It is anticipated that the spacer layers can also be used to help flatten the chip by forcing the chip to conforn to the front cover glass. The chips warped by the silicon processing. multi layer fihn deposition combined with numerous temperature cycling can be supported by the much harder glass cover. Once demonstrated with test structures this technique will be incorporated into the established post-processing procedure. The compatibility with the current procedure was considered whien developing the spacer layer fabrication process and should therefore integrate with the CTrent process without dilliculty.</p>
<p>Damascene processing &#x0005B;he alignment of'ferroelectric liquid crystal (FLC) is heailx influenced by the FLC fowy rate during SLM cell filling j5j. &#x0005B;his flow rate is affected by a number offactors which are determined by the quality ofcell assembly and the control of the tilling process. One aspect which could not be eliminated xas the structure of the silicon backplane. Iven when the device has been planarised the structure ofthe pixelated top laver metal still influences the FlC wol rate and therefore the ILC alignment. We have produced a flat silicon backplane substrate using danascene processing to manufacture the ininor/electrodes. Damascene processing is a metal polishing technique developed in silicon processing to produce multi-level interconnect in advanced microelectronic devices 161. In this process the oxide layer which has already been polished is etched to create ienches in the desired pattern of the metal layer. a blanket deposition ofimetal is then pertorned. which tills the trenches and covers the N\afer surface. finally CMIP is perfonned. which remoes the excess material on the xaler Figure 7. Schematic diagram of damascene surface leaving the metal in the trenches and the top surface flat. see figure 7. The application of this technique changes the metal structure of'the pixel. With the standard process the structure otthe metal layer is still evident. It is nonnally in the region of Iu rthick and the top surface has a variation of Ium. Also the elect ofthel pixel via is apparent which contributes to light loss through scattering. Ilowever, the pixel fabricated using the damascene process results in a flat substrate and the pixel via has no etTect on the top layer. figure 8. Iigure 8. The different pixel structures produced using standard processing and damascene processing. The pattern of the mirror/electrodes is defined in the standard process by the photolithographyfollowed by the metal ctch. With the damascene process the miTor/electrodes are defined by the photolithograph tollowed by the oxide etch. The oxide etch to produce a square grid ofxvery thin walls is easier than a metal etch to produce very thin gaps betweet the irrior/electrodes. figurc 9. Figure 9. Schematic diagram illustrating the difference between the metal etch and the oxide etch. A test structure based on the 176 )RAM SIM design was fabricated where the gap between the metal was made as small as possible. 'To do this the planarization mask used in the standard process was photographically copied onto another mask but with the opposite sense. This mask is then used to Figure 10. ihe 176 pixel mniTor/clectrodes microfabricated using the standard process and the damascene process with mask shifting and multiple exposure. define the oxide etch. The gaps between the mirror/electrodes on the mask was set for 3um on the silicon, this is the first generation post-processing mask. To reduce the gap size ie. microfabricate very small wall structures in the oxide the mask was shifted and the wafer exposed multiple times. In this manner very fine features were created in the photoresist. The Waler then proceeded through the damascene procedure. Figure 10. shows the potential ofthe damascene process to produce very high fill factor mirrors. lhe reduction in definition oftheCmirTor/clectrodes at the corners is due to the multiple exposure of the wafer during photolithograph, the edges ofthe mirrors being exposed twice to only once at the corners. Although a complex photolithography process was employed to define the oxide etch, the damascene process has reproduced in the metal layer the pattern defined by the photolithography. Tbe CMP system set tip to polish the metal is different tor the oxide polishing. A proprietr slurry based on ammonium persulphate was used with a Rodel politex polishing pad. The resultant metal surface showed no sign of scratching and was ofan high optical standard. Initial test samples have been studied and demonstrate the potential of this technique to improve the FIC alignment. Due to the flat surface ofthe completed metal struture the FLC 1flow across the device is more even which results in improved FLC alignment. We have used this technique to pattern aluminium mirror/electrodes. This technique can also be uesd to produce copper mirror/electrodes which have better optical pertormance in the near infi-a-red. I)v etching of copper is very diflicult and this is primarily the reason that copper is not used in standard silicon processing. 1lowever, with damascene processing which is based on a wet process and mechanical ellects the copper can be processed. The damascene technique is being extensively investigated in the silicon microfabrication industry as a way to produce copper interconnect and at Edinburgh we are looking at the technique to produce copper mirror/electrodes.</p>
<p>Conclusions The post-processing of commercially fabricated silicon backplanes for SIMs improves their optical performance. The use 4 of chemical -mechanical polishing to planarise the inter level dielectric produces high optical quality surfaces onto which the mirror/electrodes are deposited. Changes and additions to the post-processing procedure have been investigated with a view to enhancing further the optical perfornance of the silicon backplane. The large fill factor mirrors and the inclusion of an additional blocking layer reduced the amount of incident light onto the silicon backplane from reaching the substrate so improving the DRAM performance in the area of'photo-induced charge leakage. An additional dielectric layer is being investigated to act as a spacer layer. This layer can be shaped and the thickness determined to improve the FLC layer and tune it to the application wavelength of the device. Finally a change in the procedure to use damascene processing has been described. The application of this technique to produce high fill factor mirrors and a backplane with a flat surface conducive to good FIC alignment was demonstrated.</p></body>
<back>
<ref-list>
<ref id="r1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>O'Hara</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Rankin</surname><given-names>I.D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Begbie</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Vass</surname><given-names>D.G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Burns</surname><given-names>D.C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Underwood</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></name><name><surname>Stevenson</surname><given-names>J.T.M.</given-names></name></person-group>, :"<article-title>Post-processing using microfabrication techniques to improve the optical perfornance of liquid crystal over silicon backplane spatial light modulators</article-title>" <source>Proc SPIE on Microelectronic Structures and Microelectromechanical Devices for Optical Processing and Multimedia Applications</source>. 2641. Pp<fpage>129</fpage>-<lpage>39</lpage>, <year>1995</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1117/12.220934</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Handschy</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chase</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Cotter</surname><given-names>L.K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Cunningham</surname><given-names>J.D</given-names></name><name><surname>Pattee</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Drabik</surname><given-names>T.J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Gaalema</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>Proc. Conf Optical Pattern Recognition</source> V. <volume>2237</volume> <fpage>432</fpage>, (<year>1994</year>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>O'Hara</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Begbie</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Rankin</surname><given-names>I.D</given-names></name><name><surname>Burns</surname><given-names>D.C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Gourlay</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Underwood</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></name><name><surname>Vass;</surname><given-names>D.G.</given-names></name></person-group>, "<article-title>Protection of DRAM spatial light modulators from incident light using a multilevel metallization procedure"</article-title>. <source>Proceedings of the 25th European Solid State Devices Research Conference</source> <volume>25</volume>, <fpage>277</fpage>-<lpage>80</lpage></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Rankin</surname><given-names>I.D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Burns</surname><given-names>D.C.</given-names></name><name><surname>O&#x02019;Hara</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Underwood</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></name><name><surname>Vass</surname><given-names>D.G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bodammer</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Stevenson</surname><given-names>J.T.M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Worbous</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>A new high resolution FIC/VLSI spatial light modulator</article-title>&#x0201D;, <source>This issue</source>.</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yokoyama</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kobayashi</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kamei</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name></person-group>, '<article-title>Role of surface adsorption in the surface-induced alignment of nematic liquid crystals on evaporated SiO films</article-title>' <source>J Appl Phys</source> <volume>56</volume>(<issue>10</issue>) <fpage>2645</fpage>-<lpage>2654</lpage>, (<year>1984</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.333796</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Joshi</surname><given-names>R.V.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>A New Damascene structure for submicrometer interconnect wiring</article-title>&#x0201D;, <source>IEEE Electron 1995. Device Letters</source>, <volume>14</volume>(<issue>3</issue>), (<year>1993</year>) <fpage>129</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1109/55.215134</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></book-part></book-part-wrapper>
