<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
<collection-meta collection-type="conf">
<conference content-type="conf-name"><conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name><conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym></conference>
<conference content-type="conf-other-meta"><conf-date content-type="start">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-date content-type="end">
<day>19</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-loc>Nevada, 
<country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc></conference></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
<title-group>
<title>SLM Materials and Sructures</title>
<alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/></title-group></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
<title-group>
<title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title></title-group>
<volume-in-collection>
<volume-number>14</volume-number>
<volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title></volume-in-collection></collection-meta>
<book-meta>
<book-title-group>
<book-title>Spatial Light Modulators</book-title></book-title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Burdge</surname><given-names>Geoffrey</given-names></name></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>Sadik C.</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group>
<pub-date publication-format="electronic">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></pub-date></book-meta>
<book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
<book-part-meta>
<title-group>
<title>Microfabrication of Electro - Optical Structures in Polymer Films: Novel Polymer Waveguide Structure for Spatial Light Modulation</title></title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Harada</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>+</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Itoh</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>+</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Matsuda</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff"><sup>++</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Ohnishi</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff"><sup>++</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Tamaoki</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff"><sup>++</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Parfenov</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff"><sup>+++</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Yatagai</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<aff id="aff1">
<label>+</label>Institute of Applied Physics and Tsukuba Advanced Research Alliance, University of Tsukuba, Tsukuba, Ibaraki 305, 
<country country="JP">Japan</country></aff>
<aff id="aff2">
<label>++</label>National Institute of Materials and Chemical Research, Tsukuba, Ibaraki 305,
<country country="JP">Japan</country></aff>
<aff id="aff3">
<label>+++</label>Lebedev Physics Institute, Leninsky 53, Moscow, 117924, 
<country country="RU">Russia</country></aff></contrib-group>
<elocation-id>132</elocation-id>
<permissions>
<copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
<copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
<copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
<license license-type="open-access">
<license-p>closed</license-p></license></permissions>
<abstract>
<p>Microfabrication processing of polymer is suggested for creating new Spatial Light Arrayed Modulator (SLAM). This SLAM architecture is based on electrooptic modulation of light in 2-D array of polymer waveguide modulating pixels, providing also availability reconfiguration of optical interconnections between pixels of SLAM and optical processing scheme elements.</p></abstract>
<kwd-group kwd-group-type="OCIS">
<title>OCIS codes</title>
<kwd>Spatial light modulator</kwd>
<kwd>waveguide</kwd>
<kwd>electro-optical polymer</kwd></kwd-group>
<counts>
<book-page-count count="6"/></counts></book-part-meta>
<body>
<p>Polymers for electro-optics Electro-optical polymers feature large electro-optical coefficient. possibility to make waveguides. photoconductivity and photorefractivity, as well as attractive simple technology. The possibility of the optical microfabrication (stable changes in optical parameters and film thickness) has been shown in azo dyes-containing polymers films . Here we are reporting the light assisted microfabrication of resonance structures intended for spatial light modulation. The spatial light modulation structures based on Fabry-Perot resonator and similar resonant structures can be designed with such a processing.</p>
<p>Resonance structures for electro-optical modulation. The sensitivitv of E-O modulation can be enhanced significantly with application of the resonance structures as Fabrv-Perot interferometers 13 or structures using internal total reflection. plasmon resonance and their combinations . Another solution is concluded in waveguide light modulation. where there exists the possibility to extend the length of electrooptic interaction. increasing electro-optical response. Such modulating waveguides could be combined with Fabrv-Perot and other resonance structures. We have to take into account both the achievable contrast and possibility to integrate the separate modulating elements into SLM array. Contrast considerations. The optical transmission for the birefringence mode of electro-optic modulator is described by expression T= T, sin (A/2). (1) with the phase shift AF = 2;T -An -d / A AF.vwhere An is induced change of optical index. d is the thickness of film and A is wavelength. From (1) for T 0.3 T, one can get with enough precision: AF (T/T,,) (2) It gives the requirements for phase shift. For example. the 30&#x00025; depth of the modulation (T/Tz 0.3) requires near 1 rad of phase shift A F. Similar consideration 2for Fabry - Perot modulator gives: (3) AF (1-R).(T/T) One can see that in the case of Fabr-Perot resonator (F-P) the value of phase shift is diminished. approximately by the factor of F-P fineness: F=1/1-R where R is reflection of the F-P mirrors. Then for the same 30&#x00025; modulation - AF z (1-R) rad. Compare (2) and (3) one can see howy the depth of modulation is increased in F-P. For example with R=0.99 one needs only AF = 0.01 rad phase shift in E-O media to get the contrast of the amplitude modulation comparable with the contrast in the birefringence mode modulation (reachable there with the phase shift close to 1 rad)...e With linear electro-optic effect the induced phase shift is Anzn rE/2. where r - is electro-optical coefficient andE- electrical field. For typical value for polymers: rl0-12-10)-10 In/V and the thickness of polymer film d= 10 Ltm the phase shift at the wavelength of 0.63 im is less than 10-2 rad for the electric field lower than 106 V/cm. This estimation of needed electric field is important for understanding of possibilities to integrate separate pixels into the array. The integration of elements in the array. The SLM asa multi channel structure can be designed with electro-optic elements (formed in e n o i the p polymer) e placed a on n the top'of. microelectronic chip with electrical drivers. For a while microchips with large integration capacity (more than 10 cell/chip) allow the internal voltage only 30-40 V. Then to construct the SLM one or another technique have to be used to diinish required voltage to available 30 V. Until now the known polymer-based F-P . . .along modulators are working in the longitudinal mode, where the modulated light is propagating in the same direction as electric field and interaction length is restricted by the E-0 lver E laethic es. tuso e suggest to use waveguide technology to enhance F-P modulation abilities as well as to provide new features to SLM. The schematic construction is died f g. . Here Heeheoymriloerustaecetea the polymier film over substrate creates an optical waveguide. The silicon (or GaAs) substrate carries electronic circuitry to address array of light modulating o n elements. Each pixel consists ofwaveguide itself, beam . . . . in coupling elements (prism-like elements . are shown Fig.1) and a couple of the Bragg mirrors. made as a rib on the surface ofthe modulation of the bulk of polymer material. These Bragg mnirrors mrnphotosensitivity form F-P resonator, acting in transmission. Fig. 1. The waveCuide Fabr-Perot interferometer as a pixel of Spatial Light Arraled Modulator: optical layout of single pixel (upper part), the section of silicon wafer (chip with oxide dielectric isolation is shown as example) with polymer waveguide on its top (bottom part), M and M2 - holographic Bragg- typemirrors. Electrodes laying aside of waveguide create electric field. The advantage of transverse field i t litia oeanmakeo longitudinal geometry due to longer lonelargertin E-O interaction length. Thelightisenteringthewavegtidethroughthe coupling element as it is pointed in Fig.1. Then traveling aurl the wNaveguide it fills F-P area. The optical length field transmission) of this F-P is tuned by electrical (and supiebmcrcivieecrdsshwnn.1) Accordbingl hinteltoighathotputoF-is the intensity, of light at the output of F-P is modulated. Finally through the second coupling element (leftbreaks away onthe fg1 the mat l be a waeudtohfespcaan This construction does not need dielectric mirrors. The length of F-P cavity is determined by the distance between the Bragg-mirrors those can be positioned by the the accurate photolithography Z process. For fine tuning of F-P resonator there is possibility to place additional pair of electrodes along with main pair. The same pair might ~serve for logical operations as additional input in F-P lmetinsaseitiunsout - in this case it turns out in inw-P twvo - modul modulating ati element inputsopticalmultiplier. Thesignalsaredeliveredby silicon chip and can be initially electrical or optical (using p of silicon) ones. Planar geometry of suggested structure allows the distance between mirrors L = 100 tm (it means the density of elements at least 104 pixels/ cm2 on the chip surface) and the width of F-P cavity area near d = 5 pm. With 30 V over all length phase shift under applied voltage could be as large as 6 10 -1 rad - larger than in longitudinal F-P with the same polymer due to the ratio of L/d&gt;&gt;1. With phase shift more than 10 - rad the lower limit for the finesse of F-P drops to near 3-10, and correspondingly the demand to the Bragg-mirrors reflectivity to 70-90&#x00025;. Reflectivity determines effective number of intracavity light pass, which to some extent equivalent to the corresponding elongation of length of electro-optical interaction. Then it is physically possible to perform electro-optical modulation in waveguide F-P in polymer with 30 V or even 5 V available with high speed microelectronics. Bragg-mirrors can be made with the modulation of thickness or optical index of the waveguiding film. For guided wave rib-like area could achieve the high reflectivity. From coupled wave calculation reflectivity of rib-like waveguide area is approximately given by R=tanh2 kLo, (4) where Lo - is length of interaction (length of rib area along light propagation direction), k = co n 2c. c-light velocity. 6n - effective optical index modulation for material of Bragg- mirror. Taking 6n =0.1 we can estimate k = 0.1 in-1 With L= 10 tm Eq.4 gives R=60&#x00025;. for L=20 4m R=97&#x00025;, which leads to the finesse of F-P resonator near 30 - i.e. more than minimal requirements for the resonator finesse estimated above. In the case of surface relief (periodic change of film thickness - not its index) effective optical index modulation 6n can be estimated by 6n= (n-1) 6dc where c is film thickness and 6d is depth modulation. There are a few methods to create the surface relief on the polymers: one can selectively etch the surface of silicon, direct etching of polymer can be applied, or direct optical writing can be used. We have confirmed physical possibility with a few demonstration experiments making most of the suggested construction elements step by step. We have chosen for these experiments polymers with azo - dyes as side - groups. We have taken azo-dves containing polymers (poly-Disperse Red-19 Toluendiisocyanate and poly- Orange Tom-I Isophoronediisocyanate from Chromophore. Inc.). The structural formulae of both compounds are presented in Fig. 2. Fig.2 a. Poly-Disperse Red-19 Toluendiisocyanate Fig.2 b. Poly-Orange Tom-1 Isophoronediisocyanate These azo-dye groups impart a large electro-optical coefficient to polymers - up to 6 10 -10 in/V for polymers 1 wN ith DRI9 We prepared waveguides based on spin- coated films with thickness near 0.3-1 tm. The losses have been made less than 1 dB/cm in the best cases at wavelength 633 nmin these waveguides. This value is important as these are the losses contributing in the F-P resonator. The value 1 dB/cm corresponds to only a few percents of light losses for proposed length F-P cavity. We have modeled the microstructures manufactured with the process of the photomodification of azo - dyes side polymers. This modification includes the change of refractive index of polymer as well as the surface relief creation and the change of absorption spectrun (as shown in Fig. 4). For instance, we measured 50 nm change in the thickness of the polymer film under long UV exposure - 0.1-1 mW/c2 at 400 nm for 5 hours). So there is possibility to pattern the polymers like in photolithography - but with direct writing- without photoresist. solvents, etc. Fig. 5 shows the result of investigation of obtained surface relief with AFM (Atomic Force Microscopy). The combined optical. chemical and AFT techniques allowed to put forward the probable physical and chemical mechanisms of the observed photomodification ofazo-polmers Fig.3 Optical transmission spectrum of poly-Orange Tom-I Isophoronediisocyanate. Line marked with circles corresponds to the initial forn of polymer, line with squares - to the bleached (with UV light) form, solid line - transmission of the tilm area with written holographic grating (diffraction efticiencv near We have made periodical resonance structures as a el holographic gratings (suitable both for mirrors in F-P and for coupling purposes). To make these periodical structures we have recorded holographic phase gratings with 488 and 442 n lasers at spatial frequencies tip to 1000 lp/mm. Diffraction efficiency achieved 30&#x00025; for transmitted light . Fig 4 shows the plot of the diffraction efficiency dependence of laser exposure. This value of efficiency means that optical thickness of polymer films can be changed with at least 100 ni. nnwhat has been confirmed by direct measurement of surface reliefwith atomic force microscopy and contact scanning profiler. F'ig.4. Difraction efticienc&#x00025; ol \\ritten hologram (in poly- Orange Tom-I Isophoronediisocanate filn) as plotted during the exposure under Ar laser illumination (488 rn with intensity near 20 mW/cm )Maximum efficiency is near 30&#x00025;. Onecanseethatthespectnunofscandoesnot contain much of higher harmonics and the shape of grating is quite harmonical. This means that the process of the hologram writing is well linear on the light It means also that the shape of elementsutnder the fabrication can be easily calculated and then constructed with the exposure of the light. The grating coupling has been demonstrated. The efficiencyofcouplinginthewaveguidewasnear6-10&#x00025; whiletheefficiency of thecoupling out the waveguide was close to 50&#x00025; in one of diffraction order (as determined in respect to the light intensity coupled in waveguide). The difference is connected with length of interaction - in first case this length is of order of film thickness (1 m). in the second - of order of the aperture of the holographic attern. (1-2 mm). Fig. 5. The surface relief (near 30-36 un) produced under holographic exposure with argon laser during a few minutes at intensit near 2 W/cm 2(easured ithAFM). Period0 oratin is near 600 un. Measured diffraction efficiency (in transmission) has near 10 &#x00025; (a 633 rn. On the left side is AFT scan.Ontheright- thespectrumofthisscan. Diffraction coupling elements being manufactured from the same electro-optic material are giving new possibility. The angle of diffraction on these gratings is determined: 2Dsin82 n)_ (5) where 0 is the angle of diffraction and D is the period of pattern. Deviation of diffraction angle is proportional to the index modulation :reaofE-O These consideration. presented here for wave propagating along the waveguide. means that this wave can be deflected from the initial by changing of optical index in the grating area. Electro-optic effect in the polymers can be used for this change to deflect output light (additional electrodes should be placed in rib area). The deviation of angle is proportional to the optical index change. With 62 4 10-3 (under the same conditions as we describe forF-P resonator with r = 6 10- 10 V/m)-and at 0= 85' according to Eq.6 we can get 50 2.5 10-2 rad =1.5 0. In the same time the elements with 60 = 0.3 o are considered as practically useful 7 This consideration is valid for thin holograms. while volume holograms obtain angle selectivity. Then electro-optic modulation of optical index leads to the modulation of diffraction g efficiency . The angular selectiity of volune holograms in clectro-optic crystals is oforder0.1'. Then the change of optical index ofpolymer of order of 10-3 diminishes diffraction efficiency 102 times. Surely the thickness of this hologram has to fit the thick-hologram criteria. i.e. be in the region of 100 tm (or more) for optical index change of order of 10 Apparently such a thickness of hologram can be combined with waveguiding thin polymer films via some hybrid technology. Recently similar features for volume holograms have been suggested to use in neural network as it gives a tool for changin iand learning of neural links 9</p>
<p>Advanced SLAM architecture The advanced SLAM architecture based on the polymers andenabhngsuggestedfeaturesisshowninFig.3. Here we assume also that proposed enhanced SLAM could obtain possibility of optical and electrical control. Silicon chip carries the photodetectors with amplifiers, as well as electronic drivers controlling the electro-optical elements built in waveguide polymer film. We assume that these mentioned electronic drivers control as modulating elements. as well as coupling gratings. due the electro-optical interaction in waveguide and in grating areas. 11flcted 0 a ju e pitCosesuS Sih I I Optical inputs Fig.3. The simplified optical layout of the pixel part of the Advanced SLAM Itisimportantthatonecanwritethehologramsin polymer film placed over silicon chip. creating thus the links in optical processor (e.g., as the mentioned above coupling elements). The voltage applied to each pixel changes the intensity of each specific link or re-align this link to another site - changing the angle. All technology remains fully polymer-based - electro-optic modulation. wave-guidance. hologram writing. etc. are possible in the same polymer material, featuring fast electro-optic response 1 Conclusions The light assisted microfabrication processing of polymers is suggested to create the resonance structures for integrated optics - such as Bragg -mirrors for Fabry- Perot interferometers. On the base such structures in electro-optical polymers we propose the architecture of the new spatial light arrayed modulator (SLAM). This SLAM provides electro-optic modulation of light in 2-D array of polymer waveguide pixels. reconfiguration of optical interconnection - the change of intensity of these connections or the change of the addresses of the pixels to be connected via deflection of the light. In this sense this polymer based SLAM can serve as a binding element between waveguide modulation scheme, delivering of light pulses, and an external free-space data array processing scheme. Acknowledgments. This work has been made when A. Parfenov has been at Institute of Applied Physics of University of Tsukuba and National Institute of Materials and Chemical Research (Tsukuba. Japan). A. Parfenov thanks Japanese Society for Promotion of Sciences and New Energy Development Organization for the financial support and also Institute of Applied Physics of University of Tsukuba and National Institute of Materials and Chemical Research for given research possibilities. This research was partly supported by the Ministry of Education. Science. Sports and Culture of Japan and by Yatagai Project. Tsukuba Advanced Research Alliance. A. Parfenov' present address: Electrotechnical Laboratory. Higashi 1-1-4. Tsukuba. Ibaraki 305, Japan.e-mail : parfenov'(ineurnlpi.mnsk.su</p></body>
<back>
<ref-list>
<ref id="r1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Shi</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>, <article-title>Large stable photoinduced refractive index change in a nonlinear optical polyester polymer with disperse red side groups</article-title> - <source>Appl Phys Lett</source> <volume>58</volume>(<issue>11</issue>) <fpage>1131</fpage>-<lpage>1133</lpage>, (<year>1991</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.104393</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Dumarevskii</surname><given-names>Yu. D</given-names></name><name><surname>Kovtonyuk</surname><given-names>N.F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kompanets</surname><given-names>I.N.</given-names></name><name><surname>Parfeno</surname><given-names>A.V.</given-names></name><name><surname>Savin</surname><given-names>A. I</given-names></name></person-group>, - <article-title>Optical control of the spatial modulation of light in a liquid- crystal interferometer</article-title> - <source>Sov Phys Dokl</source> <volume>3</volume>(<issue>14</issue>) <fpage>319</fpage>-<lpage>321</lpage>, (<year>1986</year>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Harada</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Itoh</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yatagai</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name></person-group>, -<article-title>Development of SLM with nonlinear organic materials</article-title> -<source>Optical Review</source> <volume>3</volume> No. <issue>6A</issue>, <fpage>440</fpage>-<lpage>443</lpage>, (<year>1996</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF02935954</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yacoubian</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ave</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name></person-group>, - <article-title>Enhanced optical modulator with azo - dye polymer</article-title> - <source>Appl Opt</source> <volume>32</volume>(<issue>17</issue>) <fpage>3073</fpage>-<lpage>3080</lpage>, (<year>1996</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/AO.32.003073</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><source>Pochi Yeli -Optical Waves in Layered Media -</source> <publisher-name>J. Wiley  Sons</publisher-name> <publisher-loc>NY</publisher-loc>, (<year>1988</year>)<fpage>189</fpage>-<lpage>200</lpage></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Harada</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Itoh</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Matsuda</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ohnishi</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Tamaoki</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name><name><surname>Parfenov</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yatagai</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name></person-group> - <source>Photomodification of polymers films: azobenzene - containing polyurethanes - (to be published in J. of Physics.:D)</source>.</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r7"><label>7</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Klaus</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name><etal/> </person-group>, - <article-title>Effective beam deflection with a blazed LC phase grating</article-title> - <source>Optical Computing</source> (<publisher-loc>Japan Sendai</publisher-loc> <year>1996</year>)- <series>Technical Digest</series> v. <volume>1</volume>, <fpage>28</fpage>-<lpage>29</lpage></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r8"><label>8</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Stepanov</surname><given-names>S.I.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kamnshilin</surname><given-names>A.A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Petrov</surname><given-names>M.P.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Electrically controlled optical diffraction by volume holograms in electrooptic crystals</article-title>.,&#x0201D; <source>Sov Tech Phys Lett</source> v. <volume>3</volume>, pp. <fpage>36</fpage>-<lpage>38</lpage>, (<year>1977</year>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r9"><label>9</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Agranat</surname><given-names>A.J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Silberg</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name></person-group>, - <article-title>The electroholographic neurons implemented on potassium lithium tantalate niobate crystals</article-title> - <source>Optics Letters</source> v. <volume>21</volume>. No. <issue>19</issue>, <fpage>1544</fpage>-<lpage>6</lpage>, (<year>1996</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/OL.21.001544</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></book-part></book-part-wrapper>
