<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
<collection-meta collection-type="conf">
<conference content-type="conf-name"><conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name><conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym></conference>
<conference content-type="conf-other-meta"><conf-date content-type="start">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-date content-type="end">
<day>19</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-loc>Nevada, 
<country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc></conference></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
<title-group>
<title>SLM Applications</title>
<alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/></title-group></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
<title-group>
<title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title></title-group>
<volume-in-collection>
<volume-number>14</volume-number>
<volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title></volume-in-collection></collection-meta>
<book-meta>
<book-title-group>
<book-title>Spatial Light Modulators</book-title></book-title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Burdge</surname><given-names>Geoffrey</given-names></name></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>Sadik C.</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group>
<pub-date publication-format="electronic">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></pub-date></book-meta>
<book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
<book-part-meta>
<title-group>
<title>Compensated Imaging by Real-Time Holography with Optically Addressed Spatial Light Modulators</title></title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Gruneisen</surname><given-names>Mark T.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref><xref rid="cor1" ref-type="corresp"><sup>*</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Wilkes</surname><given-names>James M.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<aff id="aff1">
<label>1</label>Phillips Laboratory PL/LIMS 3550 Aberdeen Avenue SE, Kirtland Air Force Base, NM 87117-5776, phone: (505) 846-9298, fax: (505) 846-1191</aff></contrib-group>
<author-notes>
<corresp id="cor1">
<label>*</label>email: <email>gruneism@plk.af.mil</email></corresp></author-notes>
<elocation-id>220</elocation-id>
<permissions>
<copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
<copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
<copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
<license license-type="open-access">
<license-p>closed</license-p></license></permissions>
<abstract>
<p>&#x0201C;Compensated imaging by real-time holography corrects for aberrations in telescope imaging systems and allows scaling to large apertures using lightweight, low-optical-quality primary mirrors. This application leads to unique requirements for optically addressed spatial light modulators.&#x0201D;</p></abstract>
<kwd-group kwd-group-type="OCIS">
<title>OCIS codes</title>
<kwd>Aberration compensation</kwd>
<kwd>Spatial light modulators</kwd>
<kwd>Holographic recording materials</kwd>
<kwd>Adaptive optics</kwd></kwd-group>
<counts>
<book-page-count count="7"/></counts></book-part-meta>
<body>
<p>Introduction Conventional telescope imaging systems are prone to image degradation resulting from several aberrating mechanisms. These mechanisms include atmospheric turbulence, misalignment of telescope optics and primary mirror distortions. Furthermore, engineering challenges associated with fabricating, transporting and manipulating large-aperture optics limit the size of high-optical-quality primary mirrors manufactured for telescope systems. This in turn limits both the resolution and light gathering ability of present day ground-based and space-based telescope systems. In recent years real-time adaptive imaging schemes have been developed for the purpose of compensating aberrations due to atmospheric turbulence above ground- based astronomical telescope systems &#x0005B;1,2&#x0005D;. The turbulence-induced aberration introduces a spatially varying optical path deviation (OPD) which may be compensated by introducing an equal and opposite OPD. Conventional adaptive systems rely on deformable mirrors to introduce a compensating propagation path. A wavefront sensor and computer system characterize the aberrated wavefront and drive actuators on the flexible mirror, thereby restoring the image. Since optical path is the product of physical pathlength and refractive index, one can also achieve aberration compensation via spatial modulation of the refractive index. Consequently. electrically addressed liquid-crystal phase modulators are under development as low-cost high resolution replacements for the deformable mirrors &#x0005B;3,4&#x0005D;. Figure 1. Aberration compensation by holographic phase subtraction. Optical path correction schemes may also be applied tothe problem ofcompensating aberrations in lare lightweight low-optical-quality primary mirrors in space- based telescopes. One disadvantage of the OPD correction scheme in this application is the weight and complexity associated with the wavefront sensor and control electronics. In this work, we describe the application of optically addressed spatial light modulators (OASLM's) to an alternative technique for compensated imaging that eliminates the need for the wavefront analyzer, computer processor, and adaptive controls. This &#x0201C;all-optical&#x0201D; technique makes use of holographic phase subtraction, &#x0005B;5- 7&#x0005D; where the OASLM acts as a real-time holographic recording medium that allows compensation of dynamic aberrations &#x0005B;8&#x0005D;. The phase-subtraction geometry is illustrated in Fig. 1. A beacon wavefront, of amplitude B, probes the phase aberration, a, where a=(27i/k)OPD and k is the wavelength of the beacon laser. The aberrated beacon field, Beita, interferes with a mutually coherent plane wave, also of amplitude B, to produce a hologram as showninFig.a. Forthecaseofan amplitudeIhologram the hologram transmission function, which is proportional to the squared modulus of the illuminating field, is written as Once written, the hologram is illuminated by the aberrated object field, Ae eI4 a, where Aei is the original undistorted object field. Mathematically, the diffraction is described by multiplying the aberrated object fieldbythehologramtransmissionfunction; AeiqeP aT - 2 e eia + ei ei2 a + e'. This multiplication yields three terms. The first term, proportionaltoeI e aisthe0-orderdiffractionwhichis just the aberrated object field transmitted by the hologram. Inthesecondterm,proportionaltoe ei2 athecomplex phase distortions add yielding an object image with double the aberration. In the third term, the phase distortion terms have canceled leaving the complex phase ei describing the unaberrated object. Figure 2. Experimental setup along with a two dimensional photograph and three-dimensional intensity contours of aberrated and corrected images of a point source imaged by a low-quality membrane optic using a real-time holographic phase subtraction technique. SLM spatial light modlator; hwp, half-wave plate; qwp, quarter-wave plate.</p>
<p>Experimental Demonstration Recently, we presented the results of an experimental demonstration in which an OASLM is used as the real-time holographic medium in a compensated telescope geometry &#x0005B;9&#x0005D;. In this demonstration, near-diffraction-limited imaging was achieved using a membrane primary mirror with more than 100 waves of aberration. The experimental setup is shown in Fig. 2. An object point source at infinity is simulated by illuminating a 25 pm pinhole with the output from a helium neon laser operating at 543 nm, and collimating the transmitted light with a six- inch diameter f/6 parabolic reflector. The collimated light is propagated to the compensated membrane mirror telescope. The membrane mirror consists of a high-reflectivity-coated four-micron-thick nitrocellulose membrane mounted to a vacuum flange and held under partial vacuum. A 5 mW green helium-neon laser acts as the reference beacon source. The laser output is expanded, directed through a null corrector lens arrangement and onto the primary mirror surface. The null corrector arrangement produces an f/6 parabolic wavefront. The membrane pressure is adjusted to approximately match the curvature of the membrane surface to the f/6 beacon wavefront. Consequently, the reference beam measures the deviation of the primary mirror surface from the ideal parabolic surface. The retroreflected light is recollimated by the null corrector and relayed to the &#x0201C;write&#x0201D; side of the OASLM where it interferes with a mutually coherent plane wave derived from the same laser. A Displaytech &#x0005B;13&#x0005D; ferroelectric OASLM operating at 300 Hz acts as the real- time hologram. The aberrated image-bearing light is relayed to the opposite side of the SLM where diffraction from the liquid-crystal layer occurs. Note in Fig. 2 that due to an internal reflection the OASLM generates diffracted light in the backward direction. The reflected/diffracted light is propagated to a camera located in an image plane for the pinhole. The zero-order aberrated beam and the first order corrected diffracted beam are shown in the lower left-hand corner of Fig. 2. Qualitatively, one can see that the degree of correction is very high. In order to quantify the degree of correction, the image is magnified optically to produce a corrected image sufficiently large for a pixelated measurement of the spot size. A ray-trace analysis of the system, assuming a perfect f/6 parabolic primary mirror, indicates the diffraction limited spot size at the camera should be 75 ptm. The compensated image is measured to be 120 pm in diameter or 1.6 times diffraction limited. The measured uncompensated image diameter is approximately 25 mm, or 330 times diffraction limited. Thus the degree of correction is greater than 200. While the degree of correction is very high, we did not achieve complete correction to the diffraction limit. This is most likely due to the fact that the large aberration leads to intensity interference fringe densities that are beyond the resolution of the OASLM. In this experiment, the write-beam crossing angle is approximately one-degree, corresponding to a fringe density of about 30 lines/mm The severe aberration leads to significantly higher fringe densities. The OASLM diffraction efficiency begins to decline from its maximum value at fringe densities greater than about 30 /mm.</p>
<p>Optically Addressed Spatial Light Modulators as Real-Time Holographic Media Figure 3 shows a schematic of the typical liquid-crystal OASLM architecture. The device consists of a large area amorphous-silicon photoconductor or photodiode and a ferroelectric or nematic liquid-crystal layer located between transparent electrodes. The electrodes are biased in the -5 Volt range producing a field across the liquid- crystal region that depends on the local conductivity of the photoconductor. The holographic write beams produce an intensity interference pattern on the photoconductor. This leads to spatial modulation of the conductivity, and a corresponding spatial modulation of the field across the liquid-crystal layer. The liquid-crystal molecules reorient themselves according to the local field amplitude. The &#x0201C;read&#x0201D; beam is incident on the liquid-crystal side of the device. Ideally, a high-reflectivity mirror prevents the read light from illuminating the photoconductor. Consequently, the read beam passes through the liquid crystal, is reflected, and passes once again through the liquid crystal. The read beam will experience either phase or polarization modulation depending on the type of liquid-crystal medium and on the polarization properties of the incident Figure 3. Schematic of the optically addressed spatial light modulator</p>
<p>Speed and Sensitivity Early demonstrations of real-time holography were accomplished using nonlinear optical media as the holographic recording medium &#x0005B;10-12&#x0005D;. Nonlinear materials offer the advantages of high resolution and, in many cases, purely passive operation. That is, drive electronics and thermal stabilization are not required. One significant shortcoming however is the amount of laser power that is typically required to modify the material's absorptive or dispersive response. Furthermore, the required laser intensity is typically inversely proportional to the material response time hence it is difficult to achieve both speed and sensitivity simultaneously. The combination of write-beam sensitivity and reasonably high refresh rates make OASLM's very attractive for space-based telescope applications. OASLM devices typically operate with write-beam intensities near 50 PW/cm 2 . Such intensities are easily achieved with minimal power and cooling requirements. Hologram refresh rates range from -30 Hz for nematic devices to &gt;1 kHz for ferroelectric devices. Dynamic aberration compensation requires the OASLM to be operated at a refresh rate that is greater than the rate at which the aberration is changing. The operating speed requirement will be determined by the source of the time- dependence (e.g. mechanical vibrations or atmospheric turbulence) and is specific to a given application.</p>
<p>Optical Efficiency For the purpose of compensated imaging, the net optical efficiency may be defined as the percentage of uncompensated, unpolarized image light that is converted into compensated image light. Thus, this definition includes any absorption and reflection losses associated with use of the OASLM. For light-sensitive imaging applications, the low optical efficiency achievable with commercially available OASLM's is a significant shortcoming. There are two primary contributions to the low net efficiency. First is the loss experienced by the image light upon reflection from the amorphous-silicon interface. Historically, &#x0005B;13&#x0005D; high reflectivity dielectric coatings on large area photodiodes were found to reduce the resolution and degrade the switching capabilities due to the added thickness and capacitance. Recently, &#x0005B;14&#x0005D; high- performance OASLM devices incorporating high-reflection coated photoconductors have become commerciallyavailable.</p>
<p>Diffraction Efficiency The second source of optical loss is the first-order diffraction efficiency. Spatial light modulators are thin hologram devices. Typically, the nematic and ferroelectric liquid-crystal devices produce analog and binary modulation,respectively. Figure4showsthetheoretical maximum first-order diffraction efficiencies for the four possible combinations of amplitude or phase and analog or binary thin holograms. Phase holograms yield the highest first-order diffraction efficiencies with the analog and binary phase gratings yielding 34&#x00025; and 40&#x00025;, respectively. Since ferroelectric devices operate on the principle of polarization rotation, a polarizer/analyzer configuration is necessary to convert the polarization modulation into amplitude or phase modulation. When situated between orthogonal linear polarizers, the liquid-crystal layer can be oriented to produce either pure amplitude modulation, pure phase modulation, or a combination of both. When used with unpolarized read light, the polarizer/analyzer configuration is inherently lossy.  Figure 4. Maximum theoretical diffraction efficiencies for thin hologram diffraction media. Figure 5 shows two possible orientations of a ferroelectric device with a molecular-tilt angle of =22.50 and layer thickness designed to produce one-half wave of retardance. In Fig. 5a, pure amplitude modulation is generated by aligning the off-state molecular axis with the read-light polarization. In the off-state regions, the polarization state is preserved and the read light is blocked by the analyzer. In the optically activated portions of the liquid-crystal layer, the molecules undergo a discrete 20 rotation and the read-beam polarization is rotated by 40 or 90 and subsequently transmitted by the analyzer. Figure 5. Ferroelectric liquid-crystal molecule with polarizer/analyzer arrangement oriented to induce (a) amplitude modulation and (b) phase Pure phase modulation is generated, as shown if Fig. by aligning the off-state molecular axis at -0 relative to read-light polarization. In this case, the read-beam polarization is rotated -20 by the off-state molecules and +20 by the on-state molecules. The polarization component of read light transmitted by the analyzer is discretely modulated in phase by i. The ferroelectric OASLM used in Fig. 2 incorporates a liquid-crystal layer whose thickness is designed to produce a half-wave of retardance in double pass. In the optically activated portions of the liquid-crystal layer, the molecules undergo a discrete 200 rotation and the read- beam polarization is rotated by 400. With the polarizer/analyzer configuration shown in Fig. 2, the diffracted beam is generated by an amplitude-modulated field produced by the component of the 40-degree rotated light that is orthogonal to the incident read light. The maximum theoretical first-order diffraction efficiency for a binary amplitude grating is 10&#x00025;. Owing to the 40-degree polarization rotation angle, only 64&#x00025; of the diffracted light is aligned with the analyzer. Since this particular device incorporates an uncoated photodiode, the reflectivity at the amorphous-silicon/liquid-crystal boundary is only about 24&#x00025;. Consequently, the maximum theoretical efficiency of this device is only about 1.5&#x00025;. In this configuration the polarizer rejects 50&#x00025; of unpolarized image light and thus further reduces the net efficiency to less than 1&#x00025;. (a) (b) Figure 6. Commercially available (a) and proposed (b) ferroelectric liquid-crystal configuration for spatial light modulators. Figure 6a shows the current technology in commercially available ferroelectric OASLM's. The device is optimized for use as an amplitude modulator and incorporates a liquid-crystal layer with a 22.50 molecular tilt angle. The corresponding polarization rotation angle of 900 in the read beam light is well suited to applications such as video displays and incoherent-to-coherent converters. Figure 6b shows a variation of this OASLM design that is optimized for real-time holography (RTH) applications. In this case, a liquid-crystal molecular-tilt angle of 450 leads to a molecular rotation angle of 900 and a polarization rotation angle of 1800. Thus light polarized along either axis of the original molecule orientation experiences n phase modulation. In principle, this device should yield a net efficiency of 40&#x00025; with unpolarized light. High-tilt-angle ferroelectric liquid-crystal media exist, but generally lack the smectic-A phase that is required to achieve the necessary molecular alignment. Successful incorporation of high-tilt-angle media into OASLM architectures should significantly enhance their diffraction efficiencies and hence their usefulness in RTH. 7. Commercially available (a) and proposed (b) nematic liquid- crystal spatial light modulator configurations. Alternatively, commercially available &#x0005B;14&#x0005D; parallel aligned (PAL) nematic devices produce analog diffraction holograms with demonstrated efficiencies in excess of 30&#x00025;. Unfortunately, the phase modulation occurs for only one linear polarization, reducing the overall diffraction efficiency to about 15&#x00025; for unpolarized light. Figure 7a shows a schematic of the commercially available PAL nematic OASLM. In the absence of an applied voltage, the liquid-crystal molecules are aligned as shown. In the presence of an applied voltage, the molecules rotate to align themselves with the electric field. The degree of rotationisproportionaltothevoltage. Lightpolarized along the direction of the initial molecule orientation will experience a refractive index that varies with the applied voltage. Note that optimization as an amplitude modulator requires the read light to be polarized at 450 relative to the long axis of the unbiased molecules and the thickness to be such that the maximum phase retardance is 7r. Optimization as a phase hologram however requires the read light to be polarized along the long axis of the unbiased molecules and the thickness to be such that the maximum phase retardance is not T, but 3.6 in accordance with Fig. 4. Figure 7b shows a design modification that would lead to phase modulation for both polarization components. In this configuration, a thin film quarter wave plate has been added between the reflective layer and the liquid-crystal layer. A linearly polarized component of incident light will be rotated 900 in double passing the quarter wave layer. Consequently, the linear polarization component aligned with the unbiased molecules will experience the phase grating on the first pass through the liquid-crystal layer. The orthogonal polarization will experience the phase grating on the return pass. The liquid-crystal layer must now be a factor-of-two thicker to achieve the same phase retardance in a single pass. This concept has been demonstrated using a parallel aligned nematic electrically addressed SLM with a conventional quarter wave plate and mirror, &#x0005B;15&#x0005D; but has not been demonstrated in an OASLM device. Resolution Electric field fringing effects in the photosensor, liquid- crystal and reflecting layers limit the optical fringe density that can effectively be translated into a phase hologram. Commercially available OASLM's typically experience reduced diffraction efficiencies at spatial frequencies greater than 20 to 30 1/mm. This in turn limits the severity of aberration that can be corrected in this application. The required resolution is determined by both the severity of the aberration and amount of demagnification that occurs in propagating the beacon light from the primary mirror to the pupil plane containing the OASLM. Improving the resolution to &gt; 100 1/mm while maintaining maximum diffraction efficiency should make these devices adequate for a range of interesting applications. Table 1. OASLM performance characteristics. commercially desiredfor available RTH C i Conclusions seems to be on video display applications. The requirements for this application are close, but not identical, to those for RTH. In order for RTH to be competitive with conventional adaptive imaging, improvements in OASLM efficiency and resolution are essential. Efficiencies of 30&#x00025; to 40&#x00025; are theoretically possible and would make RTH competitive with Table conventional OPD convntinal correction orrctio techniques. PD tehniues. Tabe summarizes the capabilities of commercially available OASLM's and the performance characteristics required for holographically compensated imaging.</p></body>
<back>
<ref-list>
<ref id="r1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Jeys</surname><given-names>T. H.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>The Lincoln Laboratory Journal</source> <volume>4</volume>, <fpage>133</fpage>, (<year>1991</year>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Fugate</surname><given-names>R. Q.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ellerbroek</surname><given-names>B. L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Higgins</surname><given-names>C. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jelonek</surname><given-names>M. P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lange</surname><given-names>W. J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Slavin</surname><given-names>A. C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wild</surname><given-names>W. J.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>2 generations of laser-guide-star adaptive-optics experiments at the Starfire Optical-Range</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>J. Opt. Soc. Am A-Optics Image</source> <volume>11</volume>, <fpage>310</fpage>-<lpage>324</lpage>, (<year>1994</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/JOSAA.11.000310</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Love</surname><given-names>G. D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Major</surname><given-names>J. V.</given-names></name><name><surname>Purvis</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Liquid-crystal prisms for tip-tilt adaptive optics</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Opt. Lett.</source>, <volume>19</volume>, <fpage>1170</fpage>-<lpage>1172</lpage>, (<year>1994</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/OL.19.001170</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Love</surname><given-names>G. D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Fender</surname><given-names>J. S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Restaino</surname><given-names>S. R.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Adaptive wavefront shaping with liquid crystals</article-title>,&#x0201D; in <source>Optics  Photonics News</source> <volume>6</volume>, <fpage>16</fpage>-<lpage>21</lpage>, (<year>1995</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/OPN.6.10.000016</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Goodman</surname><given-names>J. W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jackson</surname><given-names>D. W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lehmann</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Knotts</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Experiments in long-distance holographic imagery</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Appl. Opt.</source> <volume>8</volume>, <fpage>1581</fpage>-<lpage>1586</lpage>, (<year>1969</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/AO.8.001581</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Munch</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wuerker</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Holographic technique for correcting aberrations in a telescope</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Appl. Opt.</source> <volume>28</volume>, <fpage>1312</fpage>-<lpage>1317</lpage>, (<year>1989</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/AO.28.001312</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r7"><label>7</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Andersen</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Munch</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Veitch</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Holographic correction of large telescope primaries by proximal, off-axis beacons</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Appl. Opt.</source> <volume>35</volume>, <fpage>603</fpage>-<lpage>608</lpage>, (<year>1996</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/AO.35.000603</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r8"><label>8</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kramer</surname><given-names>M. A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wetterer</surname><given-names>C. J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Martinez</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>One-way imaging through an aberrator with spatially incoherent-light by using an optically addressed spatial light-modulator</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Appl. Opt.</source> <volume>30</volume>, <fpage>3319</fpage>-<lpage>3323</lpage>, (<year>1991</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/AO.30.003319</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r9"><label>9</label><mixed-citation publication-type="confproc"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Gruneisen</surname><given-names>M. T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Peters</surname><given-names>K. W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Deaton</surname><given-names>T. F.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Compensating primary mirror distortions in astronomical telescopes with real-time holography</article-title>&#x0201D; In <source>Nonlinear Optics: Materials, Fundamentals and - NLO 96Maui HI, July 1996</source> Paper <fpage content-type="conf-paper">NPdP1</fpage>. <person-group person-group-type="editor"><name><surname>Gruneisen</surname><given-names>M. T.</given-names></name>, <name><surname>Peters</surname><given-names>K. W.</given-names></name>, <name><surname>Wilkes</surname><given-names>J. M.</given-names></name>, and <name><surname>Peterson</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;Compensating Primary Mirror Distortions in Astronomical Telescopes with Real-Time Holography,&#x0201D; <conf-name>IEEE Lasers and Electro-Optics Society 1996 Annual Meeting</conf-name>, <conf-loc>Boston MA</conf-loc>, <conf-date>November 1996</conf-date> Paper TuAA1.</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r10"><label>10</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yariv</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Koch</surname><given-names>T. L.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>One-way coherent imaging through a distorting medium using four-wave mixing</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Opt. Lett.</source>, <volume>7</volume>, <fpage>113</fpage>-<lpage>115</lpage>, (<year>1982</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/OL.7.000113</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r11"><label>11</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Fischer</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Cronin-Golomb</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>White</surname><given-names>J. O.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yariv</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Real-time phase conjugate window for one-way optical field imaging through a distortion</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Appl. Phys. Lett.</source>, <volume>41</volume>, <fpage>141</fpage>-<lpage>143</lpage>, (<year>1982</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.93431</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r12"><label>12</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>MacDonald</surname><given-names>K. R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Tompkin</surname><given-names>W. R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Boyd</surname><given-names>R. W.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Passive one-way aberration correction using four-wave mixing</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Ont. Lett.</source> <volume>13</volume>, <fpage>485</fpage>-<lpage>487</lpage>, (<year>1988</year>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r13"><label>13</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Handschy</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>O&#x02019;Callaghan</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name></person-group> <article-title>Phillips Laboratory/Displaytech Technical Report, PL-TN--92-1038</article-title></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r14"><label>14</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Hamamatsu technical data sheets for model X5641 PAL-SLM parallel aligned nematic liquid-crystal spatial light modulator and model X4601 FLC-SLM ferroelectric liquid-crystal spatial light modulator</article-title>.</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r15"><label>15</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Love</surname><given-names>G. D.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Liquid-crystal phase modulator for unpolarized light</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Appl. Opt.</source> <volume>32</volume>, <fpage>2222</fpage>-<lpage>2223</lpage>(<year>1993</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/AO.32.002222</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></book-part></book-part-wrapper>
