<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0"
  xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <collection-meta collection-type="conf">
    <conference content-type="conf-name">
      <conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name>
      <conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym>
    </conference>
    <conference content-type="conf-other-meta">
      <conf-date content-type="start"> <day>17</day> <month>03</month> <year>1997</year></conf-date>
      <conf-date content-type="end"> <day>19</day> <month>03</month> <year>1997</year></conf-date>
      <conf-loc>Nevada, <country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc>
    </conference>
  </collection-meta>
  <collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
    <title-group>
      <title>SLM Materials and Sructures</title>
      <alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/>
    </title-group>
  </collection-meta>
  <collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
    <title-group>
      <title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title>
    </title-group>
    <volume-in-collection>
      <volume-number>14</volume-number>
      <volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title>
    </volume-in-collection>
  </collection-meta>
  <book-meta>
    <book-title-group>
      <book-title>Spatial Light Modulators</book-title>
    </book-title-group>
    <contrib-group>
      <contrib contrib-type="editor">
        <name>
          <surname>Burdge</surname>
          <given-names>Geoffrey</given-names>
        </name>
      </contrib>
      <contrib contrib-type="editor">
        <name>
          <surname>Esener</surname>
          <given-names>Sadik C.</given-names>
        </name>
      </contrib>
    </contrib-group>
    <pub-date publication-format="electronic">
      <day>17</day>
      <month>03</month>
      <year>1997</year>
    </pub-date>
  </book-meta>
  <book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
    <book-part-meta>
      <title-group>
        <title>A new high resolution FLCVLSI Spatial Light Modulator</title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <name>
            <surname>Rankin</surname>
            <given-names>I. D.</given-names>
          </name>
          <xref rid="aff4" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <name>
            <surname>Burns</surname>
            <given-names>D. C.</given-names>
          </name>
          <xref rid="aff4" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref>
          <xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>*</sup></xref>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <name>
            <surname>O&#x02019;Hara</surname>
            <given-names>A.</given-names>
          </name>
          <xref rid="aff4" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref>
          <xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff"><sup>**</sup></xref>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <name>
            <surname>Bodammer</surname>
            <given-names>G.</given-names>
          </name>
          <xref rid="aff4" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref>
          <xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff"><sup>**</sup></xref>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <name>
            <surname>Stevenson</surname>
            <given-names>J. T. M.</given-names>
          </name>
          <xref rid="aff4" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <name>
            <surname>Underwood</surname>
            <given-names>I.</given-names>
          </name>
          <xref rid="aff4" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <name>
            <surname>Vass</surname>
            <given-names>D. G.</given-names>
          </name>
          <xref rid="aff4" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref>
          <xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff"><sup>**</sup></xref>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <name>
            <surname>Worboys</surname>
            <given-names>M. R.</given-names>
          </name>
          <xref rid="aff4" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref>
          <xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff"><sup>***</sup></xref>
        </contrib>
        <aff id="aff1"> <label>*</label>Now at Xilinx Development Corporation, 44 Mortonhall Gate,
          Edinburgh, <country country="GB">U.K.</country></aff>
        <aff id="aff2"> <label>**</label>Department of Physics and Astronomy, The University of
          Edinburgh</aff>
        <aff id="aff3"> <label>*</label>GEC-Marconi Research Centre, West Hanningfield Road,
          Chelmsford, Essex, <country country="GB">U.K.</country></aff>
        <aff id="aff4"> <label>1</label>Department of Electrical Engineering, The University of
          Edinburgh, The Kings Buildings, Mayfield Road, Edinburgh, EH9 3JL, <country country="GB"
          >U.K.</country></aff>
      </contrib-group>
      <elocation-id>89</elocation-id>
      <permissions>
        <copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
        <copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
        <copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
        <license license-type="open-access">
          <license-p>closed</license-p>
        </license>
      </permissions>
      <abstract>
        <p>Recent advances in custom silicon design, post-processing technology and the use of new
          commercially available ferroelectric liquid crystal (FLC) mixtures has led us to develop a
          faster and higher resolution backplane. The backplane does not only have uses in
          incoherent illumination systems such as displays&#x0005B;1&#x0005D; but in coherent
          systems such as optical computing where a high optical through-put is desired.</p>
      </abstract>
      <kwd-group kwd-group-type="OCIS">
        <title>OCIS codes</title>
        <kwd>SLM</kwd>
        <kwd>VLSI</kwd>
        <kwd>FLC</kwd>
        <kwd>DRAM pixel</kwd>
        <kwd>display</kwd>
      </kwd-group>
      <counts>
        <book-page-count count="5"/>
      </counts>
    </book-part-meta>
    <body>
      <p>Introduction The 512SLM was designed by Burns&#x0005B;2&#x0005D; and fabricated in 1996 by
        AMS using a 1.2&#x0005B;tm 5.5V n-well CAE (epitaxial wafer, n-well, double polysilicon and
        double metal) CMOS process. This device incorporates an enhanced DRAM pixel, which
        drastically reduces the effects of pixel charge leakage and a better addressing architecture
        to simplify real-time digital video preprocessing. The device uses essentially the same
        peripheral addressing circuitry as the SBS256 SRAM-XOR SLM&#x0005B;3&#x0005D; making its
        implementation quick and reliable. With the device having the same physical dimensions as
        the SBS256 SRAM-XOR SLM, permitted the utilisation of many of the optical / packaging
        components already available. The 512SLM consists of a 512 x 512 array of enhanced DRAM
        style pixels. Each pixel is enlarged using the in-house CMP post processing technique which
        increases the pixel mirror dimensions to I8.4tm x 18.4&#x0005B;tm on a 20pm pitch (see
        figure 1). This corresponds to an array area of 1.0486cm (10.24mm x 10.24mm) with a pixel
        fill factor of 85&#x00025;. The backplane addressing circuitry (figure 2) is based on a
        modified multiple serial shift register architecture, consisting of 64 x 8 bit shift
        registers and a decoder to write an assembled column of data (512 pixels) onto the array.
        The device has 64 data lines and 15 control lines controlling its operation. Instead of the
        rolling '0' (active low) column shift register, as used by the 176SLM, a column address
        decoder exists. This means that the device can be addressed on a column-by-column basis for
        a digital video sequential scan or in an interlaced format suiting analogue PAL and NTSC
        video. Data can be loaded onto the array at clock speeds of up to 48MHz (1.92GBits/s),
        giving rise to an electrical frame address rate of 8kHz. The backplane also includes support
        circuitry for image inversion which is necessary when addressing FLC in a DC charge
        balancing mode. Figure 1: SEM micrographs showing the 512SLM before /after in-house CMP
        planarisation. Enhanced DRAM pixel Each pixel incorporates a pMOS pass transistor and a pMOS
        storage transistor capacitor along with the appropriate data, address and power lines.
        Figure 3 demonstrates the MOS model of the pixel and its silicon implementation. Figure 4
        shows a diagrammatic cross sectional view of the enhanced DRAM pixel. The motivation for
        this particular pixel design was driven by the desire to have a quick array addressing time
        whilst storing enough charge and furthermore, to compensate for leakage effects fully switch
        the liquid crystal at a single pixel. Figure 3: Enhanced DRAM pixel MOS model and its
        silicon implementation. Figure 4: Cross sectional view of the enhanced DRAM pixel. The
        concept of using what is essentially a dual transistor pixel is not new since a MOS storage
        transistor capacitance is the largest attainable. Previous implementations of this design
        suffered severely from the photoelectric effect since generated electron-hole pairs make the
        transistor active regions more 'leaky'. The enhanced DRAM pixel overcomes these problems by
        embedding the whole pixel array in an n-well on top of a grounded p-substrate. The following
        points detail and summarise the advantage of the enhanced DRAM pixel design. * Pixel
        capacitance is large due to the large gate oxide of the pMOS storage capacitor. * Grounded
        p-substrate acts as a charge collector absorbing the photoelectric carriers deep within the
        substrate. * n-well eliminates all leakage currents associated with the substrate wafer. *
        Planarised pixel mirrors shield the MOS capacitor and the address and data lines. *
        Parasitic capacitances do not degrade the effectiveness of the storage capacitance since
        storage capacitance is much larger. The amount of charge required within a pixel gate time
        period (typically 30ns) to fully switch the liquid crystal can be obtained experimentally by
        measuring the amount of current required to reverse the polarisation state of the liquid
        crystal material. Qswach 2APs &#x0005B;1&#x0005D; Equation 1 describes this operation and
        thus it was calculated that 240fC was required to switch the liquid crystal over a single 2
        0 tm x 20pm pixel; A = area (20m x 20ptm) and Ps = liquid crystal spontaneous polarisation
        (-30nC/cm or 0.3fC/ .m 2 ).The overall storage capacitance of the enhanced pixel is
        approximately 200fF of which the pMOS capacitor contributes 175fF, the VDD / GATE / MIRROR
        capacitance's contribute 15fF and the FLC pixel capacitance contributes 10fF (assuming a
        2.4g.m cell gap). If 5 Volts can be applied across the pMOS storage capacitor, the amount of
        charge stored is approximatelyl1000fC, fours times that required forotheparticular fo h
        atclr-Cmteilue.Ti FLC materialused. This isgood sgo of a planarised 512SLM (array fully
        considering that for any image degradation to occur, the pixel will have had to have lost
        three quarters of its full charge capacity.</p>
      <p>512SLM - An optical characterisation Figure 5 depicts the charging and discharging
        characteristics of a planarised 512SLM under a continuous 0.5mW/cm2 He-Ne illumination. The
        measurements where taken using a simple optical arrangement and a fast 10MHz calibrated
        photodiode/amplifier. The optical system consists of a collimated 5mW He-Ne laser, a
        polarising beamsplitter, 1/2 wave plate, SLM and lense with the photodiode at its focal
        point. Figure 6 shows the effect of array charge leakage (FWHM) under different illumination
        levels. When compared to the 176SLM, the 512SLM is approximately 250 (&#x000B1;10&#x00025;)
        times slower at half image discharge, under a continuous 0.5mW/cm2 He-Ne illumination. In
        contrast, a SPICE 'dark' simulation showed that the enhanced pixels natural electrical
        discharge time was extremely long. The device also performs well with respect to its charge
        storage capability during the positive and negative addressing cycles Figure 5: Image
        degradation effects (charge leakage) during the -ve and +ve addressing cycles
        oaaarised51'2SLMarrayfullyON '', Figure 6: Effect of Photo-induced charge leakage on a
        planarised 512SLM.(100&#x00025; laser transmission corresponds to 0.5mW/cm 2 )
        512SLMperformance Figure 7demonstratesthefunctionality of the
        SLM.ThedevicedemonstratedhasaarrayCRof approximately 12:1 under a He-Ne illumination. Figure
        7: Single bitplane images on a planarised 512SLM. (a: A single bitplane image; b: A single
        dithered bitplane image)</p>
      <p>Conclusion From the DRAM devices analysed, the 512SLM performed best under high intensity
        illumination. It Itiexpctdthtawomtaplaarsaton that a two metal planarisation is expected
        process would make the device as robust as SRAMbaseddevices. Figure8comparesthe planarised
        176SLM and 512SLM half image degradation times versus illumination intensity on a log scale.
        As you would expect with the photoelectric effect, the image degradation is inversely
        proportional to the illumination intensity (1/I). Extrapolation of this graph enables the
        determination of the 512SLMs performance under higher illumination intensities outwith the
        region tested. Figure 8: Image degradation comparison of a 176 and 512 SLM. (100&#x00025;
        Laser Transmission corresponds to 0.5mW/cm 2 )</p>
      <p>Acknowledgments The 512 x512 display backplane was designed Z by D.C.Burns and developed at
        the University of Edinburgh through the UK Engineering and Physical Science Research
        Councils SCIOS Programme. I.D.Rankin acknowledges his suethpfo h KEa sineering n
        PhysicalScienceResearchCouncilandhisCASE sponsorship from GEC-Marconi Research Centre.</p>
    </body>
    <back>
      <ref-list>
        <ref id="r1">
          <label>1</label>
          <mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name>
            <surname>Rankin</surname>
            <given-names>I.D.</given-names>
            </name><etal/></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Full colour miniature
            display</article-title>&#x0201D;, <source>Proc SPIE</source>
            <volume>2651</volume>(<issue>1196</issue>)
            <fpage>16</fpage>-<lpage>24</lpage></mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="r2">
          <label>2</label>
          <mixed-citation publication-type="confproc"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name>
            <surname>Underwood</surname>
            <given-names>I.</given-names>
            </name><etal/></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Advances in pixel design and
            wafer fabrication for LC over silicon SLMs</article-title>&#x0201D;, <conf-name>Digest
            of IEEE/LEOS Summer Topical Meeting on Smart Pixels</conf-name>,
            (<year>1996</year>)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="r3">
          <label>3</label>
          <mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name>
            <surname>Rankin</surname>
            <given-names>I.D.</given-names>
            </name><etal/></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Full Colour Images on a Binary
            Spatial Light Modulator</article-title>&#x0201D;, <conf-name>Conference Digest for
            FLC&#x02019;95</conf-name>, <conf-date>23-27th July 1995</conf-date>,
            <fpage>231</fpage>-<lpage>2</lpage>.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    </back>
  </book-part>
</book-part-wrapper>
