<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
<collection-meta collection-type="conf">
<conference content-type="conf-name"><conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name><conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym></conference>
<conference content-type="conf-other-meta"><conf-date content-type="start">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-date content-type="end">
<day>19</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-loc>Nevada, 
<country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc></conference></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
<title-group>
<title>SLM Applications</title>
<alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/></title-group></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
<title-group>
<title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title></title-group>
<volume-in-collection>
<volume-number>14</volume-number>
<volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title></volume-in-collection></collection-meta>
<book-meta>
<book-title-group>
<book-title>Spatial Light Modulators</book-title></book-title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Burdge</surname><given-names>Geoffrey</given-names></name></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>Sadik C.</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group>
<pub-date publication-format="electronic">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></pub-date></book-meta>
<book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
<book-part-meta>
<title-group>
<title>Image Processing and Optical Storage in a Resonator with an OASLM</title></title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Rehn</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Kowarschik</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref><xref rid="cor1" ref-type="corresp"><sup>*</sup></xref></contrib>
<aff id="aff1">
<label>1</label>Friedrich-Schiller-University Jena, Institute of Applied Optics Fr&#x000F6;belstieg 1, 07743 Jena, 
<country country="DE">Germany</country></aff></contrib-group>
<author-notes>
<corresp id="cor1">
<label>*</label> phone +49-3641-636745 fax +49-3641-635986 email <email>oer@uni-jena.de</email></corresp></author-notes>
<elocation-id>255</elocation-id>
<permissions>
<copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
<copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
<copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
<license license-type="open-access">
<license-p>closed</license-p></license></permissions>
<abstract>
<p>It is demonstrated that optical information can be stored and processed in resonators which include an OASLM and show a bistable behavior.</p></abstract>
<kwd-group kwd-group-type="OCIS">
<title>OCIS codes</title>
<kwd>Analog optical image processing</kwd>
<kwd>spatial light modulators</kwd>
<kwd>photorefractive materials</kwd>
<kwd>optical data storage</kwd>
<kwd>interferometry</kwd></kwd-group>
<counts>
<book-page-count count="3"/></counts></book-part-meta>
<body>
<p>Introduction Optically addressable spatial light modulators (OASLM's) are not only of use for the introduction of an incoherent intensity distribution to a coherent optical system, but also to realize optical image processing and storage if the same coherent beam is used to write and to read out the OASLM. In our contribution we report investigations on several optical systems, where the information that was read out coherently from a OASLM is processed by an optical system and then fed back to the rear side of the OASLM. Similar systems have been described in the literature for example to compensate wavefront aberrations in adaptive optics &#x0005B;I&#x0005D;, or as a Fabry-Perot type OASLM with internal feedback &#x0005B;2&#x0005D;. We want to demonstrate the image process ing and storage capabilities of such systems and will show howbothamplitudeandphaseofabeamcanbeusedfor the processing.</p>
<p>Interferometrically Controlled Feedback 10 1+ sketched M cos(9 K(I)) in Fig.1. The feed- The optical arrangement ..I is I = - (1) back is realized with the help of a Michelson interferome ter. The interference pattern formed by one beam reflected at a mirror and a second beam that reads out the OASLM is imaged onto the rear side of this element. So the result- interference intensity will influence the interference pattern. Fig. I Michelson interferometer with feedback Fi-2Interferencefringesobtainedwiththefeedback F interferometer, according to eq.(1) With K(I) being the intensity-to-phase transfer character istics of the OASLM and p the phase of the beam reflected at the mirror (which can be easily adjusted by shifting the mirror with a piezo actuator), the interference is given by I Fig. 2 shows an experimental result with an obvious steep ening of the slopes of the sine function due to the feed back. This effect will be the subject of further investiga tions since the phase sensitivity of the interferometer is increased considerably at the steeper slopes. Unfortu- nately, the used OASLM was not sensitive enough (i.e. the phase shift that could be obtained optically was too small) to yield a saw-tooth function. Such a curve we expect from eq.(1) in the case of a linear transfer curve of the OASLM without saturation effects in a certain intensity range. However, if the arrangement works as desired, we obtain a technique for an all-optical phase (mod 27)-to- intensity conversion. In addition, such a system is expected to react sensitively to small changes of the input intensity.</p>
<p>Polarization Controlled Feedback If a birefringent film such Z' as nematic liquid crystals is used for phase modulation, the intensity at the rear side causes a rotation of the polarization plane of the reading beam. The polarizing beam splitter (PBS) transmits only those components where the angle of polarization was rotated by the OASLM &#x0005B;34&#x0005D;. The setup is shown sche- matically in Fig. 3. The OASLM is rotated by 45 by the optical axis with respect to the plane polarization of the light that is transmitted by the PBS. Fi. 3 Feedback controlled by a polarizing beam splitter (PBS). The OASLM is rotated by 450 with respect to the opticalaxis Fig. 4 Graphic solution of eq(2). The points of intersection correspond to solutions of the equation. For an appropriate K(I) an bistable or multistable behavior is obtained The Jones formalism delivers the intensity after the PBS as = 10 +K(1)) (2) with a constant phase term (Po given by the AC voltage at the OASLM and the optically induced phase change K(1) that was measured in a preliminary experiment. The behavior of such a system can be easily understood with the help of a graphic solution &#x0005B;2&#x0005D; of these equations (Fig. 4). Fig.5 Hysteresisobtainedforavaryingincidentintensity If the intensity that falls onto the system and reads out the OASLM is varied and the intensity within the loop is measured, a hysteresis is obtained. So. introducing an external intensity distribution to the rear side of the OASLM. the system can switch to a different state. So this distribution can be stored in the feedback system. Since the system has to decide whether an intensity value is large enough to cause a switch or not, a (multiple) threshold operation is carried out to the external intensity distribution. Novelty Filter Feedback In &#x0005B;5&#x0005D; we reported observations of transverse optical structures observed in a resonator as shown in Fig. 6 where a photorefractive novelty filter &#x0005B;6&#x0005D; is used to control the feedback to the OASLM. Fig. 6 Feedback controlled by a photorefractive novelty filter Besides this effect, that such an arrangement is able to store an external intensity distribution (Fig. 7) for a time period given b, the response time of the photorefractive barium titanate crystal. The external intensity was imaged to the rear side of the OASI\ tfor onlt&#x00025; 0.8otS. I ig. 7 Optical storage of an incoherent intensity distribu-tion A graphic solution (Fig. 8) is obtained in the same way such as in Fig. 4 with a phase transfer characteristics ob- tained in &#x0005B;7&#x0005D; that is valid for a time range much shorter than the photorefractive response time. Again the points of intersection of the two curves show the solutions of the s\Stemandhowalexternalintensitycanswitchthein- tensity within the resonator to a higher value. K(1) Ano\elty filter characteristics (p(a.u.) Fig. 8 Graphic solution for the setup of Fig. 6. (novelt\ filter phase transfer characteristics &#x0005B;7&#x0005D;) Finall\ the system can be considered as a technique for the temporar\ magnification of transient phase changes of the Input beam. Since for such phase changes the novelty filter characteristics is shift slightly to the left (Fig. 8), the ob-tamed points of intersection show that the phase of the beam that leaves the OASLM is enhanced with respect to the input phase value.</p>
<p>Conclusions ClosedloopsystemswithanOASLMandafeedback controlling element can exhibit a nonlinear behavior for cv light in the mWcm range. It was demonstrated that such optical arrangements can serve as a linear phase-to-intensity converter, for optical image processing such as for thresholding, and for optical storage not in a sensitive medium but in a bistable optical arrangement. Though the described effects were demonstrated with a nematic liquid crystal OASLM, in most cases any other type of OASLM with a sufficient phase shift can be used. Only for the experiments with the polarization controlled feedback an OASLM is needed where the writing beam changes the birefringence and. this way, the polarization of the reading beam.</p>
<p>Acknowledgment The authors acknowledge support by the Deutsche For- schungsgemeinschaft within the project INKI/AI "Innovationskolleg Optische Informationstechnik".</p></body>
<back>
<ref-list>
<ref id="r1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="patent"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>O'Meara</surname><given-names>T. h.</given-names></name><name><surname>Valley</surname><given-names>G. C.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>U. S. Patent Nr.</source> <patent>5090795</patent></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kompanets</surname><given-names>I. N.</given-names></name><name><surname>Parfenov</surname><given-names>A. V.</given-names></name><name><surname>Popov</surname><given-names>Yu. M.</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>Multistability in optical transmittance of spatial light modulators with internal feedback</article-title>, <source>Opt. Commun.</source> <volume>36</volume>, (<year>1981</year>), <fpage>417</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/0030-4018(81)90256-X</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Vasiliev</surname><given-names>A. A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kompanets</surname><given-names>I. N.</given-names></name><name><surname>Parfenov</surname><given-names>A. V.</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>Advances in development and applications of optically controlled liquid crystal spatial light modulators</article-title>, <source>Optik</source> <volume>67</volume>, (<year>1984</year>), <fpage>223</fpage></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Armitage</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Thackara</surname><given-names>J. I.</given-names></name><name><surname>Eades</surname><given-names>W. D.</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>Photoadressed liquid crystal spatial light modulators</article-title>, <source>Appl. Opt.</source> <volume>28</volume>, (<year>1989</year>), <fpage>4763</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/AO.28.004763</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Rehn</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kowarschik</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>Transverse Optical Structures in a Ring Resonator with Intensity-Phase Coupling</article-title>, <source>Opt. Lett.</source> <volume>21</volume>, <issue>18</issue>, (<year>1996</year>), <fpage>1505</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/OL.21.001505</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Anderson</surname><given-names>D. Z.</given-names></name><name><surname>Feinberg</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>Optical Novelty Filters</article-title><source>IEEE Journ Quant El</source> <volume>25</volume>, (<year>1989</year>), <fpage>635</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1109/3.18576</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r7"><label>7</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Rehn</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kowarschik</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>Beam fanning novelty filter with enhanced dynamic phase resolution</article-title><source>Appl. Opt.</source> <volume>34</volume>, (<year>1995</year>), <fpage>4907</fpage>-<lpage>4911</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/AO.34.004907</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></book-part></book-part-wrapper>
