<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">-->
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0"
  xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <collection-meta collection-type="conf">
    <conference content-type="conf-name">
      <conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name>
      <conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym>
    </conference>
    <conference content-type="conf-other-meta">
      <conf-date content-type="start">
        <day>17</day>
        <month>03</month>
        <year>1997</year>
      </conf-date>
      <conf-date content-type="end">
        <day>19</day>
        <month>03</month>
        <year>1997</year>
      </conf-date>
      <conf-loc>Nevada, <country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc>
    </conference>
  </collection-meta>
  <collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
    <title-group>
      <title>VLSI-based SLMs</title>
      <alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/>
    </title-group>
  </collection-meta>
  <collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
    <title-group>
      <title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title>
    </title-group>
    <volume-in-collection>
      <volume-number>14</volume-number>
      <volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title>
    </volume-in-collection>
  </collection-meta>
  <book-meta>
    <book-title-group>
      <book-title>Spatial Light Modulators (TOPS)</book-title>
    </book-title-group>
    <contrib-group>
      <contrib contrib-type="editor">
        <name>
          <surname>Burdge</surname>
          <given-names>Geoffrey</given-names>
        </name>
      </contrib>
      <contrib contrib-type="editor">
        <name>
          <surname>Esener</surname>
          <given-names>Sadik C.</given-names>
        </name>
      </contrib>
    </contrib-group>
    <pub-date publication-format="electronic">
      <day>17</day>
      <month>03</month>
      <year>1997</year>
    </pub-date>
  </book-meta>
  <book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
    <book-part-meta>
      <title-group>
        <title>Optoelectronic/VLSI</title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <name>
            <surname>Goossen</surname>
            <given-names>K.W.</given-names>
          </name>
          <xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">
            <sup>1</sup>
          </xref>
        </contrib>
        <aff id="aff1"> <label>1</label>Bell Labs, Lucent Technologies 4B-519 Crawfords Corner Road,
          Holmdel, NJ 07733</aff>
      </contrib-group>
      <elocation-id>8</elocation-id>
      <permissions>
        <copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
        <copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
        <copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
        <license license-type="open-access">
          <license-p>closed</license-p>
        </license>
      </permissions>
      <abstract>
        <p>A great goal of optics in computing is the eventual failure of electrical interconnects.
          This leads to two guiding principles for smart pixel technologies, which integrate
          optoelectronic devices to electronics for optical read-in/out. One, that the electronics
          be state-of-the-art, or, in other words, not compromised by the integration with
          optoelectronics, since the above stated goal will be reached sooner with leading edge
          electronics. Two, since a probable failure mode of electrical interconnects is a
          limitation of electrical chip pin-out, the number of optical channels per chip must be in
          the thousands, since it is apparently not until this number is reached that there will be
          a problem. Therefore, any integration process must be capable of producing such numbers of
          optoelectronic devices, preferably in a single step. Also, since currently only MQW
          modulators are available in arrays this large, that is what we use for the transmitting
          device. It is convenient that the MQW modulator also functions as a detector, but as
          described below we also have the capability of multiple levels of integration for
          dissimilar input and output devices.</p>
      </abstract>
      <counts>
        <book-page-count count="3"/>
      </counts>
    </book-part-meta>
    <body>
      <p>A great goal of optics in computing is the eventual failure of electrical interconnects.
        This leads to two guiding principles for smart pixel technologies, which integrate
        optoelectronic devices to electronics for optical read-in/out. One, that the electronics be
        state-of-the-art, or, in other words, not compromised by the integration with
        optoelectronics, since the above stated goal will be reached sooner with leading edge
        electronics. Two, since a probable failure mode of electrical interconnects is a limitation
        of electrical chip pin-out, the number of optical channels per chip must be in the
        thousands, since it is apparently not until this number is reached that there will be a
        problem. Therefore, any integration process must be capable of producing such numbers of
        optoelectronic devices, preferably in a single step. Also, since currently only MQW
        modulators are available in arrays this large, that is what we use for the transmitting
        device. It is convenient that the MQW modulator also functions as a detector, but as
        described below we also have the capability of multiple levels of integration for dissimilar
        input and output devices. The only integration technique that suffices both of the preceding
        criteria is flip-chip bonding, since it is a low temperature process and attaches many
        devices at once. We have shown that thousands of solder pads can be produced on chips by
        photolithography and evaporation. Using our commercial bonding machine, manufactured by
        Research Devices in Piscataway, New Jersey, aligning an optoelectronic chip laterally to a
        Si CMOS chip can be routinely performed to 2 micron accuracy. Thus attaching thousandsof
        high speed devices in a single step is routine. The temperatures involved are below 200 oC.
        and so do not affect the Si electronics. We have innovated on the process of flip-chip
        bonding, particularly for optoelectronics devices. The need for this is because the best MQW
        modulators operate at a wavelength of 850 nm &#x0005B;K.W. Goossen, M.B. Santos, J.E.
        Cunningham and W.Y. Jan, IEEE Photon. Tech. Lett. 5, 1392 (1993)&#x0005D;. However, the GaAs
        substrate of such modulators is opaque at that wavelength. Therefore, we remove it after the
        bonding &#x0005B;K.W. Goossen, J.E. Cunningham and W.Y. Jan, IEEE Photon. Tech. Lett. 5, 776
        (1993)&#x0005D;. This optoelectronic/VLSI process arranges so that both the n and p contacts
        of the diodes are brought to the surface and are coplanar, and defines each device so that
        it is electrically isolated from its neighbors. Solder is deposited on one or both of the Si
        and GaAs chips, and the chips are bonded together. We find that gold-coated tin works well
        as a solder and good bonding occurs by tacking the chips together at an elevated temperature
        and pressure without the need for reflow. Then epoxy is wicked between the chips by
        capillary action. The epoxy both provides mechanical stability, and protects the front
        surfaces of the chips during the next step, which is the removal of the GaAs substrate. This
        is done by chemical etching. The etch is stopped by a stop-etch layer which has been placed
        between the GaAs substrate and the device layers. The epoxy may subsequently be removed if
        necessary, e.g., to expose wire-bond pads. We demonstrated arrays of bonded modulators and
        simple circuits in &#x0005B;K.W. Goossen, J.A. Walker, L.A. D'Asaro, S.P. Hui, B. Tseng, R.
        Leibenguth, D. Kossives, D.D. Bacon, D. Dahringer, L.M.F. Chirovsky, A.L. Lentine and D.A.B.
        Miller, IEEE Photon. Tech. Lett. 7, 360 (1995)&#x0005D;. Our largest chips to date are 7x7
        mm Si chips with 140000-450000 CMOS gates with a 64x68 array of modulators arranged in a
        5.5x5.5 mm field. We have produced such chips with 100 &#x00025; modulator yield, but
        typically have about 5 nonworking diodes, with the yield reduction mostly due to defects in
        the modulators. Thus for these larger chips our device yield is about 99.9&#x00025;. That
        our circuits are not compromised by the optoelectronic integration is demonstrated since
        they have been designed with standard modeling tools and work accordingly. We have shown
        switching circuits in 0.8 pm CMOS operating with clocks of 700 Mbit/sec &#x0005B;A.L.
        Lentine, K.W. Goossen, J.A. Walker, L.M.F. Chirovsky, L.A. D'Asaro, S.P. Hui, B.T. Tseng, R.
        Leibenguth, D. Kossives, D. Dahringer, D. Bacon, T. Woodward, and D.A.B. Miller, IEEE
        Photon. Tech. Lett. 8, 221 (1996)&#x0005D;. An important advance of the hybrid CMOS-SEED
        process was demonstrated in &#x0005B;A. Krishnamoorthy, A.L. Lentine, K.W. Goossen, J.A.
        Walker, T.K. Woodward, J.E. Ford, G.F. Aplin, L.A. D'Asaro, S.P. Hui, B. Tseng, R.
        Leibenguth, D. Kossives, D. Dahringer, L.M.F. Chirovsky, and D.A.B. Miller, IEEE Photon.
        Tech. Lett. 7, 1288 (1995)&#x0005D;. Here it was shown that the modulators may be bonded to
        metal interconnect layers on the Si chip directly above transistor layers, creating a
        three-dimensional optoelectronic/VLSI circuit. Typically CMOS has three levels of metal, so
        the modulators may be bonded to the top level. Thus our modulators form an optoelectronic
        overlay to the electronics, and in a sense, our mission is complete of being able to provide
        optical I/O to Si CMOS without compromising in any way its ability to form circuits. Using
        this technique we can make chips with dense modulator arrays. Our densest chips have 32x64
        modulators arranged in a 2.3x2.3 mm field. We routinely have only one or zero bad diodes in
        these dense chips, for a yield &gt; 99.95&#x00025;. The limits of yield will ultimately be
        determined by defects in the optoelectronic semiconductor. Yield limits such as missing
        solder bumps or photolithographic errors on the optoelectronic array can be screened fairly
        easily since they are regular arrays. Screening at this point is highly desirable since no
        work has been performed except the preparation of the chips which can be done on a wafer
        basis. In our rudimentary processing environment chips that are perfect in this sense appear
        possible with 100000 diodes, in a yield of at least one chip per two inch wafer. In a
        well-controlled processing environment higher yields in this sense would certainly be
        achieved. In terms of the flip-chip bonding itself, it appears that if uniform bonding
        occurs over the area of the chip, and all metalizations are present, no errors occur in the
        bonds. The substrate removal is a step that only produces errors when a gross mistake is
        made such as the epoxy not filling the space between the chips uniformly. Errors due to
        substrate removal for single chip bonding (see discussion below regarding our foundry runs)
        can be characterized on a per area basis of approximately 2 bad diodes per square
        centimeter. This leaves defects in the optoelectronic semiconductor itself, which are of two
        types. The first is literally "dirt", large (-1-10 micron) particles which are incorporated
        into the epitaxial layers during growth. These appear to occur on the order of 10/cm 2 , but
        tend to be localized so their effective yield reduction is on the order of 1/cm2 . These
        particles are almost always fatal to a device. They are easily visible after the substrate
        has been removed. Finally, there are microscopic defects. The number of these is usually
        quoted at 100-1000 cm 2 , but based on our densest array, described above, which has very
        little space between the diodes, the sensitivity of modulators to these defects is only on
        the order of &lt;1/(2.3x2.3 mm), or &lt;19/cm2 . So our current yield limit is approximately
        10-20 defects/cm 2 , mostly due to microscopic defects. It is probably reasonable to assume
        that we could cut this number in half with sufficient research, and make projections based
        on a defect density of 7.5/cm2 . This means that a dense array of 3.7x3.7 mm can be made
        perfect with reasonable yield. Now we project how many diodes we can fit into a 3.7x3.7 mm
        area to determine ultimate array size. Our current alignment accuracy is &lt;2 microns, so
        it is reasonable to assume that solder bumps of 5 microns on a side can be used in the
        future. Simply scaling our current device design from our dense chip results then in chips
        with 47,700 diodes. Scaling device area smaller than this may be beyond the capability of
        optics to handle. Removal of the substrate has other positive qualities. We have performed
        process runs where multiple chip designs are aggregated onto a single Si chip, then a
        modulator array encompassing this entire large chip is processed, and after substrate
        removal, can be sawed into the individual chips. This is the basis for our continuing
        workshop runs when in a manner like a foundry, we aggregate smaller designs into larger
        chips to reduce our workload. Our Lucent/George Mason U. workshop consisted of 16 2x2 mm
        CMOS circuit designs aggregated onto a single 8x8 mm Si chip. Each of the 16 subchips has a
        10x20 array of MQW modulators bonded onto it. The diode attachment area of these chips was
        7.8x7.8 mm. Although the problems of bonding and removing the substrate of such large chips
        were solved, another unexpected problem specific to the foundry chip remains. That is, that
        due to the geometry involved, voids are left in the epoxy. Since the foundry chips contained
        lanes of wire-bonding area separated by modulator fields, the epoxy may wick in faster or
        slower along certain paths, creating the opportunity for air to be trapped. We are working
        on this issue. The ability to do batch processing is not only useful for our foundry runs
        but also illustrates how this technology may be manufactured in a cost-effective manner.
        Another useful aspect of substrate removal is that after the substrate is removed, further
        chips may be bonded. In particular, since the modulators may be pixilated leaving spaces
        between them on the chip, we may bond another chip in the same area as the first chip and
        produce interleaved devices. Thus dissimilar devices, either separately optimized detectors
        and modulators, or detectors and lasers, may be collocated on the Si chip. We have
        demonstrated this procedure &#x0005B;K.W. Goossen, et al, to be published&#x0005D;. In
        conclusion, we have produced a technology for placing thousands of surface-normal input and
        output optoelectronic devices onto VLSI circuitry. We have demonstrated circuit clock speeds
        near 1 Gbit/sec and chips with thousands of optoelectronic devices. Thus we have the
        capability of having aggregate data flows of greater than 1 terabit/chip. Indian Hill
        Svstamfi thin nnoulated with madnsltart Fig. 1: Typical section of our optoelectronic/VLSI
        chips, showing - 17x50 pm rectangular isolated modulators above CMOS. Each modulator
        consists of 15x15 pm n and p contacts spaced by 15 Vm. The n contact is the active area and
        functions as the mirror for reflective modulation.</p>
    </body>
  </book-part>
</book-part-wrapper>
