<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
<collection-meta collection-type="conf">
<conference content-type="conf-name"><conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name><conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym></conference>
<conference content-type="conf-other-meta"><conf-date content-type="start">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-date content-type="end">
<day>19</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-loc>Nevada, 
<country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc></conference></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
<title-group>
<title>SLM Applications</title>
<alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/></title-group></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
<title-group>
<title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title></title-group>
<volume-in-collection>
<volume-number>14</volume-number>
<volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title></volume-in-collection></collection-meta>
<book-meta>
<book-title-group>
<book-title>Spatial Light Modulators</book-title></book-title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Burdge</surname><given-names>Geoffrey</given-names></name></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>Sadik C.</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group>
<pub-date publication-format="electronic">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></pub-date></book-meta>
<book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
<book-part-meta>
<title-group>
<title>Smart pixels for optical wireless applications</title></title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>O'Brien</surname><given-names>D. C.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Street</surname><given-names>A. M.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Samaras</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Edwards</surname><given-names>D. J.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Faulkner</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Parry</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Stavrinou</surname><given-names>P. N.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>K. H.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Teo</surname><given-names>C. C.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Whitehead</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<aff id="aff1">
<label>1</label>Department of Engineering Science, Parks Rd, Oxford, OX1 3PJ, 
<country country="GB">UK</country>.</aff></contrib-group>
<elocation-id>265</elocation-id>
<permissions>
<copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
<copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
<copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
<license license-type="open-access">
<license-p>closed</license-p></license></permissions>
<abstract>
<p>Most smart pixel systems use optical channels that are highly directed: Care is taken to use efficient optical paths that transfer as much energy as possible from source to detector. In this paper we describe the use of highly inefficient 'loosely directed' optical channels in wireless local area networks, and how smart pixel integration techniques can be applied to such systems. An overview of the system and its operation is presented. Techniques for meeting eyesafety regulations at the transmitter are discussed, as well as receiver design issues.</p></abstract>
<kwd-group kwd-group-type="OCIS">
<title>OCIS codes</title>
<kwd>Optical communications</kwd>
<kwd>Optoelectronics</kwd>
<kwd>Vertical cavity surface emitting lasers</kwd>
<kwd>Diffractive optics</kwd></kwd-group>
<counts>
<book-page-count count="7"/></counts></book-part-meta>
<body>
<p>Introduction There is a growing interest in providing wireless data networking within buildings, to allow flexible, low cost networks that can be quickly installed and recon- figured. Static data cabling is expensive to install. and older buildings do not contain the necessary duct net- works, so the possibility of wireless networks is ex- tremely attractive. RF wireless LANs products are the main commercial interest in this area. There are however problems with these radio LANs: The spec- trum is highly regulated so the data rates are limited by this regulation. The cards have high power dissipa tion, and components are relatively expensive. Free space optical links have many advantages over radio channels. The optical spectrum is subject only to eve safety regulation. and the bandwidth of the optical channel means data rates into the Gbit/s range are possible. Components are relatively inexpensive. and have low power consumption &#x0005B;1-6&#x0005D;. 'Point and shoot' opticallinksthatconformtotheInfraRedDataAsso- ciation (IRDA) are routinely fitted to laptop comput- ersandincreasinglyintegratedwithprintersandother peripherals. These ports offer data transfer at up to 4Mb/s. At higher data rates there has been academic interest and several products operating at ethernet data rates &#x0005B;1-6&#x0005D;. Optical channels can generally be classified as diffuse, or line of sight (LOS). Diffuse links diffuse Lambertian emitters that fill the coverage volume with optical power. This creates robust channels that cannot be blocked by an obstacle between source and detector; In this situation an alternative path exists (perhaps due to a reflection off a wall). The problem with this approach is that each of the multipaths has a different propagation distance, creating a dispersive optical channel. An estimate of the unequalised bandwidth-distance product of a typical channel is given in &#x0005B;4&#x0005D; as 260 Mb.m/s . Diffuse systems operat ing at 50 and a possible extension to 100 Mb/s have been reported &#x0005B;6.7&#x0005D;. and these use equalisation to overcome the dispersive channel. Fast optical channels must therefore be line- of-sight. if this complex equalisation is to be avoided. The coverage of a single channel is a function of the power flux density that can be provided at the receiver by the source, so that a compromise between a single source above the room providing flood illumination. and a large number of low power line of sight channels must be found. Systems that use relatively high power trans- mitters and large cells have been demonstrated at 155Mb/s &#x0005B;81, and a IGbit/s tracked architecture has been shown to be feasible &#x0005B;9,10&#x0005D;. This latter architec- ture used tracking of a mobile and a solid state beam- steering antenna to cover the space. The system we envisage builds on this, but removes the acquisition time involved in a tracking process. In this paper we describe a cellular optical network that uses vertical cavity surface emitting lasers to provide high bandwidth optical links to termi- nals in a room. using a number of small cells of coverage. This architecture uses transceivers, and in- corporates control functions that are well suited to a smart pixel integration technology. Figure 1. Freespace optical network</p>
<p>Overview Figure 1 shows a diagram of the proposed architecture. A Base Station (BS) is located above the cover- age area. and this contains an optical transmitter and receiver. The transmitter uses an array of semiconduc- tor sources which emit normal to the surface of the array. These are likely to be either Vertical Cavity Surface Emitting Lasers (VCSELs) or resonant cavity LED's (RCLEDs). Each source emits light which passes through a short focal length lens that deviates the beam according to how far the source is displaced from the optical axis of the system. This position- angle mapping allows the space to be covered by an array of cells, each illuminated by a single source. The Terminal or Mobile Station (MS) is identical to the base station. The receiver section that is shown in the diagram uses a system of lenses to fo- cus light onto one element of a photodetector array. creating a angle-sensing detector array. The photodi- ode detects the radiation. and transmitted data is re- covered from this. The position of the active detector indicates the angle of the incoming beam. Segmenting the detector into an array also narrows the capture angle of the receiver (by keeping only one element ac tive) thus reducing the noise from background illumination. The cells are designed to be on a hexagonal pitch, and a hexagonal pitch source array will be used. The opti cal systems perform a position-angle mapping in the transmit antenna and the inverse at the receiver, which implies the topology of transmitter and receiver array should be the same. The systems we envisage will operate at data rates of 155Mbits to up to IGbit/s. Calculations have shown that realistic receiver designs require approximately -30dBm of incident optical power to support data rates of this order. In the next section we analyse the transmitter and receiver components in more detail and discuss methods of meeting this demand.</p>
<p>System components Transmitter The receiver plane power flux density should be approximately -30dBm/cm for operation at &gt;150Mbits/s. This corresponds to a 6.4mW point source evenly illuminating each Im diameter hcxago-nal cell. This is a major barrier to using these free space optical channels, as this is an order of magni tude larger than Class 1 eye safety Accessible Emission Limits (AELs) at typical wavelengths. Table I summarises the eyesafetv limits at a number of wavelengths. Table 1. AELsfor laser sources Several methods for meeting the Class I limits have been identified. Above 1400nm evesafe operation is almost assured, as the water in the cornea of the eye absorbs radiation and prevents focusing on the retina. The system requires surface normal emitters at these wavelengths, but VCSELs operating at these long wavelength are not available. Resonant cavity LEDs (RCLEDs) &#x0005B;111 have the potential to operate at this wavelength, due to their simpler structure. and de- vices have been demonstrated at 980 and 1300nm. Work on 1500nm designs is progressing. RCLEDs are expected to show efficiencies of around 5&#x00025; and modulation bandwidths of 100's of MHz, and appear to be an attractive source for long wavelength, low cost systems. The optical 'antenna' consists of an array of surface normal emitters combined with beamnsteering optics, as shown in figure 2 . This uses an array of point sources on a hexagonal array of pitch 250 pm, with a beamangletypicalofaRCLED(NA=O.1)incombi- nation with commercially available singlets that form a short focal length combination. A combination of custom and commercial software is used to model the propagation of light from the emitters, which are as- sumed Gaussian. to the receiver plane. Figure 3 shows . atypicalresultforaBS2mabovethereceiverplane using 19 OdBm sources. The -42dBm contour would be the limit of the operating region, and the plot shows that there is a 6dB variation in power flux den- sitv with all transmitters on. This could be reducedby varying the power that each device transmits, which is to be avoided due to added circuit complexity. or us ing modified optics or an irregular pitch array. Work on the development of RCLEDs at eyesafe wave- lengths (&gt;1400nm) is continuing, and we consider op eration attheselongerwavelengthstobethemost desirable option, due to the ease in meeting safety considerations. Expander optics Commercial singlet lenses expand individual beams and steer radiation to cell positions Figure 2. Transmit antenna Figure 3. Intensity contours in receiver plane. Dia- gramn shows contours for a hexagonal arrayv (250mm pitch) of 19 ImW Gaussian beam profile sources 2m above receiver plane. Intensity is calculated over areanormaltolocalraydirection(i.e.facingtrans- mnitter arrav). At wavelengths below 1400nm meeting the eve safety limits becomes more difficult. and the effective radi- anceofsourcesneedstobereducedbyafactorof ancca oful souce ned to be reduce bye aeeie factrno about 25 to meet eve safety limits. The use of a Holo graphic Optical Element (HOE) as a shaped diffuser was demonstrated by a group at BT labs who demon- stratedadiffusesstemovera2x2mcellwithasin- glelaserdiodesource15.TheHOEdiffractsthe incoming radiation into the required far field pattern, sothatateachpointontheelementlightisscattered into a range of angles. The effective source is the illu- mmitated m area on the diffuser. as the eve cannot focus back to the actual source. Figure 3 shows a diffuser design that would meet this requirement. An array of diffuserscanbeintroducedapproximately15mmfrom the front of the antenna described earlier. The refrac tive optics performs most of the routing functions and the diffuser array shapes the cell illumination. This approach puts heavy demands on the holographic design and fabrication of the diffractive element. The emitted power sets the area of diffuser required to achieve Class I evesafe operation, and an area of approximately 5x5mm is required to emit 25 times the AEL. These diffusers require wavelength order feature size, and therefore even single diffusers are high space bandwidth product elements. The etch depth of the holographic element must be carefully controlled, as the zero order undif-fracted beam is subject to the point source (rather than diffuse) AELs. In the diffuser array the beams enter the hologram at varying angles, which means that the etch depth must vary across the array. Work on holographic diffusers is being pursued in collaboration with the Chalmers University of technology. Array Figure 4. Modified evesafe antennafor operation be- low 1400nm. Receiver Optics Receives beam and focuses onto hexagonal detector array. Design uses commercially available singlets.</p>
<p>Receiver Thereceive antenna and associated circuitry offersig- nificant challengesinterms of opticaland electrical design.andintegration ofthecomponentsintoacom- pactstructure. Figure 5shows an initial optical design for tics as a parallel beam of light at an angle dependent on the position of the terminal within the coverage area. The light is focused on one element ofa hexago- nal pitch array, which is paired with an equivalent napitchramitterThispredthahequlnt uplink transmitter. This ensures that the uplink will automatically return at the correct azimuth and elevation. The use of a detector array with the optical system allows awide collection area tobe combined with asmall angular field of view, as only one detec- tor is active at once, restricting the range of the input angles. The receiver optical system must meet several conflicting requirements: It must have a large collec tion area, over a wide range of input beam angles, and must focus this radiation to as small an output spot as possible. The optical design shown uses commercially available AR coated singlet lenses, and is designed to focus at least 1cm2 of power flux density onto the appropriate detector at the receiver plane at angles up to 40 degrees either side of the optical axis Work on an optimised design using aspheric plastic optical element is underway, and it is expected that this will be folded to reduce the volume of the receiver. One of the major sources of interference in free space optical channels is the interference due to background illumination. Daylight can induce DC photocurrents, and fluorescent light fittings can in duce significant interference components up to IMHz &#x0005B;121. ReceiverdesignsforthesesystemsareAC coupled to reduce the effect of the photocurrent from this background noise. Optical filtering can also used to reduce the optical bandwidth of the system othertechniqueweareinvestigatingistogrowsemi- &#x0005B;3&#x0005D;. The conductor layers in the receiver photodetectors with the correct bandgap to provide a short wavelength cut-off, and use the natural detector roll offin respon-sivity for the high cut-off. This principle has been demonstrated at 980nm using a combination of an AR coated GaAs wafer and a Silicon detector, providing a bandwidth of 100nm or so with little angular dependence 1131. We are presently designing InGaAsP detec tor structures to achieve this at longer (1300 and 1500nm) wavelengths.</p>
<p>Smart Pixel Implementation Figure 6 shows a block diagram of the functions the transceiver must perform, in its simplest form. Each local transceiver pair launches and receives light from the same angular cone (corresponding to a cell) and forms the basic 'smart pixel'. This contains laser driver circuitry, and some of the receiver circuitry. This is likely to be a preamplifier and main Gain Control.TheAGCamplifier amplifier, bothesignalstothinputlvlherecockre boost the signals to the input level where clock recov ery and data decision circuits can be used. . . As there are many pixels simultaneously re ceiving received data signal the transceiver to the must pass the recovery strongest circuits and discard the receeaesever yh cobiningthe rest. There are several methods of combining these signals, and our initial approach will be to use the AGC control signals from the amplifiers as an indica tion of signal strength and to route the nal strongest sig- to the data recovery circuit. Theclock recovery nlto nciruitare globalfui ock recould and decision circuits are global functions, and would beipeetdsprtl.rmtepxla es Figure 6. Block diagram ofSmart pixel implementation nitiall. The transmission acknowledge signals. and other aspects of the medium access control would also be implemented at this level In more sophisticated systems each pixel wouldbeacompletetransceiverunitandreceiveand output digital data from the terminal. The global task is then to choose the best digital (rather than analogue signal). In the BS this would be an advantage, as each pixel could function as an autonomous downlink, in- creasing the aggregate bandwidth of the system. In the terminal this is less advantageous as there is only one smart pixel active at any one time. At present we are investigating the sort of division between the tasks that is straightforward to implement and makes effi- cient use of the components. The restricted user model that we are considering means that simple transceiver pixels with global (i.e.) a single data and clock recov- ery circuit is most likely. The intention is to use a custom integrated circuit to implement the electronics. and to flip-chip bond receiver and transmitter devices to this. Optical components would then be integratedwith these components. Our aim is to use a hybrid of diffractive and refractive components to create a compact transceiver that is suitable for manufacture.</p>
<p>System operation User model At presentthemodelofthetypeofuseofthenetwork has been restricted, although the antenna designs al- lowforagreatdealofflexibility.Themodelwehave used is that of a wired ethernet type system. with static terminals within the space. that can be reposi tioned. There is no allowance made for portable ter minals that can roam within the network, as this requires handover between illumination cells. al though we believe this could be implemented at a later date. Terminals have to be configured once they enter thesystem.inasimilarwaytoawiredethernet. Initiallythesystemwilluseasingledown- link channel, and each uplink getting time divided ac cess to a single output from the base station, again for compatibility with ethernet. The intention is to in crease the complexity of the base station to allow mul tiple downlinks, and increase the aggregate bandwidth at some future date.</p>
<p>Link model Thelinkprotocolweenvisageisarelativelyshort length data packet sent from the transmitter, with an acknowledge signal sent back from the receiver. In the case of the downlink the BS transmits to the MS. using previous knowledge of its position, or using all transmitter downlinks (There is only one downlink, but turning off transmitters that transmit to unoccu- pied cells saves power, and reduces the chances of multipaths). The MS receives power from a particular angle, depending on the relative positions of the two transceivers. This power is focused onto a particular detector. The MS transmits acknowledge on the paired uplink VCSEL if the signal is intended for it. and it is received correctly. The BS receives the ac- knowledge signal and knows the data has been cor- rectlv received. Any blocking results in the acknowledge not being transmitted or not received. so the link is robust. Blocking The major problem with any system that uses line of sight links is blocking, and the only means to reduce the problem are by correct placing of the BS and MS. The BS is above the coverage area and the MS would most likely be on top of the monitor of the worksta tion. Blocking occurs when both the channel is active andthepathisblockedsoamodeloftheprobability of the channel being active is required, as well asa model of the blocker being in line with the BS to MS path. A number of models to describe the probability of a blocker (usually a person) being in a particular posi tion in the space have been formulated. These use a range of assumptions i.e. the blocker is equally likely to be anywhere in the room, more likely to be around the edge etc. and from these the probability of geo- metrical channel blockage is obtained. The probability of a channel being active is dependent on the type of traffic in the network, the Medium Access Control (MAC) protocols. and the data rate supported. A number of models have been combined with the blocker models to calculate worst case blocking probabilities. These range from less than 2&#x00025; for a single blocker, to 6&#x00025; for 2 blockers in the room. These are preliminary, and necessarily theoretical results. but indicate that blocking is un- likely to be a major problem.</p>
<p>Demonstrator A demonstrator system is currently being fabricated using commercially available components and a reduced square cellular architecture. The design is to cover an area approximately 2x2m in extent using 16 overlapping square cells, with a bit rate of 20Mbits/s. Commercial ethernet IC's will be used to provide net- work protocols and line coding, the optical links being a replacement for coaxial cables. A 4x4 array of 850 nm VCSELs forms the source array. These emit up to 2mW in a single transverse mode, and are modulated using a laser driver IC. Initially the illumination will be the natural shape of the VCSEL devices, and the system will not be eyesafe until a diffuser is intro duced at a later stage. Commercial singlet lenses are used to create an optical antenna, using the design il lustrated in figure 2. Figure 4 shows the antenna opti cal system, that uses commercial singlet lenses. The receiver uses an array of 16 2.5x2.5mm square Silicon PIN diodes, and a simple transimped ance receiver design &#x0005B;131. At present 20Mbit/s designs have been tested using a single Silicon PIN diode, and work on the 16 receiver channels for the demonstrator are underway. Discussion and Conclusions The workwepresent herecoversseveralaspectsof theproblemswithoptical wireless networks andtheir potentialsolutions.Theeyesafetofthetransmitter and the design of the receiver appear to represent the major challenges, and we are working in both these areas.Longerwavelengthmicrocavitydevicesarean attractive solution, and holographic diffuser elements have the potential to provide a solution at shorter wavelengths. The problem of noise from daylight and other ambient optical noise is being addressed using tailored semiconductor devices to narrow the optical bandwidth, and AC coupled receivers to block DC photocurrent. The hea system sstem we describe here isrelatively iweidepeeisnreabily complex, and its viability is dependent on the ability to integrate the components into a compact trans- ceiveratrelativelylowcost.A'smartpixelapproach to grouping functionality, and integration and fabrica tion techniques offers the potential to provide this. Work on a hybrid transceiver implementation is pro gressing, with the aim of creating a suitable pixel design. lessLANs.and optical wireless can provide this facil less LAts a otial w an prvd is ail- itywithalargepotentialbandwidththatisrelatively free of regulation. Free space links are attractive for providing high bandwidth channels, and smart pixels are an attractive topology for controlling these rela tively 'undirected' wireless links.</p>
<p>Acknowledgments The authorswould liketo acknowledge UKEPSRC for financialcsupport of this work (Grant GRK/3500- Highspeed devices for freespace opticaluLANs). We would alsoliketoacknowledge the valuable discus- sionandcollaborationwiththeChalmersUniversity of Technology. K. Samaras would like to acknowl- edge the State Scholarships Foundation of Greece for personal support.</p></body>
<back>
<ref-list>
<ref id="r1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Street</surname><given-names>A. M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Stavrinou</surname><given-names>P. N.</given-names></name><name><surname>O'BRIEN</surname><given-names>D.C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Edwards</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></name></person-group>, "<article-title>Indoor Optical Wireless Systems &#x02013; A Review</article-title>.", to be published in <source>International Journal of Optical  Quantum Electronics</source></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">	<name><surname>Smyth</surname><given-names>P.P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Eardley</surname><given-names>P.L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Dalton</surname><given-names>K.T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wisely</surname><given-names>D. R.</given-names></name><name><surname>McKee</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wood</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>	</person-group>: "<article-title>Optical Wireless - A Prognosis</article-title>.". <source>Proc SPIE</source>, (<year>1995</year>)<volume>2601</volume>, pp <fpage>212</fpage>-<lpage>225</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1117/12.228143</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Barry</surname><given-names>J. R.</given-names></name></person-group>, "<source>Wireless Infrared Communications</source>", <publisher-name>Kluwer Academic</publisher-name>, <publisher-loc>Boston</publisher-loc>, <year>1994</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/978-1-4615-2700-8</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Gfeller</surname><given-names>F. R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bapst</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></name></person-group>"<article-title>Wireless In-House Data Communication via Diffuse Infrared Radiation</article-title>.", <source>Proc. IEEE</source>. <year>1979</year>, <volume>67</volume>, (<issue>11l</issue>), pp <fpage>1474</fpage>-<lpage>1486</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1109/PROC.1979.11508</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Smyth</surname><given-names>P. P.</given-names></name><name><surname>McCullagh</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wisely</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wood</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ritchie</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Eardley</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Cassidy</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name></person-group> "<article-title>Optical Wireless Local Area Networks - Enabling Technologies</article-title>.", <source>BT Tech. Jnl</source> <year>1993</year>, <volume>11</volume>(<issue>2</issue>) pp <fpage>56</fpage>-<lpage>64</lpage></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Marsh</surname><given-names>G. W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kahn</surname><given-names>J. M.</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>50 Mb/s Diffuse Infrared Free-Space Link Using OOK With decision-Feedback Equalisation</article-title><source>IEEE Phot Tech Letts</source>, (<year>1994</year>)<volume>6</volume>, (<issue>10</issue>), pp <fpage>1268</fpage>-<lpage>70</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1109/68.329659</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r7"><label>7</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Audeh</surname><given-names>M. D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kahn</surname><given-names>J. M.</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>Performance Evaluation of Baseband OOK for Wireless Indoor Infrared LAN's Operating at 100 MB/s</article-title>, <source>IEEE Trans on Comms</source>, (<year>1995</year>)<volume>43</volume>, (<issue>6</issue>), pp <fpage>2085</fpage>-<lpage>2094</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1109/26.387449</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r8"><label>8</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>McCullagh</surname><given-names>M. J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wisely</surname><given-names>D.R.</given-names></name></person-group>, "<article-title>155 Mbit/s Optical Wireless Link Using a Boot-strapped Silicon APD Receiver</article-title>.", <source>Elect Letts</source>, (<year>1994</year>)<volume>30</volume>, (<issue>5</issue>), pp <fpage>430</fpage>-<lpage>432</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1049/el:19940308</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r9"><label>9</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>McCullagh</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wisely</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Eardley</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>A 1 Gbit/s Optical Wireless LAN Supporting Mobile Transceivers</article-title> <source>Wireless 94, Calgary</source></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r10"><label>10</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wisely</surname><given-names>D. R.</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>A 1 Gbit/s Optical Wireless Tracked Architecture for ATM Delivery</article-title> <source>IEE Coll On Optical Free Space Communication Links 1996</source>, <publisher-loc>London</publisher-loc></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r11"><label>11</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Hunt</surname><given-names>N. E. J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Schubert</surname><given-names>E. F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>R. A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zydzik</surname><given-names>G. J.</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>Enhanced Spectral Power Density and Reduced Linewidth at 1.3 m in InGaAsP Quantum Well Light-Emitting Diode</article-title>, <source>Appl. Phys. Letts.</source>, (<year>1992</year>)<volume>61</volume>, (<issue>19</issue>) pp <fpage>2287</fpage>-<lpage>2289</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.108489</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r12"><label>12</label><mixed-citation publication-type="confproc"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Boucouvalas</surname><given-names>A. C.</given-names></name></person-group> "<article-title>Ambient Light Noise and Its Effect on Receiver Design for Indoor Wireless Optical Links</article-title>.", <conf-name>IEEE Second Communications Network Symposium</conf-name>. <conf-loc>Manchester, England</conf-loc>, <conf-date>July 1995</conf-date>, pp <fpage>54</fpage>-<lpage>63</lpage></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r13"><label>13</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Street</surname><given-names>A. M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Stavrinou</surname><given-names>P. N.</given-names></name><name><surname>O'Brien</surname><given-names>D. C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Edwards</surname><given-names>D. J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Parry</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>Optical Pre amplifier Designs for IR-LAN Applications</article-title>, <source>IEE Coll on Optical Free Space Communication Links</source>, (<year>1996</year>), pp <fpage>8/1</fpage>-<lpage>8/6</lpage></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></book-part></book-part-wrapper>
