<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
<collection-meta collection-type="conf">
<conference content-type="conf-name"><conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name><conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym></conference>
<conference content-type="conf-other-meta"><conf-date content-type="start">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-date content-type="end">
<day>19</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-loc>Nevada, 
<country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc></conference></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
<title-group>
<title>SLM Materials and Sructures</title>
<alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/></title-group></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
<title-group>
<title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title></title-group>
<volume-in-collection>
<volume-number>14</volume-number>
<volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title></volume-in-collection></collection-meta>
<book-meta>
<book-title-group>
<book-title>Spatial Light Modulators</book-title></book-title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Burdge</surname><given-names>Geoffrey</given-names></name></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>Sadik C.</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group>
<pub-date publication-format="electronic">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></pub-date></book-meta>
<book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
<book-part-meta>
<title-group>
<title>Electro-optic polarization modulation in &#x0005B;110&#x0005D;-oriented GaAs-InGaAs multiple quantum wells</title></title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Snelling</surname><given-names>M. J.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>X. R.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Harken</surname><given-names>D. R.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Smirl</surname><given-names>Arthur L.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Towe</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff"><sup>2</sup></xref></contrib>
<aff id="aff1">
<label>1</label>Laboratory for Photonics and Quantum Electronics University of Iowa, 100 IATL, Iowa City, IA 52242-1000</aff>
<aff id="aff2">
<label>2</label>Laboratory for Optics and Quantum Electronics Thornton Hall, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, VA 22903-2442</aff></contrib-group>
<author-notes><fn id="fn1">
<label>&#x02020;</label>
<p>Present address: Optex Communications Corporation, Rockville, MA.</p></fn><fn id="fn2">
<label>&#x02021;</label>
<p>Present address: Norand Corporation, Cedar Rapids, IA</p></fn></author-notes>
<elocation-id>141</elocation-id>
<permissions>
<copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
<copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
<copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
<license license-type="open-access">
<license-p>closed</license-p></license></permissions>
<abstract>
<p>Ellipsometric techniques are used to measure the anisotropy in the complex indices of refraction of strained &#x0005B;110&#x0005D;-oriented quantum well p-i-n structures as a function of bias voltage and to characterize their performance as polarization modulators.</p></abstract>
<kwd-group kwd-group-type="OCIS">
<title>OCIS codes</title>
<kwd>Aniostropic optical materials</kwd>
<kwd>Semiconductors including MQW</kwd>
<kwd>Electro-optical devies</kwd>
<kwd>Ellipsometry and polarimetry</kwd></kwd-group>
<counts>
<book-page-count count="6"/></counts></book-part-meta>
<body>
<p>Introduction In order to modulate the polarization state of incident light, an in-plane anisotropy in the refractive index or the absorption coefficient or both are required. Unfortunately, conventionally-grown &#x0005B;001&#x0005D; heterostructures possess no intrinsic anisotropy in the plane of the quantum wells. Such material can be made anisotropic by application of an in- plane uniaxial strain. Indeed, Shen et al. &#x0005B;1&#x0005D; have recently fabricated a polarization rotation modulator with impres- sive performance by introducing uniaxial strain into a &#x0005B;001&#x0005D;-oriented multiple quantum well (MQW) structure. To obtain the uniaxial strain, they bonded a MQW structure to a substrate with an anisotropic thermal coefficient of expansion. In one direction, the substrate matched the expansion coefficient of the MQW material, while in the orthogonal direction the differential contraction between the substrate and the semiconductor imparted the required uniaxial strain. A maximum contrast ratio of 5000:1 was recorded; however, a significant amount of post-growth processing was necessary, and the thermally derived nature of the anisotropy make it sensitive to environmental temperature fluctuations. Our approach here is to take advantage of the intrinsic anisotropy that can be obtained by growing in directions other than the &#x0005B;001&#x0005D; direction. The maximum anisotropy is predicted for growth on ( lO) and (10) surfaces &#x0005B;2&#x0005D;, however such material has not yet been fabricated. More readily available material can be found based on substrates orientated in the &#x0005B;l Ie&#x0005D; family of planes, for which the &#x0005B;110&#x0005D; direction has the largest predicted anisotropy &#x0005B;3&#x0005D;. Application of an in-plane biaxial strain enhances the optical anisotropy &#x0005B;3,4&#x0005D;. We demonstrate that the optical anisotropy inherent in biaxially strained &#x0005B;110&#x0005D;-oriented GaAs-InxGal-xAs MQWs can be used to construct a prototype electro-optic modulator that is sensitive to the polarization state of the transmitted light. In this device, application of a voltage across a p-i-n region containing the MQWs is used to produce a change in the in-plane birefringence and dichroism. This, in turn, causes a change in the ellipticity and a rotation of a linearly polarized input beam. Subse quently, a phase retarder and a linear analyzer are used to convert this polarization modulation into an intensity modulation. Ellipsometric measurements, which directly determine the degree of dichroism and birefringence as a function of wavelength and voltage, are used to optimize the operating wavelength, the alignment of the modulator and to predict the maximum contrast ratio. These results allow the design of future structures with an enhanced contrast ratio (1000:1), good bandwidth (4 nm), tunability (10 nm) and operating temperature range (35 oC), but with a relatively low throughput (1&#x00025;). Even larger contrast ratios and throughputs are predicted for MQW structures with narrower excitons, but with a degraded bandwidth, tunability, and hence, increased sensitivity to temperature. This approach to the construction of polarization modula tors requires only elementary post-growth processing. It is applicable to systems that require high contrast modulation and that can tolerate the larger insertion losses.</p>
<p>Experimental The sample used in these studies is the same one used in our nonlinear optical studies and is described elsewhere &#x0005B;5,6&#x0005D;. It is a p-i(MQW)-n diode that was grown on a &#x0005B;110&#x0005D;- oriented semi-insulating GaAs substrate, which is tilted 6 towards the &#x0005B;111&#x0005D;B direction to ensure good layer quality &#x0005B;7&#x0005D;. The n region was grown immediately on top of the GaAs substrate and consists of a 1 pm n GaAs buffer layer and a 100 nm layer of n-type GaAs. The intrinsic MQW region consists of 50 periods of 6-nm-wide In 0 .13Gao.87 As quantum wells separated by 8-nm-thick GaAs barriers. The 13&#x00025; indium concentration provides the necessary biaxial strain to enhance the optical anisotropy. The capping layer is 100 nmof p-type GaAs. Following growth, Follwin thesamplewasprocessedintoa th grwth saple as rocsse ino a series of mesas, each with an electrical contact which allows the capping layer to be biased with respect to a common electrical connection to the substrate. The electrical characteristics of the sample show it to be a good diode with a breakdown voltage of 20 V. The laser used for these experiments was a mode- locked styrl-13 dye laser producing pulses with a full-width-at-half-maximum of 2 ps. The repetition rate was set at less than 3.8 MHz, to ensure complete recovery of the sample between pulses. Laser fluences of less than 0.2 pjcm-2 were used in order to ensure that the sample remained in a regime in which the absorption was linearly related to incident power.</p>
<p>Intrinsic Anisotropy The room-temperature in-plane anisotropy in the absorption of the MQW region of this device is illustrated in Fig. 1. The solid curve represents the absorption spectrum measured for light polarized along the &#x0005B;110&#x0005D; direction and the dotted curve for light polarized along &#x0005B;001&#x0005D;. The dashed curve gives the dichroism, AcImQw (i.e., the difference in the two spectra). The peak dichroism is seen to be 6.6x10 3 c- 1 , wich is close to the value predicted theoretically &#x0005B;3&#x0005D;. Also, notice that the heavy-hole excitonic resonance is much broader in this particular sample than in high-qualityMQWsgrowninthe&#x0005B;001&#x0005D;-direction.Aswe discuss below, this feature can be advantageously used to increase the tunability and operating temperature range of the polarization modulator. For the data displayed in Fig. 1 the effects of the substrate have been eliminated by performing the measurements through the device plus substrate and through the substrate alone, then subtracting the two. The birefringence AnQw associated with the dichro ism AmQw can be indirectly obtained byp erforming a Figure 1. The absorption coefficients of the MQW region for light polarized along the two in-plane crystallographic axes (top two curves) and the dichroism (bottom line). Kramers-Kronig transformation on the Amow data shown in Fig. 1. The results are shown as the open triangles in Fig. 2. For later comparison with our ellipsometric measurements, we also replot the dichroism shown in Fig. 1 as the open squares in Fig. 2. Figure 2. A comparison of the dichroism measurements obtained from absorption spectra (open squares) and the birefringence measurements derived from a Kramers-Kronig transformation of this data (open triangles) with the direct ellipsometric measure ments of dichroism (top, solid dots) and birefringence (bottom, solid dots). Thisbirefringenceanddichroismcanbemoredirectly and simultaneously determined by placing the sample between two crossed polarizers with its principal axes oriented at 450 with respect to the polarizer axes and by subsequently measuring the transmission as a function of analyzer angle V. (Note that this geometry is identical to that described below for our modulator, which is shown in Figs. 5 and 6, except that the quarter wave plate is removed). The transmission of the analyzer-polarizer pair with the sample in place is given (for small angles) by: T(W) (1 - R)20eXpf-(aQWd + asl)5 0 _dwithout +ssample Aa MQWd&#x000B1; Acs + (1)(AaMwd+Aa) 4 Where W represents the angular deviation of the analyzer from its crossed position, R is the sample reflection coefticient, X is the wavelength, a = (0(Tol +a oo) / 2 is the average absorption coefficient and X is the extinction coefficient of the crossed analyzer-polarizer pair. The subscripts mnw and s denote the MQW region and the substrate, respectively, and d and I represent their respective thicknesses. Au=uxnoj-axoo denotes the dichroism and An= nioi -n&#x0005B;ooi represents the birefrin- gence, where n is the refractive index. Note that this equation assumes that the anisotropy (i.e. the applied voltage) and, therefore, the modulation of the polarization are constant during the transmission of the optical signal pulse, so that averaging over the pulse envelope is unnecessary &#x0005B;8&#x0005D;. Typical measurements of the transmission of the nominally-crossed analyzer-polarizer pair as the analyzer is rotated through a small angle y with and without the sample in place are shown in Fig. 3 for a wavelength of 925 nm and a bias voltage of 0 V. The key features to notice from inspection of Eq. (1) and Fig. 3 are that (i) the analyzer transmission is a parabolic function of the analyzer angle, (ii) the horizontal displacement of the minima determines the in-plane anisotropy in the absorp tion coefficient, and (iii) the vertical displacement determines the anisotropy in the refractive index. Such measurements were systematically performed as a function of wavelength for each bias voltage of interest. Representative values for the MQW dichroism, Ancw, and birefringence, Anmnw, that are distilled from these measurements are shown in Fig. 4 for 0 and 6 V. For this figure, the effects of the substrate again have been carefully removed by performing the measurements through both the substrate and the MQW region and through the substrate alone. Figure 3. Transmission through two linear polarizers as a function of the final linear polarizer angle, y (open trianles). The same measurement with the sample placed between the linear analyzers (closed circles). Finally, as a check on consistency and as assurance that we have successfully separated the effects of the MQWs from those of the substrate, we compared the direct ellipsometric measurements of the dichroism and birefrin gence with those extracted indirectly from the absorption measurements. One such comparison is shown in Fig.2 where we have replotted AcmQw and AnCw for 0 V from Fig. 4 as the solid circles. The overall agreement is very good, except for a slight systematic shift between the Wavelength(nm) Figure 4. The two components of the complex index of refraction which relate to the optical anisotropy of the MQW region. The top two curves represent the dichroism at 0 V (solid circles) and 6 V (solid triangles) while the bottom two curves represent the birefringence at 0 V (open circles) and 6 V (open triangles). birefringence data obtained by the two methods. We attribute this to the finite spectral window available for the numerical Kramers-Kronig transformation.</p>
<p>Polarization Modulator The intrinsic anisotropy measured in the previous section can be used to fabricate a simple prototype polarization- sensitive electro-optic modulator by placing the MQW diode followed by a quarter wave plate (14-plate) between two polarizers with the principal axes of the sample oriented at 450 with respect to the incident polarization, as shown in Figs. 5 and 6. In the absence of a bias voltage, the 14-plate and analyzer are initially oriented to reject the signal light. When a bias voltage is applied to the diode, it produces a change in the in-plane birefringence and dichroism (as discussed in the previous section), which in turn, modulates the ellipticity and the direction of polarization of the transmitted signal pulse, thus, increasing the device transmission. Sample 98 1 23 Figure 5. The geometry of a polarization modulator. P, and P, are linear polarizers, and "/4" represents a quarter-wave plate. The arrows and ellipse schematically represent the polarization state of light at that point in the device. P0 1y X/4 &#x0005B;001&#x0005D; 6 &#x0005B;ii10&#x0005D; Y P2 A X Figure 6. The nomenclature and relative alignment of the components of the polarization modulator shown in Fig. 5. For small angular deviations of y and 6 from their initial "off' positions, the modulator transmission can be written as: T(V,6)=(1-R)2exp-((MQwd+axsl)} (t (AnQwd + Ansl) 2 (2) X Au d + Aust1 4+ X We emphasize that cxmaw, AumQuw and AnmQw are functions of both wavelength and voltage and that (x, Aus and Ans are functions of wavelength, but not voltage, as discussed in the previous section. Notice that the device transmission is a parabolic function of the angle 4 (0) for a fixed 0 (V), bias voltage and wavelength k. This behavior is illustrated in Fig. 7 for a wavelength of 923 nm, fixed 0 and for bias voltages of 0 and 6 V. 10 Contrast Ratio 6 V 4 00V 2 mm 0 2 4 6 8 10 (degrees) Figure 7. The measured transmission of the modulator at 923 nm in both the on (6 V) and off (0 V) states. The contrast ratio derived from these measurements is also shown. The contrast ratio (CR), which is given by the transmission in the on-state (in this case, 6 V) divided by that in the off-state (0 V), is also shown in Fig.7 for 923 nm and a fixed 0 . Notice that the peak CR occurs very near (but not exactly at) the minimum in the transmission in the off state. This observation suggests a convenient means of (analytically and experimentally) optimizing the orientation oftheX14-waveplateandanalyzer,namely,thatthey shouldbeorientedsuchthattheyminimizethetransmission in the off state. Using this condition, together with Eq. (2), we can write the contrast ratio as: exp&#x0005B; , (V,X)-a ,(6Vk)Pd CR(X)= X (Xa o. (6V,X)d - AM, (0V,)d + (3) 4 ((An, (6V,1)d - An (0V,1)d X k+ The first term in Eq. (3) gives the contribution of the dichroism, the second the contribution of the birefringence, and the third represents the contribution of the amplitude modulation of the average absorption coefficient as a function of voltage. The latter produces no change in the polarization state. The measured values for AcmQw and AnQ.w as a function of wavelength and voltage from the ellipsometric measurements described in the previous section can now be used in Eq. (3) to predictably optimize the operating wavelength. This procedure is illustrated in Fig. 8, where the contrast ratio has been calculated as a function of wavelength using the dichroism and birefringence shown in Fig. 4. The individual contributions of the dichroism, birefringence and amplitude modulation are also plotted. The contrast ratio is strongly peaked with a maximum value of -10:1 predicted near 923 nm and a width of -10 nm (FWHM). It is also clear from this figure that the contribu tions of amplitude modulation (i.e., the third term in Eq. (3)) to the contrast ratio are small and that the polarization modulation terms (i.e., the changes in the dichroism and birefringence) dominate. In fact, at the peak wavelength, dichroic effects (polarization rotation) dominatethoseofbirefringence. 10 CR 8 - ,"\ Dichroism 61! 4-o / \ Birefringence Amplitude M dl n 2 '. * * 0900 910 920 930 940 950 960 Wavelength (nm) Figure 8. The contrast ratio calculated from the ellipsometric measurements shown in Fig. 4. The individual contributions from dichroism, birefringence and amplitude modulation to the contrast ratio are also shown. This modulator can be tuned by simply rotating the analyzer slightly, as illustrated in Fig. 9. This figure shows the contrast ratio as a function of wavelength for several measured fixed analyzer orientations. Notice that an unoptimized device, which contains only 50 6-nm-wide wells and is operated at 6 V is capable of maintaining a contrast of &gt;4:1 over a range of &gt;10nm. Since the excitonic resonance shifts at a rate of -1 nm/3.50 C, this corresponds to a useful operating temperature range of -35'C. In effect, this figure illustrates one of the potentially useful characteristics of polarization modulators. Namely, that the broad exciton in the present sample has effectively allowed us to trade contrast ratio for tunability or, equivalently, for insensitivity to changes in ambient temperature. 10 Optimum 8 - 2 v! P z 6 -0.7., .+0.6 CZ 4 -1.40 0 . +1 .20 .v 4. 2 * ,o i ' t * l 0 915 920 925 930 935 Wavelength (nm) Figure 9. The measured contrast ratio as a function of wavelength for different values of y , the anle of the final linear analyzer. At =0. P, is optimized to give the largest contrast ratio possible. The orientation of the quarter-wave plate was fixed throughout at the value found to give the maximum contrast ratio at 923 nm.</p>
<p>Discussion In summary, we have measured the birefringence and dichroism of a strained &#x0005B;110&#x0005D;-oriented InGaAs/GaAs p-i(MQW)-n diode as a function of wavelength and voltage. This information was then used to predictably evaluate the performance of this device when used as a polarization-sensitive modulator. The tunability (10 nm), optical bandwidth (4 nm), switching voltage (6 V) and temperature range (35 C) of the current device are impressive; however, the contrast ratio (10:1) is disappointing and the insertion loss (-33 dB) is daunting. This relatively low contrast ratio and the high insertion loss are not typical, however, but are primarily the result of the thin quantum well region and broad broad excitonic linewidth of the unoptimized sample that happened to be available for this demonstration. By simply increasing the number of quantum wells, while continuing to use the current material, we estimate that the contrast ratio can be increased to &gt;1000:1 and the transmission increased to -1&#x00025; while maintaining the current optical bandwidth, tunability, and operating temperature range, but at the expense of an increased switching voltage. The use of MQW material with narrower excitonic features should further improve both the contrast ratio and throughput, but at the expense of optical bandwidth, tunabilityandoperatingtemperaturerange. Generically, polarization-sensitive quantum-confined Stark-effect (QCSE) modulators should be capable of higher contrast ratios than the equivalent amplitude modulators, but they will have a higher insertion loss. A disadvantage of the polarization modulators described here is that they require growth in an unconventional direction. Nevertheless, they have an advantage over uniaxi- ally-strained polarization-rotation modulators, which require bonding to a substrate and subsequent epitaxial lift off, in that they require less post-growth processing. as a class, QCSE polarization t modulators Consequently, will be most useful for applications that require high dynamicrangeandcantoleratelargeinsertionloss.</p>
<p>Acknowledgments ThisworkwassupportedbytheArmyResearchOffice,the wok wavsupportedabylt y Research oice 7. D. Sun and E. Thie Office ofNaval Research and the National Science Cdoping Founesdation</p></body>
<back>
<ref-list>
<ref id="r1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Pamulapati</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wraback</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Taysing-Lara</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Dutta</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kuo</surname><given-names>H.C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>High contrast optical modulator based on electrically tunable polarization rotation and phase retardation in uniaxially strained (100) multiple quantum wells</article-title>, <source>IEEE Photon Tech Lett</source>, <fpage>6700</fpage>-<lpage>702</lpage>, (<year>1994</year>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Henderson</surname><given-names>R.H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Towe</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name></person-group>, "<article-title>Effective mass theory for III-V semiconductors on arbitrary (hkl) surfaces</article-title>," <source>J Appl Phys</source> <volume>79</volume> <fpage>2029</fpage>-<lpage>2037</lpage>, (<year>1995</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.361057</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Henderson</surname><given-names>R.H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Towe</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name></person-group>, "<article-title>Strain and crystallo graphic orientation effects on interband optical matrix elements and band gaps of &#x0005B;11&#x02113;&#x0005D;-orientated III-V epilayers</article-title>," <source>J Appl Phys</source> <volume>78</volume>, <fpage>2447</fpage>-<lpage>2445</lpage>, (<year>1995</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.360098</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>Decai</given-names></name><name><surname>Towe</surname><given-names>Elias</given-names></name><name><surname>Bennett</surname><given-names>Brian R.</given-names></name></person-group>, "<article-title>Study of lattice-mismatched (In, Ga)As/GaAs heterostructures on the unconventional (110) GaAs surface</article-title>," <source>J Vac Sci Technol B</source><fpage>121095</fpage>-<lpage>1098</lpage>, (<year>1994</year>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>McCallum</surname><given-names>D.S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>X.R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Smirl</surname><given-names>Arthur</given-names></name><name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>LD.</given-names></name><name><surname>Towe</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name></person-group>, "<article-title>Polarization rotation modulator in a strained&#x0005B;10&#x0005D;-oriented multiple quantum well</article-title>," <source>Appl Phys Lett</source>66<fpage>2885</fpage>-<lpage>2887</lpage>, (<year>1995</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.113462</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Towe</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hayduk</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Boncek</surname><given-names>R.K.</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>Observation of polarization-dependent electroabsorption in (In, Ga)As/GaAs modulator structures orientated in the &#x0005B;110&#x0005D; crystallographic direction</article-title>, <source>Appl Phys Lett</source> <volume>63</volume>, <fpage>2881</fpage>-<lpage>2883</lpage>, (<year>1993</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.110313</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r7"><label>7</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Towe</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name></person-group>, "<article-title>Molecular beam epitaxial growth of (Al, Ga)AlGaAs heterostructures and Si characterization study on vicinal (110)-GaAs substrates</article-title>," <source>J Cryst Growth</source> <volume>132</volume>, <fpage>166</fpage>-<lpage>172</lpage>, (<year>1993</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/0022-0248(93)90258-X</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r8"><label>8</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Andreas Schroeder</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name><name><surname>McCallum</surname><given-names>D.S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Harken</surname><given-names>D.R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Dvorak</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Anderson</surname><given-names>David R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Smirl</surname><given-names>Arthur L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wherrett</surname><given-names>Brian S.</given-names></name></person-group>, "<article-title>Intrinsic and induced anisotropy of nonlinear absorption and refraction in zinc blend semiconductors</article-title>," <source>J Opt Soc Am B</source> <volume>12</volume> <fpage>401</fpage>-<lpage>415</lpage>, (<year>1995</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/JOSAB.12.000401</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></book-part></book-part-wrapper>
