<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
<collection-meta collection-type="conf">
<conference content-type="conf-name"><conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name><conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym></conference>
<conference content-type="conf-other-meta"><conf-date content-type="start">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-date content-type="end">
<day>19</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-loc>Nevada, 
<country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc></conference></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
<title-group>
<title>SLM Materials and Sructures</title>
<alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/></title-group></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
<title-group>
<title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title></title-group>
<volume-in-collection>
<volume-number>14</volume-number>
<volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title></volume-in-collection></collection-meta>
<book-meta>
<book-title-group>
<book-title>Spatial Light Modulators</book-title></book-title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Burdge</surname><given-names>Geoffrey</given-names></name></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>Sadik C.</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group>
<pub-date publication-format="electronic">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></pub-date></book-meta>
<book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
<book-part-meta>
<title-group>
<title>InGaAs Photodiodes for Infrared-Sensitive Optically Addressed Spatial Light Modulators</title></title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Y.-C.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Barbier</surname><given-names>P. R.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>F.G.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Ho</surname><given-names>P.-T.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Burdge</surname><given-names>G. L.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<aff id="aff1">
<label>1</label>Electrical Engineering Department and Laboratory for Physical Sciences University of Maryland, 8050 Greenmead Dr., College Park, MD 20740</aff></contrib-group>
<elocation-id>138</elocation-id>
<permissions>
<copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
<copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
<copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
<license license-type="open-access">
<license-p>closed</license-p></license></permissions>
<abstract>
<p>Infrared-sensitive InGaAs/InP photodiodes for liquid crystal spatial light modulators were grown by MBE. They exhibit record low dark current and capacitance.</p></abstract>
<kwd-group kwd-group-type="OCIS">
<title>OCIS codes</title>
<kwd>Detectors-infrared</kwd>
<kwd>Optical devices-spatial light modulators</kwd>
<kwd>Materials-detector materials</kwd></kwd-group>
<counts>
<book-page-count count="3"/></counts></book-part-meta>
<body>
<p>I. Introduction Currently available optically addressed spatial light modulators (OASLMs) are sensitive only to the visible and near infrared (&lt; 1.1 pm) light II&#x0005D;. For many applications OASLMs which are sensitive to infrared (IR) light at 1.55 pm are required or preferred. A common OASLM light-modulating material is liquid crystal (LC) which can beaddressed by a thin film photosensor &#x0005B;21. This scheme requires that the photosensor exhibits very low dark current to prevent the LC from switching on in the absence of write light, and high photosensitivity to switch the LC on in the presence of write light &#x0005B;3&#x0005D;. An InGaAs/InP photosensor fulfilling these requirements will allow the successful fabrication of an IR-sensitive OASLM. An OASLM incorporating such a photosensor has been previously reported but exhibited a poor contrast ratio due tothelargeInGaAs/InPdarkcurrent&#x0005B;4&#x0005D;. Jn this paper. we investigate the optoelectronic properties of InGaAs/InP mesa-type p-i-n photodiodes grown by solid-source molecular beam epitaxy (MBE) for OASLMs. We summarize the requirements that these photodiodes must fulfill to address successfully ferroelectric liquid crystal (FLC) in an OASLM, as well as their fabrication and characterization. We present experimental data which include very low dark current densities (Ix10-5 A/cm 2 ), comparable to those of InGaAs photodiodes grown by other techniques &#x0005B;5-7&#x0005D;, and the lowest reported for photodiodes grown by solid-source MBE. We found that the dark current at low applied voltage was limited by thermal generation-recombination in the depletion region. We measured a photoresponsivity at 1.55 pm of 0.8 A/W without anti-reflection coating. Capacitance was below 8 nF/cm 2 at 5 V reverse bias. Where defects were visible under an optical microscope, higherdark currents were measured which may explain the poor contrast ratio of OASLMs made with these films.</p>
<p>II. Design of IR-Photodiodes for LC OASLMs For its fast response &#x0005B;8&#x0005D;, we have chosen to incorporate FLC in our OASLM. The dark current of the IR-sensitive photosensor must be sufficiently small that it does not switch the FLC on during the write (negative voltage) drive period in the absence of write light. But the photosensor must provide sufficient photocurrent to switch the FLC on in the presence of IR write light during the write drive period of the OASLM &#x0005B;3&#x0005D;. Among various types of IR photosensors, InGaAs/InP p-i-n photodiodes provide both the lowest dark current and high photosensitivity to fulfill these requirements &#x0005B;4&#x0005D;. To achieve a high spatial resolution OASLM by incorporating the InGaAs/InP p-i-n photodiode to the FLC, thetopp'layermustbemadethinenoughtoreducelateral charge spreading &#x0005B;9&#x0005D; in that layer. In addition to increase the depletion width in the InGaAs layer and hence reduce the undesirable asymmetry in the driving wave form which may cause ion accumulation in the FLC. the background carrierconcentrationofInGaAs must be as small as possible &#x0005B;4&#x0005D;. We have consistently obtained InGaAs 3 background doping concentrations of Our O . 1-5xl01 cm- . calculations show that for this background carrier concentration and for typical FLC OASLM driving voltages, the depletion width should be about I to 3 pm. Our photodiodes have been grown accordingly and fabricated using</p>
<p>III. Photodiode Fabrication and Characterization TwoInGaAsfilmsweregrow -nbs/i-srceMBaon InPsubstrates:filmIis C In sustrtes:fil I s a ap+-InGaAs/u-JnGaAs/n+-JnGaAs homojunction structure with a 3 tm thick undoped InGaAs layer and film II is a p+-InP/U-InGaAs/n+-InP heterojunction structure with a 2.6 pm thick undoped InGaAs layer. Both films have a very thin (&lt; 1000 A) and heavily doped p-InGaAs ohmic contact layer on top. Figure 1. Schematic cross sections of (a) film I (In 0.5 3Ga0 .4 7 As homojunction) and (b) film II (InP/In 0 .5 3Ga0 .4 7 As/InP double heterojunction) photodiodes. Since the photosensor cannot be electrically probed after assembly with FLC into an OASLM, we fabricated mesa-type photodiodes of various areas (0.01, 0.05, 0.1 and 0.5 mm2 ) by standard photo-chemical processing. The structures of the photodiodes obtained form both films are shown in Figs. 1(a) and (b). Capacitance-voltage (C-V) and current-voltage (I-V) characteristics were measured by probing the top metal contact and the substrate contact. The normalized C-V characteristics of photodiodes of film I are shown in Fig. 2. At 5 V reverse bias, the capacitance was below 8 nF/cm for both films. However, while the Figure 2. Capacitance-voltage characteristics of filmI photodiode. slope of the inverse capacitance squared versus reverse voltage curve (1/C 2 -V characteristic ) is linear for film I (and yields a net background concentration of 15 3xl0 cm -3 ), it is nonlinear for film II because of the heterojunction. Still, we believe the background concentrationsarethesameinbothfilmsastheywere grown by the same technique. In Fig. 3 current densities versus applied voltage at room temperature are plotted for both films. Dark current densities were measured to be approximately 1-2x10-5 A/cm 2 at -5 V. At low reverse voltages the I-V characteristics fit well with a model of generation-recombination current in the depletion region assuming an intrinsic carrier concentration of 5x10 11 cm -3 and an effective carrier lifetime of 0.8-1.0 ps (Fig. 3) &#x0005B;6&#x0005D;. Figure 3. Measured dark current density, JD and current, density, Jg- versus applied voltage of (a) film I and (b) film II photodiodes.</p>
<p>IV. Anomalous dark currents Although diodes of smaller areas exhibit low dark currents, some deeo diodes of larger area are (0.5 mm2) m 2 have dark current densities 2 to 3 orders of magnitude higher (Fig. 4). These anomalous high dark currents have been found to correlate with visually observable defects(approximately25m 2 in area). The average defect density was approximately 2000 cm-2 for both films after MBE growth. This large dark current which may be caused by these defects may explain the poor contrast ratio of OASLM assembled with these films. We are currently investigating the nature and cause of these defects. Surface oxide on the mesa walls can also lead to additional leakage currents &#x0005B;10, 11&#x0005D; that we were able to eliminate by a simple passivation technique using a negative photoresist. This technique may also be used for pixellation of the InGaAs to improve OASLM spatial resolution. Figure 4. Dark cur-rent density versus applied voltage characteristics of film II diodes (1) without visible defects and (2) with a visible defect, approximately 25 s2 in area.</p>
<p>V. Summary and conclusions We have fabricated low-dark-current, low-capacitance InGaAs/InP p-i-n photodiodes which meet the requirements of IR-sensitive liquid crystal OASLMs. However, the presence of defects in the InGaAs films seems to increase photodiode dark current and impede the proper operation of FLC OASLMs fabricated with these films.</p>
<p>VI. Acknowledgments This work was supported by the Joint Program for Advanced Electronic Materials. The authors acknowledge helpful discussions with Prof. Garret Moddel's group at the University of Colorado, Boulder, Colorado. We also wish to thank Dr. Colin Wood for experimental assistance.</p></body>
<back>
<ref-list>
<ref id="r1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="confproc"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Sterling</surname><given-names>R.D.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>, "<article-title>Video-rate liquid-crystal light-valve using an amorphous silicon photoconductor</article-title>," in <conf-name>SID Int. Symp., Digest of Technical Papers 21</conf-name>, <fpage>327</fpage>-<lpage>329</lpage>, (<year>1990</year>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Moddel</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name></person-group>, "<article-title>Optically addressed spatial light modulator</article-title>," Ch. 11, in <source>Amorphous and Microcrystalline Semiconductor Devices</source>, <person-group person-group-type="editor"><name><surname>Kanicki</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name></person-group>, Editor, <year>1991</year>, <publisher-name>Artech House</publisher-name>, <publisher-loc>Boston</publisher-loc>, <fpage>369</fpage>-<lpage>412</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Barbier</surname><given-names>P.R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Moddel</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>Opt Eng</source> <volume>33</volume>(<issue>4</issue>), <fpage>1322</fpage>-<lpage>1329</lpage>, (<year>1994</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1117/12.166935</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Moddel</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Burdge</surname><given-names>G.L.</given-names></name></person-group>, "<article-title>Design of an optically addressed spatial light modulator sensitive 155-&#x003BC;m write light</article-title>," in <source>Spatial Light Modulators and Applications</source>, <volume>9</volume> <series>1995 OSA Technical Digest Series</series> (<publisher-name>Optical Society of America</publisher-name>, <publisher-loc>Washington DC</publisher-loc>, <year>1995</year>) <fpage>89</fpage>-<lpage>92</lpage></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Tsang</surname><given-names>W.T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Campbell</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>Appl Phys Lett</source> <volume>48</volume>(<issue>21</issue>), <fpage>1416</fpage>-<lpage>8</lpage>, (<year>1986</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.96925</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>T.-P</given-names></name><name><surname>Burrus</surname><given-names>C.A.J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Dentai</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>IEEE J Quantum Electron</source> <volume>QE-17</volume>, <fpage>232</fpage>-<lpage>238</lpage>, (<year>1981</year>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r7"><label>7</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Carey</surname><given-names>K.W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>S.-Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Crys</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>Growth</source>, <volume>98</volume>, <fpage>90</fpage>, (<year>1989</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/0022-0248(89)90189-9</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r8"><label>8</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Moddel</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name></person-group> "<article-title>Materials, devices, and applications</article-title>, in <source>Spatial light modulator technology</source>, <person-group person-group-type="editor"><name><surname>Efron</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></name></person-group>, Editor, (<year>1994</year>) <publisher-name>Marcel Dekker</publisher-name>, <publisher-loc>New York</publisher-loc>, <fpage>287</fpage>-<lpage>359</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r9"><label>9</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Moddel</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>Opt Lett</source> <volume>19</volume>, <fpage>2033</fpage>-<lpage>2035</lpage>, (<year>1994</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/OL.19.002033</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r10"><label>10</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Sloan</surname><given-names>S.R.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>Hewlett-Packard Journal</source>, <fpage>69</fpage>-<lpage>75</lpage>, (<year>1989</year>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r11"><label>11</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>R.-T</given-names></name><name><surname>Renner</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>IEEE Photonics Technology Lett</source> <volume>3</volume>, <fpage>934</fpage>, (<year>1991</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1109/68.93268</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></book-part></book-part-wrapper>
