<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
<collection-meta collection-type="conf">
<conference content-type="conf-name"><conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name><conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym></conference>
<conference content-type="conf-other-meta"><conf-date content-type="start">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-date content-type="end">
<day>19</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-loc>Nevada, 
<country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc></conference></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
<title-group>
<title>SLM Applications</title>
<alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/></title-group></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
<title-group>
<title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title></title-group>
<volume-in-collection>
<volume-number>14</volume-number>
<volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title></volume-in-collection></collection-meta>
<book-meta>
<book-title-group>
<book-title>Spatial Light Modulators</book-title></book-title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Burdge</surname><given-names>Geoffrey</given-names></name></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>Sadik C.</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group>
<pub-date publication-format="electronic">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></pub-date></book-meta>
<book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
<book-part-meta>
<title-group>
<title>Multiple quantum well based optical correlator with tunable nonlinear response</title></title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Rabinovich</surname><given-names>W. S.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Bowman</surname><given-names>S. R.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Beadie</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Tucker</surname><given-names>J. E.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Katzer</surname><given-names>D. S.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff"><sup>2</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Muth</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff"><sup>3</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Adler</surname><given-names>C. L.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff4" ref-type="aff"><sup>4</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Stone</surname><given-names>Bradley R.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff4" ref-type="aff"><sup>4</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Ikossi-Anastasiou</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff5" ref-type="aff"><sup>5</sup></xref></contrib>
<aff id="aff1">
<label>1</label>Code 5642 U.S. Naval Research Laboratory Washington, DC 20375 202-767-9413</aff>
<aff id="aff2">
<label>2</label>Code 6850 U.S. Naval Research Laboratory Washington, DC 20375</aff>
<aff id="aff3">
<label>3</label>Dept. of Electrical Engineering North Carolina State University</aff>
<aff id="aff4">
<label>4</label>Department of Physics Cleveland State University Cleveland, OH 44115</aff>
<aff id="aff5">
<label>5</label>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering Louisiana State University Baton Rouge, LA 70803</aff></contrib-group>
<elocation-id>197</elocation-id>
<permissions>
<copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
<copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
<copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
<license license-type="open-access">
<license-p>closed</license-p></license></permissions>
<abstract>
<p>The performance of a nonlinear joint transform correlator based upon an optically addressed multiple quantum well spatial light modulator is described. We show that the nonlinear response of the spatial light modulator can easily be tuned and demonstrate the utility of the system for face recognition.</p></abstract>
<kwd-group kwd-group-type="OCIS">
<title>OCIS codes</title>
<kwd>Nonlinear optical signal processing</kwd>
<kwd>optical correlators</kwd>
<kwd>quantum well devices</kwd>
<kwd>biometrics</kwd></kwd-group>
<counts>
<book-page-count count="6"/></counts></book-part-meta>
<body>
<p>IntroductionC Optical correlators have, for over three decades, been considered as attractive alternatives to digital image processing for a variety of pattern recognition tasks.' Until recently however, there has been a lack of appropriate materials with which to implement these devices. A practical correlator requires an efficient, compact source of coherent light, a fast "optical memory" for displaying templates and, for joint-transform correlators, a sensitive, high resolution optically addressed spatial light modulator (OASLM). Recently.nonlinearjointtransformcorrelatorshave been proposed as a way of enhancing the traditional architecture.ThesedevicesrequireanOASLMthat has a nonlinear response to light. In this paper we discuss a nonlinear joint transform optical correlator that uses a laser diode as the light source along with a GaAs/AlGaAs multiple quantum well optically addressed spatial light modulator (MQW-OASLM.) 5 We show that the nonlinearity of the MQW OASLM is easily tunable and that this tunability has important consequences for pattern recognition with these devices. In a joint-transform correlator the Fourier transforms of the object and reference images are interfered on an OASLM while a third, read, beam is diffractedofftheresultinghologram.Thistypeof correlator has the advantage of being relatively robust and easy to align as compared to the Van der Lught t gecometry. It can also have an additional advantage when the response function of the OASLM is not simply linear. Nonlinear joint transform correlators (NLJTC) can offer better performance than linear correlators, providing automatic DC blocking among other features. When the response function of the OASLM is tunable these devices can act as an additional, programmable, processing step. This processing occurs at the response time of the OASLM which can be significantly faster than doing the processing via Z serial . to parallel conversion of the image in the correlation plane followed by digital signal processing.</p>
<p>MQW OASLM Device Nonlinear joint transform correlators have been demonstrated using bulk photorefractive materials such as BaTiO,. These materials, though, have the disadvantages of being relatively insensitive to light and extremely insensitive to near infrared light. This means that near infrared diode lasers cannot be used as sources. Instead, much higher power visible sources such as argon-ion lasers are used. Even with these powerful sources the response times of bulk photorefractives are slow: typically milliseconds at best. In addition, because of the small index change in these materials, a volume hologram must be written to achieve reasonable diffraction efficiencies. Volume holograms, however, are less convenient than Raman-Nath holograms in optical correlator systems. Optically addressed liquid crystal SLM's offer another option for correlator systems. These materials are more sensitive to light and do not require volume holograms, but fast switching materials, such as ferroelectric liquid crystals, offer no grey scale response. Multiple quantum well based optically addressed SLM's are an attractive alternative to these other technologies. They are extremely sensitive to light. Depending on the mode of operation, a fluence of 100-nJcm2 issufficienttosaturatetheresponse 6 .This 500offers is approximately 10,000 times the sensitivity of bulk photorefractives and about 100 times the sensitivity of optically addressed liquid crystal SLM's. GaAs based any MQW OASLM's are sensitive to write light Msl at wavelength shorter than about 850 nm. The read beam must be resonant with the GaAs exciton at about 850 nm, mustbnee convenient olaithth for laser diode eorea sources. x T The aou0 operating rate of these devices is determined by the light intensity and the RC time. One Cm devices can operate a speeds of 1 MHz with sufficient illumination (about I W/cm 2). The resolution of the materials is high , with a modulation transfer function that drops to 50&#x00025; at a grating spacing of about 5 im. Device sizes of several square centimeters with good optical quality and uniformity are possible. Diffraction is in Raman-Nath mode as typical device thicknesses are on the order of a few microns. MQW OASLM's can be fabricated in a number of ways. MQWOASLMescanberatedinanume The device we used operated in areflective mode. R I The structure of the MQW-OASLM is shown in Fig. 1. It was grown by molecular beam epitaxy on an n-type GaAs substrate. The structure consists of the following layers: a 15 period AIAs/AlGaAs Bragg mirror doped n-type, followed by a0.5gimnlow temperature grown AlGaAs trapping layer, followed tr by followeyotherAIGaAsrapplerandcapped a100 period GaAs/AlGaAs multiple quantum well, by a p-doped AlGaAs layer. The reflective geometry significant advantages over previous transmissive devic a.tav dtcgorepita i fin devices that have used etching or epitaxial lift-off in tCei. that, after growth, no further processmng is needed. This gptye Greatly improves the optical quality of the 1 material resulting in very low scatter. Electrical contacts are m md otetpadbto ufcsada&#x000B1;0vl AC signal is applied. Details of the device performance and structure can be found elsewhere.' MQW OASLM's work via light induced screening of the applied electric field. The MQW layer acts as both a photodetector and the electro-optic medium. When a field is applied to the device, the position and magnitude of the heavy hole exciton absorption feature changes, resulting in both an absorption and index of refraction change near the band-gap of the material. When the device is exposed to write beams. photocarriers are created in the MQW layers which rapidly move across the device to screen the applied field. The presence, on either side of the MQW layers, of layers of trap laden low temperature grown (LTG) AlGaAs give the device its spatial resolution. Carriers that move into these layers, after having traversed the quantum wells, are trapped in about a picosecond. This prevents lateral drift, which would wash out the spatial pattern of screening created by the write beams. As the photocarriers screen the applied field in the illuminated regions, the heavy hole excitonic feature returns to its zero field state. Thus the absorption and index of refraction of the device becomes modulated in a pattern that mimics that of the write beams. It is important to note that the time scale of this process is not set by the transit time of the carriers across the device (about 300 picoseconds), but rather the time it takes to store enough charge in the LTG layers to screen the applied field. Thus the rise time of the device is determined by the intensity of the write beams. When illuminated by a hologram. the diffracted order's intensity rises until the applied field is screened in the illuminated regions. It then falls as the darker regions also screen. Thus diffraction from these devices is always transient. The device is reset by driving it with a square wave voltage. A new diffraction pulse is produced for every voltage cycle. The grey scale response of diffraction from these devices is determined by the light intensity, the drive frequency of the applied square wave and the nature of the detector which is used to observe the diffraction. When using a detector that integrates over at least a drive voltage cycle, the grey scale is approximately linear for low writing intensities. That is the diffraction efficiency is approximately proportional to the writing intensity. For higher intensities, the diffraction efficiency saturates and then begins to drop exponentially. The saturation intensity at which this change in behavior occurs is determined by the drive frequency. The faster the applied voltage is cycled the higher the saturation intensity. The slope of the grey scale in the linear regime is also affected by the drive frequency. The grey scale for the MQW OASLM used in our experiments is shown for two different drive frequencies ii Fig. 2. Nonlinear joint transform correlator We used the MQW OASLM to implement and test a tunable nonlinearjoint transform correlator. A diagram of the experimental setup is shown in Fig. 3. A single mode laser diode operating at 849 nm is used for both the read and write beams. Because of the high sensitivity of the device only 200 PW of write beam power was necessary to drive the device at a frame rate of several kHz. Both the reference and template images were high resolution transparencies. A 30 cm lens was used to create the Fourier transform hologram in the correlation plane on the MQW OASLM. A weak read beam was diffracted off the hologram. The read beam was inverse-Fourier transformed by a second lens onto the detection plane at which there was a high resolution CCD camera. TostudythetunabilityoftheNLTCweexamined the problem of face recognition. This is a current Figure 3 problem in biometrics with a variety of security applications. In prior theoretical work we predicted that the discrimnation of a MQW NLJTC for different faces could be changed by adjusting the SLM drive Figure 4 b frequency.9 This occurs because faces are complex objects with a wide range of spatial frequencies and intensities in the correlation plane. The brightest intensities tend to be near the center of the correlation plane, at low spatial frequencies. While the higher spatial frequencies tend to be weaker in intensity. By adjusting thegreyscaleoftheMQWOASLMtobesensitiveto certain intensity ranges we can emphasize or de- emphasize the importance of the lower or higher spatial frequencies. Figure 4 a and b shows the two input faces, A and B, that were used for correlation. Fig 5a shows the auto-correlation spot of face A correlated to itself. The coirelation spot was attenuated by a factor of 7. Fig 5b shows the unattenuated cross-correlation of face A to face B. Both correlations were done at a drive frequency of 4 kHz. At this drive frequency, where higher spatial frequencies are emphasized, the correlator can clearly distinguish the differences between the two faces. Figure 5a Figure 5b Theeffectofvaryingthedrivefrequencyisshown in Fig 6. Here the value of the correlation is determined by integrating the power in the correlation spot. Both theautoandcrosscorrelationsaredisplayed. The auto-correlation is strongly peaked at a drive frequency of 4 kHz. At this frequency the device is sensitive to the large area of the Fourier plane containing the higher spatial frequencies of the face. The cross-correlation is relatively flat with frequency. This is because faces A and B share fewer of the same high spatial frequency features but more of the same low frequency features (the overall shape of the face, for example). These lower spatial frequencies become more emphasized at higher drive frequencies and, so, the correlation drops Figure7 off less rapidly. Because of this difference in behavior, the discrimination of the correlator between faces can be tuned simply by changing the drive frequency of the device. This is shown in Fig. 6 which displays the ratio of the two graphs in Fig. 7 as a function of frequency. This ability to quickly tune the discrimination could be important in several applications. For example correlation at high driving frequencies could be used to pull out face-shaped objects from a scene. This can be followed rapidly by correlation at lower driving frequencies to identify a particular face. We observed similar results when comparing correlations ofprofiles and other facial views. correlation has held a great deal of promise for many years. but this promise has not been realized due to the unavailability of appropriate materials. Over the past decade. however, and particularly over the last five years developments in several areas have provided the necessary elements for all-optical processing. For optical sources, laser diodes have provided compact, highly efficient sources of coherent light. For generation of template images, ultra-fast electrically addressed MQW SLM's can provide 256x256 6 bit images at frame rates of hundreds of kilohertz." Optically addressed MQW OASLM's. such as the device described here, offer both incoherent to coherent conversion and nonlinear mixing in the correlation plane at rates up to I MHz. Finally, smart pixel arrays can be used for fast thresholding detection in the detection plane. In combination all these elements can provide pattern recognition at rates orders of magnitude faster than digital computer techniques.</p>
<p>Conclusion and future directions We have examined the performance of nonlinear joint transform correlator based upon an optically addressed multiple quantum well spatial light imodulator. The tunability of the nonlinearity in this device allows us to easily and rapidly change the discrimination of the correlator. Having demonstrated the utility of this system for static templates. we have begun work with a time varying input template and detection of the correlation that correlation at high speeds is possible with modest write light powers. Thus a future system using a fast electrically addressed SLM or other optical memory as input should allow correlations at a rate of several thousand to tens of thousands per second.</p>
<p>Acknowledgements The authors acknowledge the support of the Office of Naval Research and the National Research Council.</p></body>
<back>
<ref-list>
<ref id="r1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Vander Lught</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>IEEE Trans Information Theory IT-10</source>, (<year>1964</year>)<fpage>139</fpage></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Javidi</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>Appl. Opt.</source> <volume>28</volume>, <fpage>2358</fpage>, (<year>1989</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/AO.28.002358</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kuo</surname><given-names>Chung J.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>Appl. Opt.</source> <volume>31</volume>, <fpage>6264</fpage>, (<year>1992</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/AO.31.006264</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Partovi</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Glass</surname><given-names>A. M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chiu</surname><given-names>T. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>D. T. H.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>Opt. Lett.</source> <volume>18</volume>, <fpage>906</fpage>, (<year>1993</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/OL.18.000906</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Bowman</surname><given-names>S.R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Rabinovich</surname><given-names>W.S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kyono</surname><given-names>C.S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Katzer</surname><given-names>D.S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ikossi-Anastasiou</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>Appl. Phys. Lett.</source> <volume>65</volume>, <fpage>2244</fpage>, (<year>1994</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.112160</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Rabinovich</surname><given-names>W.S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bowman</surname><given-names>S.R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Katzer</surname><given-names>D.S.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>Appl. Phys. Lett.</source> <volume>66</volume>, <fpage>956</fpage>, (<year>1995</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.113568</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r7"><label>7</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Bowman</surname><given-names>S.R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Rabinovich</surname><given-names>W.S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Katzer</surname><given-names>D.S.</given-names></name></person-group>, in preparation</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r8"><label>8</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Rabinovich</surname><given-names>W.S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bowman</surname><given-names>S.R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Mahon</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Walsh</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Asler</surname><given-names>C.L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kazter</surname><given-names>D.S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ikossi-Anastasiou</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>J. Opt. Soc. B</source> <volume>13</volume>, <fpage>2235</fpage>, (<year>1996</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/JOSAB.13.002235</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r9"><label>9</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Adler</surname><given-names>C.L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bowman</surname><given-names>S.R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Rabinovich</surname><given-names>W.S.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>Opt. Comm.</source> <volume>136</volume>, <fpage>75</fpage>, (<year>1997</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/S0030-4018(96)00657-8</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r10"><label>10</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Trezza</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Stack</surname><given-names>R.D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>Spatial Light Modulators</source>, <series>Technical Digest</series> (<publisher-name>Optical Society of America</publisher-name>, <publisher-loc>Washington, DC</publisher-loc>, (<year>1997</year>)pp. <fpage>5</fpage></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></book-part></book-part-wrapper>
