<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
<collection-meta collection-type="conf">
<conference content-type="conf-name"><conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name><conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym></conference>
<conference content-type="conf-other-meta"><conf-date content-type="start">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-date content-type="end">
<day>19</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-loc>Nevada, 
<country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc></conference></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
<title-group>
<title>SLM Applications</title>
<alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/></title-group></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
<title-group>
<title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title></title-group>
<volume-in-collection>
<volume-number>14</volume-number>
<volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title></volume-in-collection></collection-meta>
<book-meta>
<book-title-group>
<book-title>Spatial Light Modulators</book-title></book-title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Burdge</surname><given-names>Geoffrey</given-names></name></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>Sadik C.</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group>
<pub-date publication-format="electronic">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></pub-date></book-meta>
<book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
<book-part-meta>
<title-group>
<title>On the Storage Capacity of Electrically Addressable SLMs in Coherent Optical Information Processing Systems</title></title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Teiwes</surname><given-names>Stephan</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Schwarzer</surname><given-names>Heiko</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Aagedal</surname><given-names>Harald</given-names></name><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff"><sup>*</sup></xref></contrib>
<aff id="aff1">
<label>1</label>Berlin Institute of Optics Rudower Chaussee 6, 12484 Berlin, 
<country country="DE">Germany</country></aff>
<aff id="aff2">
<label>*</label>University of Karlsruhe, Department of Informatics Am Fasanengarten 5, 76131 Karlsruhe, 
<country country="DE">Germany</country></aff></contrib-group>
<elocation-id>258</elocation-id>
<permissions>
<copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
<copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
<copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
<license license-type="open-access">
<license-p>closed</license-p></license></permissions>
<abstract>
<p>The development of electrically addressable spatial light modulators (EASLs) is leading to the implementation of new opto-electronic information processing devices, where the optical function can be switched. Applications such as optical image processing, free-space communications or holographic pattern generation have been described in literature. The amount of information which can be processed in coherent optical systems depends on the storage properties of modulators. However, only few publications deal with this topic &#x0005B;1,2,3&#x0005D;.</p>
<p>In this paper, the storage properties of an EASLM in a coherent optical system and the transmission of information in this system are expressed in terms of information theory. It is demonstrated that the restriction of an EASLM to fixed modulation schemes may seriously disable an error-free processing of information due to strong noise effects. These noise effects are described by measures of information theory. We focus on coding methods of diffractive optics to reduce the noise energy in optical signal waves which carry information. The correspondence of these methods to channel coding methods known from communication theory is stressed. Finally, the storage capacity of an EASLM is analysed in a numerical simulation experiment.</p></abstract>
<kwd-group kwd-group-type="OCIS">
<title>OCIS codes</title>
<kwd>Spatial light modulators</kwd>
<kwd>diffractive optics</kwd>
<kwd>optical information processing</kwd>
<kwd>information theory</kwd></kwd-group>
<counts>
<book-page-count count="7"/></counts></book-part-meta>
<body>
<p>EASLMs in Diffractive Optics EASLMs are characterized by a pixelated microstruc- ture, where the optical properties of each pixel can be electrically controlled. The lateral pixel size of currently available EASLMs ranges from 20 to 100 microns, and thus it is much larger than the wavelength of visible light. If an EASLM is illuminated with coherent light, due to the micropixel structure, it behaves as diffractive optical element. In this case, the optical function of the EASLM is basically specified by the pixelated transmis sion function which corresponds to a certain diffracted wave. The effect of an EASLM on a coherent illumination wave can be expressed in terms of diffraction theory. It is helpful to simplify this formalism by restriction to scalar theory &#x0005B;4&#x0005D;. In the case of EASLMs, this is allowed for two reasons. First, the pixel structures of an EASLM are large compared to the wavelength of the used illumination. Secondly, EASLMs behave as thin optical media. Hence, and due to the pixel struc ture, the transmission function of an EASLM can be described by G(xo, xj) = rectAz(xo, xi) * T(xo, xj) (1) denoting the convolution of the discrete transmission function N-1 T(xoxi) ZT(kAxlx)S(x0 - k-xx,- liAx) k,1=0 (2) with a rectagular pixel function rect(xo,xi) of lateral size Ax in both directions. 6 denotes the Dirac func tion. The values of T are complex and restricted to a certain modulation domain which depends on the tech nical properties of an EASLM. Figure 1 depicts the modulation of an illumination wave S by an EASLM and the subsequent wave propagation in a schematic view. Using the argument that an EASLM is a thin op tical element, the modulated wave U can be expressed Figure 1. A pixelated EASLM with the discrete transmis- sion function (Uk,1) generates a diffracted wave which is specified by vector components u,,, on a sampling grid. simplybytheproduct U(xo, a) = S(xo, xX) T(xo, xa . (3) This wave propagates in free space and forms a diffracted wave u which can be optically processed or detected by a sensor. In order to determine the shape of a diffracted wave in a specified plane the diffraction integral has to be solved. However, since the pixel struc- tures of an EASLM are large compared to the wavelength, the maximum diffraction angle is quite small. Consequently, the diffracted wave is well expressed by the Fresnel integral in a near field or by the Fraunhofer integral in a far field region. According to figure 1, the diffracted wave is com- pletely specified on a sampling grid as well as the trans- mission function of the modulator. Thus, instead of integral equations, the corresponding summation equa tions can be used to determine the complex amplitude of the diffracted wave on the grid points. If the mod- ulated wave right behind the EASLNI is defined by the twodimensional complex vector U (Uk,1), k, I = 0,.., N- 1, the corresponding diffracted wave in a dis- tance zo is completely specified by the Fresnel transform vector u = FrT&#x0005B;U&#x0005D; with A- Up,u, = UkieXO jA(pv)-Az(k,1)1 , (4) k,1=o pv= 0,.. ,N - 1. Ax and AA denote the sampling spacings in the plane of the EASLM and the output plane in a distance zo, respectively. The vectors (k,1) and (p, v) run through all sampling points in the cor- responding planes. If the sampling condition A Azo () N is considered, the Fresnel transform according to (4) is an invertable linear operator &#x0005B;5&#x0005D;. Complex amplitudes between the sample points u,,, result from interpola tion effects which will not be discussed here. In analogy to the above examinations, the diffracted wave in the far field is described by the Fourier transform vector u FT&#x0005B;U&#x0005D; with N-1 UAV U,,i N (6) k,1=0 f denotes the focal length of a Fourier transform lens that is usually applied to generate far field diffracted waves. In the Fourier case, the sampling condition (5) is fulfilled with zo = f. In coherent information processing, optical functions are implemented via diffracted waves. A diffractive element is used to generate a certain diffracted wave and so to perform a desired function. EASLMs give the opportunity to implement computer-generated transmis sion functions of diffractive elements by direct adressing of the modulator pixels. Different functions can be achieved by addressing the pixels with different in formation defining the transmission function or corre spondingly the diffracted wave.</p>
<p>EASLM as Planar Storage Medium A computer-generated transmission function is digitally represented by a two-dimensional vector data structure and stored in a computer memory. The information of the vector components specifies amplitude or phase values which can be dynamically mapped onto the pixel matrix of an EASLM. This mapping can be interpreted as computer memory access, where a section of the com puter memory is copied to the EASLM. To account for this, the EASLM is a storage medium which is charac- terized by an electrical write-in and an optical read-out mechanism. The read-out is performed in parallel by illuminating the EASLM with an optical carrier wave. This process is usually denoted as modulation of the carrier wave. A modulated wave carries the informa tion of a computer-generated transmission function and can be used to implement an optical function. The ca pability of an EASLM to implement different optical functions strongly depends on its storage capacity. The storage capacity C of an EASLM determines the maximum number of bits which can be correctly read out per time interval. Considering an EASLM as thin optical element, according to equation (3), a modulated wave right behind the EASLM carries the information introduced by the EASLM pixels. Thus if an EASLM is characterized by an array of N2 pixels and a modulation alphabet D containing |D| modulation values,thecapacityisgivenby C = N 2 log2 DI bits (7) per pixel frame. This value determines an upper limit without consideration of any noise effects. However, such effects may occur during the free-space transmis- sion of the information-carrying signal wave or due to technical inadequacies of the EASLM &#x0005B;6,5&#x0005D;. Figur 2. Equivalent representations ofan information vec- tor with its amplitude to the left and its phase to the right. The binary vector in (top) is invertably transformed into complex-valued vectors applying a Fresnel operator (mid (le) and a Fourier operator (bottom).</p>
<p>Free-space Transmission of Information EASLMs are used to modulate in parallel digital in- formation, coded as amplitude or phase values, onto a carrier wave. Right behind the EASLI a digital in- formation vector U is represented by discrete modulation values located on a sampling grid. The infor- mation propagates with its carrier wave through free space and changes its representation continuously with the distance covered due to wave-physical effects. As already motivated before, the propagation of the mod- ulated wave U is adequately described by the Fresnel integral. In correspondence with this integral the dis- crete Fresnel operator (4) determines the complex am- plitudes of the propagated wave U on a sampling grid of a plane in a distance zo. If the sampling condition (5) is fulfilled, the discrete Fresnel operator is invertable. In this case, the sample vector U of the modulated wave U is invertably transformed into a vector u. Conse quently, both vectors U and u represent the same infor- mnation. The complex amplitudes between the sample values up,, of a propagated wave u do not give any additional information since they also result from a linear combination of the values Uk. -We draw the fundamental conlusion: The information of a modulated carrier wave is preserved by the wave propagation process and can be identified on a sampling grid which is specified by the sampling condition (5). Figure 2 demonstrates an example of three equivalent representations of the sarne information vector that differs only due to the application of discrete wave propagation operators. In the upper row the information vector U is specified by an array of 55 x 55 san-ples with binary amplitudes (left) and constant phase (right). The illustrative example shows a binary smiley the infornation of which amounts to 3025 bits. This information can be used to address an EASLM and so to modulate a carrier wave. The effect of wave propagation can be numerically simulated on the basis of equations (4) and (6). In our example, we assumed a pixel size of Ax 30pm in the EASLM plane, the wavolength A 633nm. and condition (5). The infor-nation vector u of the propagated wave u in the near field distance zo = 200m in shown in the middle row. Another representation of the information depicted in the bottom row appears in the far field. Compared to the original information vector U the propagated vectors u look very complicated since each vector component is not any longer a binary value but a complex value of a continuous domain. The impression that a complex vector u might carry more information than the original vector U is deceptive. Using the inverse propagation operator U can be directly reduced to u confirming that the information vectors, as in fig-ure 2, are equivalent and carry the same amount of information.</p>
<p>Information Processing and Detection In coherent optical systens. information processing or detection is performed via diffracted signal waves in a specified plane which we call the output plane. It is essential that the diffracted wave has a certain shape in order to perform a desired optical function or to show an information vector such as the smiley in figure 2. Hence, it is sensible to define the information vector of a coherent optical signal in the output plane. From a specified information vector, generated by a diffracted wave, the corresponding transmission function of the EASLM is derived by an inverse wave propagation operator. This point of view implies a different meaning of the storage capacity of the EASLM. We redefine the storage capacity by the maximum number of bits which are correctly received in the output plane per time interval. If no noise effects occur, its value is given by C = N2 10g 2 IS bits, (8) where S represents the finite alphabet of information symbols. Note, that in general D -6 S. Noise Effects of EASLMs In most cases, the transmission function, derived from a discrete information vector by an inverse propaga tion operator, is complex-valued. This can be directly confirmed by the example in figure 2, where a binary information vector is transformed into equivalent complex vectors. The resulting problem is that there is no EASLM available which is capable to implement arbitrary complex transmission functions &#x0005B;7&#x0005D;. Depending on its techical properties an EASLM is restricted to a certain modulation domain DC C&lt; = {x EC : | &lt; 1}. (9) The implementation of a complex vector U by an EASLM which is restricted to a modulation domain D can be mathematically modeled by the projected vector PD&#x0005B;U&#x0005D; = U +N, (10) where the projection operator PD is characterized by the norming condition U EDNxN A ||0 - U|1 2 =m . (11) PD minimizes the additive projection noise N but in general the occurance of noise cannot be avoided. Due to its restricted modulation characteristics, an EASLM itself can be a &#x0201C;noise source&#x0201D; leading to a noisy infor- mation vector FT&#x0005B;V&#x0005D; = u+n (12) in the output plane. Noise effects in an optical system go together with a loss of information or equivalently with a decrease of storage capacity. . Projection noise may have serious consequences on Pro jetionnomayhaveer onsequces thquliyoannfrmtinvctroadffacedav, where by the example mn figure 3, This is demonstrated Thiisdmostrtebyteeampeifigrewhre the complex transmission function of the binary signal th infigure emlxa 2has been n computed sonfutionoftheinrs by aninverse Fourier ia operator and projected onto its phase. Such a phase-only transmission function, shown to the left, can be well implemented by an EASLM. However, the image Figure 3. The projection of a complex transmission function onto its phase (left) leads to strong projection noise in the information vector of the diffracted wave (right). of the binary signal in the far field is strongly distorted by additive noise as depicted to the right. Obviously, there are pixels the gray value of which has changed from bright to dark and vice versa. Theory of Noisy Information Transmission The additive noise which is introduced by the projec tion PD can be numerically determined if the informa tion vector, the propagation operator, and the modulation domain D are specified. However, it has to be emphasized that the noise vector n differs with each information vector u. As a consequence, a general ex amination of the storage capacity of an EASLNI can only lead to an average limit. We apply methods of information theory &#x0005B;8,9,5&#x0005D; to express the loss of information due to noise effects and so to derive the storage capacity. From an information-theoretical point of view, an EASLM is an information source which generates information vectors u in the output plane of an opti cal system. Each vector component is an element of a finite signal alphabet S {s0,.. ,Sq-1}, where each signal sj, j = 0,..,q - 1, is assumed to occur statisti cally independently with a certain probability p(sj) and j p(sj) = 1 holds. So, the EASLM is characterized by its source entropy s -1 K(S) = -N Ep(s) log 2 p(Sj) (13) j=0 determining the average information of an information vector. vetr The influence of the noise effects, due the restricted modulation characteristic of anEASLM, can be inter preted mdlto as the hrceitco uncertainty about nESM the correctness a of eitr ade- pee steucranyaottecreteso e tected byheuvclnrp information vector. This quantity is expressed 1 = 1 K(S|S)= N&#x000A3;E&#x0005B;log2 PSi (j1 The argument of the expectation E determines the information of the event that a symbol si is the original information signal but sj is detected due to noise. For the sake of simplicity it can be assumed that the alphabet 9 of the detected signals is equal to S. The difference between source and equivocal entropy, the mutual information I(S,5)= K(S) - K(SIS), (15) is the amount of correctly transmitted information which can be evaluated in the detection plane. The maximum mutual information C = max I(S, 9) (16) is known as channel capacity. In the context of this pa- per, C gives an upper bound of the storage capacity of an EASLM. Evidently, a statement about a representa- tive value of I(S, 9) has to be achieved by consideration of sufficiently many information vectors. EASLM Plane Output yPlane x P Y&#x0005D; Redundance Domain o xo InfDmaion omatin Signal EASLMWave Figure 4. Concept of a redundant optical signal wave. The signal wave, located in the output plane, consists of sep- arated information and redundance domains. In contrast, information and redundance are mixed in the transmission function in the EASLNI plane.</p>
<p>Redundant Coding of Information A basic aim of coding theory &#x0005B;9&#x0005D; is to develop meth- ods to optimize the mutual information in communication systems. Efficient coding schemes are already used for the detection or correction of bit errors occur ing due to noise on the transmission channel. These coding schemes are based on the introduction of redundant symbols which are used to control the correctness of information symbols. Interestingly, the basic idea of redundant coding can also be used to diminish the projection noise of an EASLM. Different coding methods from diffractive optics are known, where parameters of freedom are introduced in Figure 5. Block-encoding scheme for optical signals. The encoded signals are characterized by low additive projection noise. order to adapt the discrete transmission vector U to a specified modulation domain D &#x0005B;10,12,11,13&#x0005D;. The pa rameters of freedom are redundant signal values com parable to the control symbols of an error correcting code. In figure 4, the concept of a redundant optical signal wave is depicted. The signal wave, representing a diffracted wave in the output plane, is partitioned in an information and a redundance domain. The aim of a coding procedure is to define the redundance with respect to the information in a smart way so that the resulting coded signal wave corresponds to a transmis sion function which fulfills the modulation restriction of the EASLM in good approximation. As a result, additive projection noise is reduced. In summary, this basic effect of a redundant coding scheme is sketched in fig- ure 5. It should be mentioned that in some applications only the amplitude of the signal wave is used to carry information. In this case, also the phase parameters represent redundance which can be used to code the signal wave. Figure6.Conceptofaniterativecodingmethod. The most efficient and widely used coding meth ods in diffractive optics are based on iterative opti- mization strategies &#x0005B;11,10,13&#x0005D;. The principle of these coding methods is represented by the flow diagram in figure 6. Following the directions of the arrows, the iteration moves back and forth between the representa tion domains of the coded signal wave c and the cor- responding transmission function C. In both domains projection operations are performed on the one hand to adapt C to the modulation restrictions of the EASLM and on the other hand to diminish the noise effects the information block of the signal wave. The redun- dant parameters are developed during the iteration that a merit function such as the mutual information in (15) is optimized. This aim can be achieved by minimization of the energy of the projection noise. Figure7. Resultofan iterative codinglrocedure. The oh- tainedtransmissionfunction(left)foraphase-onlyEASL generates the desired information vetor (right) in the far field. Figure 7 demonstrates the effectiveness of an iter ative coding method as it is described in &#x0005B;13&#x0005D;. In this example, the binary signal, shown in figure 2, has been coded to be generated in the far field by a phase-only EASLM. According to figure 5, the block of 55 x 55 binary information samples has been embedded in a larger block of 80 x 80 samples. Thus 3375 redundant symbols have been available to optimize the merit func tion. Comparing the results of figure 3 and figure 7, it becomes obvious that coding methods from diffractive optics optimize the mutual information in the output plane and with it the storage capacity of an EASLM.</p>
<p>Storage Capacity of EASLM - An Example The storage capacity of an EASLNI in a coherent op- tical system is limited by the maximum mutual infor- mation. This quantity is difficult to determine since the coding results may differ for different information vectors. However, empirical examinations show that if information vectors consist of equally distributed signal components and, to account for this, have the same en- ergy, the coding results are very similar with respect to projection noise. From information theory it is known that Huffman's coding method &#x0005B;8,9&#x0005D; can be used to code digital information to obtain the desired statistical dis- tribution of signal components. If information vectors are coded by applying Huffman's method the iterative coding methods of diffractive optics show very similar results with respect to the noise energy as merit func tion. In this case, a general statement on the storage capacity can be derived by numerical simulations. Figure 8. Progress of source entropy, equivocal entropy, and mutual information for N = 128 and increasing alphabet size jS|. The aim of a simple simulation experiment was to derive the capacity of an EASLM with 128 x 128 pixels and a phase-only modulation domain D = {x EC : Ix = 1}. (17) According to figure 1, the EASLM is capable of gener ating diffraction waves which are specified on a samling grid with 128 x 128 sample values. Thus the informa tion vector of the signal wave has at maximum 128 x 128 components. In the simulation experiment, such infor mation vectors with equally distributed and quantized amplitude signal components have been generated. An iterative coding scheme according to &#x0005B;13&#x0005D; has been used to code the information vectors in 100 iteration cycles, where free phase parameters served as redundance &#x0005B;6,5&#x0005D;. For each coded vector, the mutual information I(S, S) have been computed according to equation (15), where S = S had been assumd. By taking many information vectors into account, the value of the mutual information I(S,8) converged quickly to a limit. In order to find the capacity of the EASLM, I(S, S) has been com puted for an increasing number |S| of equally quantized amplitude signals. The results of the simulation experiment are sum- marized by the diagram in figure 8 showing the progress of source entropy, equivocal entropy, and mutual infor mation for an increasing alphabet size |S|. The source entropy which is linearly growing with the logarithm of IS represents the absolute upper limit of the storage ca pacity stated by equation (8). An increasing alphabet size corresponds with with a finer quantization of signal amplitudes. However, the finer a quantization is per- formed the more signal errors occur due to noise effects. This phenomenon is expressed by the progress of equiv- ocal entropy in figure 8. Asymptotically, the equivocal entropy behaves like the source entropy. In account to this, the mutual information converges against an upper limit which is identified as storage capacity of the EASLM considering projection noise. It should be kept in mind that the values of the information measures depend on the coding procedure and the number of its iteration cycles.</p>
<p>Conclusion The application of EASLMs in coherent optical systems for information processing purposes is becoming very attractive due to remarkable advances in EASLM tech- nology. The performance of such systems is character- ized by the amount of information that can be stored, transmitted, or processed per time interval. so theo- retical methods to measure information introduced by an EASLM are helpful to characterize and optimize the systemperformance. In this paper, we focused on the storage proper- tiesofEASLMsincoherentopticalsystems. Consid- ering paraxial diffraction theory, it has been explained that information modulated onto a carrier wave by an EASLM is preserved by the wave propagation and can be identified on a sampling grid. The storage capac ity of an EASLM has been defined as the maximum number of bits which can be correctly evaluated from a diffracted wave in the output plane of a system. Infor- rnation which is specified in a domain of the diffracted wave usually corresponds to a complex transmission function to be implemented by an EASLM. However, currently available EASLMs are restricted to a limited set of modulation values. As a consequence, strong noise effects may occur and reduce the storage capacity of an EASLM. The loss of capacity has been stressed in terms of information theory. Additionally, it has been demonstrated that redundant coding methods from dif- fraction theory can be used to diminish these noise ef- fects and improve the storage capacity. Finally, in a simple example, the storage capacity of a specified coherent system with one EASLM has been examined assuming a certain coding scheme. The pre- sented results are strongly related to the discussed ex- ample and its boundary conditions. However, it is pos- sible to adapt the proposed analysis methods to other system parametrizations.</p>
<p>Acknowledgments This work has been supported by the Bunderminis- terium fir Bildung, Wissenschaft, Forschung und Tech- nologie, Germany, under contract 01M3019B6.</p></body>
<back>
<ref-list>
<ref id="r1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Neifeld</surname><given-names>M. A.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Computer-generated holography for optical memory using sparse data words: capacity and error tolerance</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Appl. Opt.</source> <volume>32</volume>, <fpage>5125</fpage>-<lpage>5134</lpage>, (<year>1993</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/AO.32.005125</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Neifeld</surname><given-names>M. A.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Improvements in the capacity of computer-generated holographic storage using the Lee method with sparse multivalued reconstructions</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Appl. Opt.</source> <volume>34</volume>, <fpage>1396</fpage>-<lpage>1400</lpage>, (<year>1995</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/AO.34.001396</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Psaltis</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Neifeld</surname><given-names>M. A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yamamura</surname><given-names>A. A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kobayashi</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Optical memory disks in optical information processing systems</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Appl. Opt.</source> <volume>29</volume>, <fpage>2038</fpage>-<lpage>2057</lpage>, (<year>1990</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/AO.29.002038</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Goodman</surname><given-names>J. W.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>Introduction to Fourier Optics</source> (<publisher-name>Mc-Graw-Hill, Publishing</publisher-name>, <publisher-loc>New York</publisher-loc> <year>1968</year>).</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="thesis"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Teiwes</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Entwurf linearer optischer Prozessoren mit Anwendungen in der Informationstechnik</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Ph D Dissertation</source> <publisher-name>U. Chemnitz</publisher-name>, <publisher-loc>Germany</publisher-loc>, (<year>1996</year>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Teiwes</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Schwarzer</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wyrowski</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Aagedal</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Storage capacity of pixelated paraxial diffractive elements</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Proc SPIE</source> <volume>2969</volume>, <fpage>163</fpage>-<lpage>169</lpage>, (<year>1996</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1117/12.262593</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r7"><label>7</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Neff</surname><given-names>J. A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Athale</surname><given-names>R. A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S. H.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Two- dimensional Spatial Light Modulators</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>IEEE Proc</source> <volume>78</volume>, <fpage>826</fpage>-<lpage>854</lpage>, (<year>1990</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1109/5.53402</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r8"><label>8</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ash</surname><given-names>R. B.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>Information Theory</source> (<publisher-name>Dover Publications</publisher-name>, <publisher-loc>New York</publisher-loc>, <year>1990</year>).</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r9"><label>9</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>McEliece</surname><given-names>R. J.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>The Theory of Information and Coding</source> (<publisher-name>Addison-Wesley, Publishing</publisher-name>, <publisher-loc>New York</publisher-loc>, <year>1977</year>).</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r10"><label>10</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Gerchberg</surname><given-names>R. W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Saxton</surname><given-names>W. O.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>A practical algorithm for the determination of phase from image and diffraction plane pictures</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Optik</source> <volume>35</volume>, <fpage>237</fpage>-<lpage>246</lpage>, (<year>1971</year>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r11"><label>11</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Fienup</surname><given-names>J. R.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Phase retrieval algorithms: a comparison</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Appl. Opt.</source> <volume>21</volume>, <fpage>2758</fpage>-<lpage>2769</lpage>, (<year>1982</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/AO.21.002758</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r12"><label>12</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Akahori</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Spectrum leveling by an iterative algorithm with a dummy area for synthesizing the kinoform</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Appl. Opt.</source> <volume>25</volume>, <fpage>802</fpage>-<lpage>811</lpage>, (<year>1986</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/AO.25.000802</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r13"><label>13</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wyrowski</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Diffractive optical elements: iterative calculation of quantized, blazed phase structures</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>J. Opt. Soc. Am. A</source> <volume>7</volume>, <fpage>961</fpage>-<lpage>969</lpage>, (<year>1990</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/JOSAA.7.000961</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></book-part></book-part-wrapper>
