<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
<collection-meta collection-type="conf">
<conference content-type="conf-name"><conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name><conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym></conference>
<conference content-type="conf-other-meta"><conf-date content-type="start">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-date content-type="end">
<day>19</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-loc>Nevada, 
<country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc></conference></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
<title-group>
<title>SLM Materials and Sructures</title>
<alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/></title-group></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
<title-group>
<title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title></title-group>
<volume-in-collection>
<volume-number>14</volume-number>
<volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title></volume-in-collection></collection-meta>
<book-meta>
<book-title-group>
<book-title>Spatial Light Modulators</book-title></book-title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Burdge</surname><given-names>Geoffrey</given-names></name></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>Sadik C.</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group>
<pub-date publication-format="electronic">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></pub-date></book-meta>
<book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
<book-part-meta>
<title-group>
<title>The Concept of Electroholography and its Implementation in KLTN Crystals</title></title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Balberg</surname><given-names>Michal</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Razvag</surname><given-names>Meir</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Vidro</surname><given-names>Shimon</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Refaeli</surname><given-names>Eli</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Agranat</surname><given-names>Aharon J.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref><xref rid="cor1" ref-type="corresp"><sup>*</sup></xref></contrib>
<aff id="aff1">
<label>1</label>The Interdisciplinary Center for Neural Computing and Division of Applied Physics. The Hebrew University of Jerusalem, Jerusalem 91904, 
<country country="IL">ISRAEL</country></aff></contrib-group>
<author-notes>
<corresp id="cor1">
<label>*</label>T. 972 2 658 4710; Fax 972 2 658 6069; <email>AGRANAT@shum.huji.ac.il</email></corresp></author-notes>
<elocation-id>118</elocation-id>
<permissions>
<copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
<copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
<copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
<license license-type="open-access">
<license-p>closed</license-p></license></permissions>
<abstract>
<p>We present an experimental demonstration of <bold>Electroholography</bold> which is a new generic architecture for spatial light modulation. It is shown that Electroholography, which is based on the voltage controlled photorefractive effect at the paraelectric phase, enables to govern the reconstruction process, and perform electrical multiplexing of volume holograms by an external electric field.</p></abstract>
<kwd-group kwd-group-type="OCIS">
<title>OCIS codes</title>
<kwd>Photorefractive nonlinear optics</kwd>
<kwd>Volume holographic gratings</kwd>
<kwd>Electroholography</kwd>
<kwd>Spatial light modulators</kwd></kwd-group>
<counts>
<book-page-count count="3"/></counts></book-part-meta>
<body>
<p>Electroholography (EH) is a generic concept in optoelectronics, which enables to govern the reconstruction process of volume holograms by an external electric field. EH is based on the use of the voltage controlled photorefractive (PR) effect in crystals at the paraelectric phase(l) . The PR effect enables the recording of volume holograms in a crystal, by spatially modulating its index of refraction in response to light energy it absorbs. In crystals at the paraelectric phase the PR effect is voltage controlled, namely, one can control the efficiency of the effect by applying an external electric field to the crystal during the reading (reconstructing) stage. In general, the diffraction efficiency of a phase hologram is proportional to the local photoinduced changes in the index of refraction (6(An)). At the paraelectric phase the electrooptically induced modulation of the index ofrefraction depends quadratically on the induced (low frequency) polarization (1). When, during the PR process, a space charge field Ese(x) is formed in the crystal, the modulation which it induces in the index of refraction, and contributes constructively to the diffraction is given by: 6LAn(x)&#x0005D; n'gFE E where 6&#x0005B;An(x)&#x0005D; is the amplitude of the induced birefringence grating, no is the refractive index, g is the effective quadratic electrooptic coefficient, F is the dielectric constant (assuming the polarization is in the linear region (i.e. P = SE), with &#x000BB;,&gt;&gt;1), and Eo is the externally applied field. Thus it can be seen that a hologram stored as a spatial distribution of a space charge is transparent to the reference beam, unless an external electric field is applied. The application of the field causes the space charge to induce a spatially correlated modulation in the index of refraction which diffracts the reference beam and reconstructs the hologram. It should also be noted that since it is required that the reference beam will be Bragg-matched to the recorded hologram, a Bragg-detuning occurs by changing the field during the reconstruction (2). It can be shown that in a transmission geometry with equal angles of incidence there is no detuning. However, in a reflection geometry the detuning is zero only when the external field during the reading stage (ER) is equal to the external field used in the writing stage (E\N) Thus, the transmission geometry is desirable for devices in which analog control of the diffraction is required, whereas the reflection geometry is advantageous for the implementation of electric field multiplexing of the holograms. EH was originally conceived for the implementation of artificial neural networks(3) In the EH ANN the integration between the electronic processor and the holographic synapses is done at the component level (3). Each neuron is an electronic circuit integrated with a minute volume hologram acting as its synaptic terminals. Thus, a neuron complete with its synapses is implemented in an area element. As a result the dimension of the network scales as the area of the device (rather than its square root as in purely electronic realizations). The EH concept was experimentally demonstrated on a system containing two EH pixels(4). A KLTN crystal doped with copper and vanadium was used. The temperature of the crystal was set to 12C above its phase transition temperature, therefore the experiments were performed well within the paraelectric phase. Two samples (2x2xl mm each ) were cut and polished along the crystallographic &#x0005B;100&#x0005D; direction, for realizing the two transmission EH pixels. Gold electrodes were sputtered over the edges perpendicular to the optical axis of the system. The same SLM was used to produce the source images of the holograms stored in the EH elements. During writing, a different picture created by the SLM is stored in each one of the EH pixels separately. During reading (reconstruction), the reference beam is incident on both pixels and the stored holograms are reconstructed according to the voltages applied to the two EH elements (Va and Vb respectively). Consider Figure I showing a typical experiment. The Letters 'H' and 'U' are produced by the SLM, and are stored as holograms in the EH pixels a and b respectively. Reconstruction of these letters is shown in Figure la and lb. In figure la Va=200V (producing a field of IkV/cm on the crystal), and Vb=O. In Figure lb Va=0 and Vb=200V. In Figure Ic Va=Vh=200V and consequently both hologram are reconstructed and superimposed in the detectors array plane. Figure 1. Selective reconstruction from two Electroholographic elements (a) V.x'on' &amp; VB='Off, (b) V,='off &amp; V1 'on', and (c) VA='on' &amp; VB='on' Electric field multiplexing of three planar gratings in a reflection EH element is presented in Figure 2. We recorded reflection holograms on a sample of KLTN crystal. The sample dimensions were 4x4x3 mm , it was cut and polished along the crystallographic &#x0005B;001&#x0005D; directions Transparent ITO electrodes where deposited on the optical faces in order to align the external electric field with the direction of the grating wave vector. The three gratings were recorded under fields of 1.7, 2.7, and 3.7 kV/cm respectively. Finally, we multiplexed images of a resolution target rotated at three different angles under fields of 1.7 , 2.7, and 3.7 kV/cm respectively. No cross talk was observed during reconstruction of the three images at the respective writing fields. Figure 2: Electric field multiplexing Results of the Diffraction Efficiency as Function of the - during electric field applied - the reconstruction. ~5. Finally it should be noted that EH was implemented in special KLTN crystals. The composition of these crystals was optimized for this purpose(5). Furthermore, special efficient fiigpoesewihdntrqielre fixng whch rocsse o nt temperature rquie changes lrg are being developed in these crystals(6). The two sets of experiments described above demonstrate the potential of EH as new type of spatial light modulation. In the EH SLM each element can generate a complete image rather than one pixel. The image is not hard-wired but can be preprogrammed by the user In addition if electric multiplexing is used, each element can generate one image out of a set of prestored user defined images.</p>
<p>Acknowledgments This research was supported by grant No. 92-00361 from the United States - Israel Binational Science Foundation (BSF), Jerusalem, Israel, and by a grant from the Ministry of Science of the State of Israel.</p></body>
<back>
<ref-list>
<ref id="r1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Agranat</surname><given-names>A.J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Leyva</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yariv</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Voltage Controlled Photorefractive Effect in Paraelectric KTa<sub>1-x</sub>Nb<sub>x</sub>O<sub>3</sub>: Cu, V</article-title>&#x0201D; <source>Opt Lett</source> <volume>14</volume>, <fpage>1017</fpage>, (<year>1989</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/OL.14.001017</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>De-Vre</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jeganathan</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wilde</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hesselink</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Effect of applied electric field on the writing and the readout of photorefractive gratings</article-title>&#x0201D; <source>J Opt Soc Am B</source> <volume>12</volume>, <issue>600</issue>, (<year>1995</year>)<fpage>3A</fpage></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Agranat</surname><given-names>A.J.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Electroholographic Artificial Neural Networks</article-title>.&#x0201D; <source>Physika A</source> <volume>200</volume>, <fpage>608</fpage>-<lpage>612</lpage>, (<year>1993</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/0378-4371(93)90566-M</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Balberg</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Razvag</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Vidro</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Refaelli</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Agranat</surname><given-names>A.J.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Experimental Demonstration of the Electroholographic Neurons Implemented on KLTN Crystals</article-title>&#x0201D; <source>Optics Letters</source> <volume>21</volume>(<issue>19</issue>) <fpage>1544</fpage>-<lpage>1546</lpage>, (<year>1996</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/OL.21.001544</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Hofmeister</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yagi</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yariv</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Agranat</surname><given-names>A.J.</given-names></name></person-group>, '<article-title>Growth and Characterization of KLTN:Cu, V Photorefractive Crystals</article-title>', <source>J Cryst Growth</source> <volume>131</volume>, <fpage>486</fpage>-<lpage>494</lpage>, (<year>1993</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/0022-0248(93)90201-7</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Agranat</surname><given-names>A.J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Razvag</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Balberg</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x02018;<article-title>Photorefractive hologram fixing by a 4K cooldown to the phase transition in KLTN</article-title>&#x02019;, <source>Appl Phys Lett</source>, <volume>68</volume>, <fpage>2469</fpage>-<lpage>2471</lpage>, (<year>1996</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.115823</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></book-part></book-part-wrapper>
