<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
<collection-meta collection-type="conf">
<conference content-type="conf-name"><conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name><conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym></conference>
<conference content-type="conf-other-meta"><conf-date content-type="start">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-date content-type="end">
<day>19</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-loc>Nevada, 
<country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc></conference></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
<title-group>
<title>SLM Materials and Sructures</title>
<alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/></title-group></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
<title-group>
<title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title></title-group>
<volume-in-collection>
<volume-number>14</volume-number>
<volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title></volume-in-collection></collection-meta>
<book-meta>
<book-title-group>
<book-title>Spatial Light Modulators</book-title></book-title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Burdge</surname><given-names>Geoffrey</given-names></name></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>Sadik C.</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group>
<pub-date publication-format="electronic">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></pub-date></book-meta>
<book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
<book-part-meta>
<title-group>
<title>Optical Response of Polymer Dispersed Liquid Crystals to the Frequency of the Applied Voltage</title></title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Vicari</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref><xref rid="cor1" ref-type="corresp"><sup>*</sup></xref></contrib>
<aff id="aff1">
<label>1</label>Istituto Nazionale per la Fisica della Materia, Universit&#x000E0; di Napoli &#x0201C;Federico II&#x0201D; Dip. Scienze Fisiche, Facolt&#x000E0; d'Ingegneria, p.le Tecchio 80.I,80125 Napoli, 
<country country="IT">Italy</country></aff></contrib-group>
<author-notes>
<corresp id="cor1">
<label>*</label>Fax+39812391821 EMAIL:<email>VICARI@NA.INFN.IT</email>; <ext-link xlink:href="http://LOA.dsfing.unina.it/" ext-link-type="uri">http://LOA.dsfing.unina.it/</ext-link></corresp></author-notes>
<elocation-id>155</elocation-id>
<permissions>
<copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
<copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
<copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
<license license-type="open-access">
<license-p>closed</license-p></license></permissions>
<abstract>
<p>We study the light transmittance of PDLCs a function of applied field shape and frequency. We present some experimental result and a mathematical model able to explain the device behaviour as a consequence of liquid crystal dielectric permittivity dependence on the applied voltage frequency.</p></abstract>
<kwd-group kwd-group-type="OCIS">
<title>OCIS codes</title>
<kwd>Optoelectronics</kwd>
<kwd>Liquid crystal devices</kwd></kwd-group>
<counts>
<book-page-count count="5"/></counts></book-part-meta>
<body>
<p>Introduction A Polymer Dispersed Liquid Crystal (PDLC) is a material made by the dispersion of liquid crystal microdroplets in a polymeric binder &#x0005B;1-2&#x0005D;. Droplet size is close to visible light wavelength. Since they behave as randomly oriented anisotropic spheres they produce strong light scattering so that the sample is opaque translucent &#x0005B;3-5&#x0005D;. Light scattering can be controlled by changing the droplet effective refractive index mismatch to the surrounding polymer. The simplest and more used way to accomplish this result is the application of an external, low frequency, electric field &#x0005B;6&#x0005D;. PDLC may be used for several purposes, from large scale flexible displays to windows with controlled transparency or thermal sensors. We have recently presented detailed experimental and theoretical studies of the behavior of a PDLC sample when a light beam impinges on it &#x0005B;7-10&#x0005D;. In this paper we devote some attention to the study of the influence of the dependence of the liquid crystal dielectric permittivity response to the frequency of the applied voltage on the electro-optical behavior of the PDLC, and in particular on its transmittance. To this aim we use a mathematical model assuming the liquid crystal dielectric permittivities s and a to be the most important parameters for the applied field frequency dependence of light transmittance. Theoretical results show a sudden decrease of the transmitted intensity increasing the frequency of the applied voltage. We present also preliminary experimental results confirming this behavior. The Model In the framework of the Pallfy-Muhoray theory &#x0005B;11&#x0005D; we describe the PDLC sample by means of three order parameters: the local order parameter S = (P, (n -), the droplet order parameter Sd 2= d /droplet' andthesampleorderparameter S, = P2 I\ Td )isample whereP-isthesecondorderLegendrepolynomial I is the molecular axis n is the nematic director Nd is the droplet director (i.e. the mean value of h . . d applied electric field and the &lt;&gt; parentheses denotes the spatial average. The local order parameter, i.e. the usual scalar order parameterS is assumed to be unaffected by droplet configuration and by the external electric field. For the temperature dependence, from the Maier and Saupe theory &#x0005B;12&#x0005D; we have: S (1- 0.980),2 where G is an universal function of the reduced temperature: 9 TVT,, V2 T is the temperature. V is the volume and T and aretheirvalues attheNeatic-Isotropic transition. account the liquid crystal orientation with respect to the droplet's symmetry axis, being Sd I when all the moleculesareparallelto andSd= 0fora d random distribution (isotropic droplet). It describes the droplet configuration and allows to compute the droplet ordinary and extraordinary refractive indices: 2 T 2 - t1 do o n 2'n 3 n- n 1 intensiry of a PDLC sample is on 1 7 de n e 2 - )Sd+ n where Io is the incident light intensity. 0 3 Where F()isthecompleteellipticintegralofthe first kind and ne extraordinary . no are the . and . and . ordinary liquid crystal refractive indices respectively. For the sake of simplicity, in this paper we assume a constant value for the droplet order parameter (Sd=0. 7); a more detailed study can be found in &#x0005B;8&#x0005D;. The sample order parameter Ss describes the droplet reorientation due to the external field, and is computed by the implicit relations: 1 3(e +1) 3(3e, +1(e. +1) e +1 S - + + In 4 16e2 32e' e -1 e, (S) = EK c, + 2e- vi - p)E Kd Cst (SS) = 6e +3 1(+2SSdSjc - where vic is the liquid crystal volume fraction in the sample, s, is the polymer dielectric permittivitve and s are the liquid crystal dielectric permittivities. Kd is an elastic constant per unit surface (units: Newton per square meter) taking into account the torque which, after the field is switched- off, produces relaxation of the droplets to their original orientation. The sample order parameter is a function of both the polymer and the liquid crystal dielectricpermittivities. For droplet radius approximately equal to the light wavelength, condition required to achieve high transmittance contrast. , the transmitted 1, = -In exp(- p.da,) Fresnel reflection coefficient for the air-glass and glass-polimer interfaces. pN the droplet number per unit volume, ds is the sample thickness, as the sample scattering cross section given by: Rd is the spherical droplet radius, k is the wave number of the incident light and np is the polymer refractive index.</p>
<p>Frequency Dependence We have used this model to study the response of the transmitted intensity to the variation of the parameters that are affected by the frequency of the applied voltage. The PDLC appears to be almost insensible to most of them. As an example in Fig.1 we show its dependence on the polymer dielectric permittivitya p . We see that transmitted intensity is constant in a range from one to twelve times the vacuum dielectric permittivity. The values we have assumed for the other parameters, here and everywhere in this paper when not differently stated, are: liquid crystal volume fraction in the sample vic=0.45, liquid crystal dielectric permittivities =1860. and s.=6so., elastic constant per unit surface Kd=30 (units: Newton per square meter), droplet radius Rd=0.5ptm , light wavelength 1=0.633&#x0005B;tm, condition required to achieve high transmittance contrast, sample thickness ds=204m polymer and glass refractive index np=nv=1.54 Temperature T=25.5 'C (room temperature), applied voltage V = 50 V, applied voltage frequency v = 1Khz. The only frequency dependent parameters that appear to have a strong influence on the sample transmittance is the dielectric anisotropy of the liquid crystal. In Fig.1 we show the dependence of I/Io on F - a_. Now the polymer dielectric permittivitv p. is set equal to three times the vacuum one. Therefore we assume the liquid crystal dielectric permittivities , and a. to be the most important parameters for the applied field frequency dependence of light transmittance. On the other side for our experiment we use the liquid crystal E7 by BDH and we do not know the behavior of its permittivity versus the frequency. Fig.1 To apply our model we have used at room temperature and at v= 1Khz the values F =180. and _.=6F0. thatwehavefoundinliterature&#x0005B;13&#x0005D;,but for the dependence on the frequency we used an expression able to simulate the behavior reported in &#x0005B;14&#x0005D; for liquid crystal K-24: =(v) = - 1) erfc&#x0005B; 2.4 (Log v - Log vo )- 1 (v) = 1)erfc&#x0005B;2.4(Logy- Log - 1 In Fig. 2 we show the behavior represented by these expressions. It can be seen to be very similar to the one reported in &#x0005B;14&#x0005D;.</p>
<p>Experiment The PDLC solution is included between glass slides coated with conducting transparent layers (ITO). Introduction of Mylar spacers 20ptm thick before pressing the sandwich determines sample thickness. The sample is cured for 16 hours in a 600 C oven. The average molecular weight of the polymeric molecules increases while the reaction proceeds liquid crystals droplets separate. Droplets diameter is determined by curing rate that, in our case, is low enough to have diameters comparable with visible light wavelength. sample is translucent. beam from a 5 mW He-Ne laser (Fig.3) impinges normally on the sample (S). Voltage is applied by a function generator (FG) and a voltage amplifier (VA). A photodiode (Di) is used to measure the transmitted intensity. A chopper (C) lock-in (LI) configuration is used to avoid noise and background signal. A reference beam is sent by a beam splitter (BS) to a second photodiode (D2) to check impinging beam stability. In Fig.4 we report the experimental transmitted intensity Vs the applied voltage for different shapes of the field that is centered on zero value and has a frequency of 1000Hz (circular, square and triangular symbols correspond to sinusoidal, square and triangular signals respectively). As we can see the transmitted intensity is not influenced by field shape but only by its square average value. Full line represent the results of the application of the described model. We see that the switching is not simulated in a very accurate here, for the sake of simplicity, droplet order parameters has been assumed to be constant. This problem has been discussed elsewhere&#x0005B;8&#x0005D;. Here we show this comparison only to demonstrate that the set of parameters value we have chosen to describe our sample is reasonable. Fig.5 Finally in Fig.5 we report experimental data of the transmitted intensity versus the field frequency for two values of the applied voltage (circles for 50V and crosses for 20V). Full lines are theoretical results of our model having as input the same set of parameters used for Fig.4 but with the dielectric permittivities dependence of Fig.2. These results seem to confirm the hypotheses that the sample transmittance depends almost exclusively on liquid crystal response. We hope to have more detailed and reliable information when experimental results about the liquid crystal dielectric permittivities dependence on the applied voltage frequency will be available.</p></body>
<back>
<ref-list>
<ref id="r1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Doane</surname><given-names>J.W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Vaz</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>B.G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zumer</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Field controlled light scattering from nematic microdroplets</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Appl Phys Lett</source> <volume>48</volume>, <fpage>269</fpage>, (<year>1986</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.96577</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Drzaic</surname><given-names>P.S.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Polymer dispersed nematic liquid crystals for large area displays and light valves</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>J Appl Phys</source> <volume>60</volume>, <fpage>2142</fpage>, (<year>1986</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.337167</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zumer</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Doane</surname><given-names>J.W.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Light scattering from a small nematic droplet</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Phys Rev A</source> <volume>34</volume>, <fpage>3373</fpage>, (<year>1986</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevA.34.3373</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zumer</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Light scattering from nematic droplets: Anomalous Diffraction Approach</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Phys Rev A</source> <volume>37</volume>, <fpage>4006</fpage>-<lpage>4015</lpage>, (<year>1988</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevA.37.4006</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Drzaic</surname><given-names>P.S.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Reorientation dynamics of polymer dispersed nematic liquid crystal films</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Liq Cryst</source> <volume>3</volume>, <fpage>1543</fpage>-<lpage>59</lpage>, (<year>1988</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/02678298808086694</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Jain</surname><given-names>S.C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Rout</surname><given-names>D.K.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Electro-optic response of polymer dispersed liquid-crystal films</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>J Appl Phys</source> <volume>70</volume>, <fpage>6988</fpage>, (<year>1991</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.349828</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r7"><label>7</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Bloisi</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ruocchio</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Terrecuso</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Vicari</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Angular dependence of light transmittance through a polymer-dispersed liquid crystal above threshold</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Opt Lett</source>, <volume>21</volume>, <fpage>95</fpage>-<lpage>97</lpage>, (<year>1996</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/OL.21.000095</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r8"><label>8</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Bloisi</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ruocchio</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Vicari</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Frequency dependence of light transmittance in a PDLC</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Mol Cryst Liq Cryst</source>, <volume>290</volume>, <fpage>21</fpage>-<lpage>29</lpage>, (<year>1996</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/10587259608031888</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r9"><label>9</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Bloisi</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ruocchio</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Vicari</surname><given-names>Terrecuso L.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>PDLC: influence of droplet order parameter in light trasmittance</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Opt Commun</source>, <volume>123</volume>, <fpage>449</fpage>-<lpage>452</lpage>, (<year>1996</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/0030-4018(95)00638-9</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r10"><label>10</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Bloisi</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ruocchio</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Terrecuso</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Vicari</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Angular dependence of light transmittance in Polymer Dispersed Liquid Crystals</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Phys Rev E</source> <volume>54</volume> <fpage>5242</fpage>-<lpage>5248</lpage>, (<year>1996</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevE.54.5242</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r11"><label>11</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kelly</surname><given-names>J.R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Pallfy-Muhoray</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>The optical response of polymer dispersed liquid crystals</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Mol Cryst Liq Cryst</source> <volume>243</volume>, <fpage>11</fpage>, (<year>1994</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/10587259408037759</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r12"><label>12</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>de Jeu</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>Physical properties of liquid crystalline materials</source> <publisher-name>Gordon  Breach Science Publishers</publisher-name>, <publisher-loc>New York</publisher-loc>, (<year>1979</year>)<volume>10</volume>, <fpage>11</fpage></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r13"><label>13</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhong</surname><given-names>D.E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Schuele</surname><given-names>W.L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Gordon</surname><given-names>K.J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Adamic</surname></name><name><surname>Akins</surname><given-names>R. B.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Dielectric Properties of a PMMA/E7 Polymer-Dispersed Liquid Crystal</article-title>&#x0201D;, <source>J Polym Sci B</source> <volume>30</volume>, <fpage>1443</fpage>-<lpage>1449</lpage>, (<year>1992</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/polb.1992.090301303</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r14"><label>14</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Rout</surname><given-names>D.K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jain</surname><given-names>S.C.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Dielectric properties of a polymer dispersed liquid crystal film</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Mol Cryst Liq Cryst</source> <volume>210</volume>, <fpage>75</fpage>, (<year>1992</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/10587259208030758</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></book-part></book-part-wrapper>
