<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
<collection-meta collection-type="conf">
<conference content-type="conf-name"><conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name><conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym></conference>
<conference content-type="conf-other-meta"><conf-date content-type="start">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-date content-type="end">
<day>19</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-loc>Nevada, 
<country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc></conference></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
<title-group>
<title>VLSI-based SLMs</title>
<alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/></title-group></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
<title-group>
<title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title></title-group>
<volume-in-collection>
<volume-number>14</volume-number>
<volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title></volume-in-collection></collection-meta>
<book-meta>
<book-title-group>
<book-title>Spatial Light Modulators</book-title></book-title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Burdge</surname><given-names>Geoffrey</given-names></name></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>Sadik C.</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group>
<pub-date publication-format="electronic">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></pub-date></book-meta>
<book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
<book-part-meta>
<title-group>
<title>Demonstration of a CMOS Static RAM Chip with High-Speed Optical Read and Write</title></title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Krishnamoorthy</surname><given-names>A. V.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Rozier</surname><given-names>R. G.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff"><sup>*</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Ford</surname><given-names>J. E.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Kiamilev</surname><given-names>F. E.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff"><sup>*</sup></xref></contrib>
<aff id="aff1">
<label>1</label>Bell Laboratories, Lucent Technologies, Holmdel, NJ 07733</aff>
<aff id="aff2">
<label>*</label>UNCC, Charlotte NC 28223</aff></contrib-group>
<elocation-id>23</elocation-id>
<permissions>
<copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
<copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
<copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
<license license-type="open-access">
<license-p>closed</license-p></license></permissions>
<abstract>
<p>We demonstrate a dense VLSI RAM technology with high-speed optical read and optical write capability. The CMOS-based Static-RAM technology is capable of parallel optical access with read/write speeds limited by the native RAM access times. We have fabricated a 2mm &#x000D7; 2mm optoelectronic-VLSI test chip incorporating 800b storage and 200 optical I/O based on the hybrid integration of GaAs/AlGaAs MQW modulators onto CMOS. Results from the test chip confirm 6.2ns read and 8ns write capbilty.</p></abstract>
<kwd-group kwd-group-type="OCIS">
<title>OCIS codes</title>
<kwd>optical interconnects</kwd>
<kwd>smart pixels</kwd>
<kwd>memories</kwd></kwd-group>
<counts>
<book-page-count count="4"/></counts></book-part-meta>
<body>
<p>In the last three decades, random access memory (RAM) densities have progressed at an incredible rate, from the early I Kilobit chips to the 1 Gigabit DRAMs that have recently been producedI 1&#x0005D;. Similar progress has been made in the development of micro-processors, with 64-bit RISC processors now operating at 450MHz, and GHz processors on the horizon &#x0005B;2&#x0005D;. Data transfer rates from high-density memories to processors have not, however, followed this growth curve, producing an increasing gap between memory and processor bandwidths. This has created an opportunity for new techniques for high-speed data transfer from main memory. In this paper, we investigate the potential for parallel optical data transfer to and from silicon VLSI Such optoelectronic memory devices are likely to be useful for a variety of applications. Special purpose hardware for direct processor-to-memory optical interconnection are under investigation by several research groups &#x0005B;3&#x0005D;. Recent udeforsatnvelgatongbhigh-calrac ou eeant free-space optical memory-access systeis have also created a need for high-speed, optoelectronic buffer-memory interface circuits. Such free-space digital optoelectronic systems promise the ability for direct processing and data- reduction on the contents of high-capacity optical memories. The availability of parallel optical access to high-speed RAM will also permit the development of an efficient, nenor-based optoelectronic-switch: a goal that cannot be achieved with conventional space-division photonic switching technologies. Optoelectronictechnologiesthatcanprovidefast such . VLSI chips now exist. One tehooysaednhhbiitertoo.~ access to Silicon optical integration of GaAs Multiple Quantum Well (MQW) photodetectors and light- modulators onto a pre-fabricated silicon integrated circuit using flip-chip bonding technique followed by substrate removal of the GaAs chip to allow surface-normal operation of the optical modulators at 850nm &#x0005B;4&#x0005D;. Previous work based on this hybrid technology has demonstrated that optoelectronic page-buffer circuits based on FIFO buffers &#x0005B;5&#x0005D; or shift-register pixels &#x0005B;6&#x0005D; can be achieved. Here, we present, for the first time, a dense CMOS VLSI RAM with high-speed optical read and optical write capability. Specifically, we demonstrate an optically-accessed SRAM technology with 6.2ns read and 8ns write capability. The Photonic SRAM test chip (Fig. 1) is an optically and electrically accessible SRAM with 96 parallel optical inputs and 96 optical outputs. Data is stored in 8 separate addresses(words)with96bitsperword,providinga of approximately 800 bits. The eight least significant bits of each word of the RAM are electrically accessible fromanon-chipshiftregister.Eightbitsofdata can be loaded . into the shift register from off-chip and then stored in the RAM. Similarly, the first eight bits of the RAM can be transferred in parallel into the shift register and then shifted out serially. All 96 bits of each address can be written to, or read out, optically. Multiplexers select whether data is read/written electrically or optically. All data address lines (3 in this case) to the chip were electrical. These features permit electrical, optical, and electrical/optical mixed-signal testing of the RAM chip. The dimensions, of the Photonic RAM test chip were approximately 2mm x 2mm. The chip contained approximately 11,000 transistors. Figure 1: Microphotograph of the 0.8pm. CMOS/MQW- modulator, Static-RAM integrated-circuit, showing a portion of the 10 x 20 array of diodes after bonding and substrate removal &#x0005B;II&#x0005D;. MQW modulators are 20pm x 50pm with 62.5pm / 125pm separations. ASEM photograph of the chip surface before bonding is shown in Figure 2. The MQW diodes were integrated directly over the circuits in this design &#x0005B;5&#x0005D;. The top-level metal (Metal-3) was reserved for bond-pads and wiring to the diodes. Static-RAM cells were laid out beneath the bond-pads and wired with two levels of metal interconnect. Measured bit-cell sizes for the Photonic SRAM fabricated in a 0.8um technology was approximately 1271m 2 . The cell efficiency was 55&#x00025; due to the conservative layout applied to the metal bit-lines and supply lines. Scaling the design to a 0.5pm technology would provide a cell size of approximately 46&#x0005D;.m 2 and an aerial density of 1.2 Megabit/cm2 . Figure 3 contrasts the aerial density of various electronic memory technologies, including embedded (synthesized) SRAM, optimized SRAM, Flash memory, and DRAM produced in standard logic (ASIC) as well as optimized technologies &#x0005B;7,8&#x0005D;. The use of DRAM circuits instead of SRAMs, even in logic (non-optimized) technologies can provide substantial increase in aerial density. Flash memory can provide further increases in aerial density, at the expense of slower writing times. Figure 2: SEM of silicon CMOS integrated circuit prior to bonding, showing 20pm x 20pm flip-chip-bond pads (Metal-3) with underlying SRAM cells. Each memory cell occupies 10pm x 13pm in a 0.8pm technology' Figure 3: Cell-sizes and densities of optimized SRAM, DRAM. ASIC-DRAM and Flash memory technologies for typical 0.5pm implementations &#x0005B;7,8&#x0005D;. Projected photonic SRAM density based on the fabricated cell for the 0.8pm and a potential 0.5pmn implementation are shown for comparison. The memory array in the Photonic SRAM test chip is a two-dimensional grid of memory cells, each storing 1 bit. Each memory cell is a 6 transistor circuit that consists of two cross-coupled inverters and two pass transistors (Fig. 4). Although electronic SRAM ICs typically use only a small number of external I/O channels, internally, the SRAM can be a highly parallel device capable of supporting large word sizes. Read/write circuitry is repeated once per bit column. The write circuit consists of write select multiplexers for data input lines. The read select circuitry consists of bit line pull-ups to precharge the bit lines to VDD, write select multiplexers for data output lines, and a sense amplifier. The data-input and data-output circuitry is repeated once per bit column. This circuitry consists of a bit line drive for write operations and an output sense amp that supplies a second stage of amplifications. Receiver circuits and transmitter circuits accounted for the remaining area of the chip. These transceiver circuits have previously been implemented &#x0005B;9&#x0005D;. Figure 4. CMOS Memory cell circuit for static RAM uses 6 transistors and occupies 25 x 20. Writing to the RAM is performed in three steps. First the address bus is set to the memory address that is being written to. At the same time, the input-data bus is loaded with the data to be written. Second, the write signal (WR). which normally stays high. is pulled low and held there for aspecified time period (twc). When the WR signal goes high, the data on the DIN bus is written to memory. As is typical for edge-triggered storage circuits, the input-data bus must remain unchanged for a specified amount of time before (setup time) and after (hold time) the rising edge of the WR sienal. Reading from the RAM is accomplished in two steps. First, the address bus is set to the memory address that is being read from. Second, after a certain amount of time (trc), the contents of that memory location appear on the data-output bus. The photonic SRAM chip was tested for data storage and retrieval. Substantial electrical and optical read/write testing was performed for the photonic SRAM to verify correct operation. Once data was written to the photonic SRAM, the read cycle involved changing the three electrical address lines, and waiting for the appropriate data to appear on the output modulators. The minimum time required for data to be valid after the address lines had settled can be defined as trc (Fig. 5a). This was determined by continuing to increase the frequency with which the electrical address lines were cycled until invalid data was read out on the optical modulators. As shown in Fiure 5b, trc was determined to be 6.2ns. This corresponds to a total read-bandwidth of 15 Gigabits/s from the test chip. Figure 5. Read/write speed measurements of the photonic SRANI integrated circuit: (a) schematic waveform showing definition of minimum read cycle time trc: (b) measured output optical waveform from photonic SRAM at 160Mbit/s with trc = 6.2nsec: (c) schematic waveform showing definition of minimum write cycle time twc: (c) measured pulse width of twc=8ns applied to electrical WR line results in correct write operations to memory. High speed writing to the photonic SRAM was. similarly performed both electrically and optically to a particular address. The minimum write cycle was determined by shifting a desired 8-bit data pattern into the shift register and then electrically pulsing the WR line with a short pulse. The stored data was then loaded back into the shift register, shifted out of the chip, and compared to the original data. If the data was valid, the minimum pulse width was then reduced. For optical tests, the data was placed on the appropriate detectors before the WR line was pulsed. Data was then read out on the appropriate modulators and verified. Figure 5c shows a schematic waveform defining the minimum write cycle time twc. Figure 5d presents the measured minimum pulse width (twc) of 8ns applied to electrical WR line that result in correct write operations to memory. This corresponds to a total write-bandwidth of 12 Gigabit/s. Static and dynamic power dissipation was measured during operation. The chip was mounted in a standard 84 pin grid array package. The tiny chip consumed approximately 650mW of static power dissipation due to the transimpedance receivers and the sense-amplifier read circuits. Dynamic power dissipation was measured at I10mW at 25MHz operation up to 300mW at the maximum readout operation speed of 160MHz. The maximum total chip dissipation was measured at 950mW at an operating voltage of 5V. In summary, we demonstrate, for the first time, a CMOS Static-RAM technology capable of high-speed parallel optical access. The tiny 2mm x 2mm test chip incorporated 96 optical inputs and outputs, 800b storage, and several electrical and optical control and test features. Storage cell size was approximately 10pm x 20gm in a 0.8pm process. This is smaller than typical SRAM cells, but significantly larger than custom SRAM, DRAM. or Flash technologies. Minimum read-cycle and write-cycle times were measured at 6.2ns and 8ns respectively. This corresponds to aggregate optical read and write bandwidths of 15 Gigabit/s and 12 Gigabit/s, respectively.</p></body>
<back>
<ref-list>
<ref id="r1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yoo</surname><given-names>J.-H</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>, <source>Proc ISSCC</source>, <fpage>378</fpage>, <month>February</month> <year>1996</year></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Roadmap</surname><given-names>S.I.A.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>Industry Association Semiconductor</source> <publisher-loc>Jose San CA</publisher-loc>, , (<year>1994</year>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="confproc">see for example: <person-group person-group-type="editor"><name><surname>Rozier</surname><given-names>R. G.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>, <source>Proc. MPPOI-&#x02019;96</source>, <conf-loc>Maui</conf-loc>, <fpage>36</fpage>, <conf-date>October 1996</conf-date></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Goossen</surname><given-names>K.W.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>, <source>IEEE PTL</source> <volume>7</volume>, <fpage>360</fpage>, <month>April</month> <year>1995</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1109/68.376802</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Krishnamoorthy</surname><given-names>A.V.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>, <source>Applied Optics</source> <volume>35</volume>, <fpage>2439</fpage> <month>May</month> <year>1996</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/AO.35.002439</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Chau</surname><given-names>K.K.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>, <source>Proc. LEOS Summer Top. Meet. Smart Pixels</source>, -<fpage>28</fpage>, <month>August</month> <year>1996</year></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r7"><label>7</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Foss</surname><given-names>R. C.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>Proc ISSCC</source>, <fpage>260</fpage>, <month>February</month> <year>1996</year></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r8"><label>8</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Miwa</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>, <source>Proc ISSCC</source>, <fpage>34</fpage>, <month>February</month> <year>1996</year></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r9"><label>9</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Krishnamoorthy</surname><given-names>A.V.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>, <source>Photonics Tech Lett</source> <volume>7</volume>, <fpage>1277</fpage> <month>November</month> <year>1995</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1109/68.473474</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r10"><label>10</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kiamilev</surname><given-names>F.E.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>, <source>Proc. LEOS Summer Top. Meet. Smart Pixels</source>, <publisher-loc>Keystone</publisher-loc>, <fpage>38</fpage>, <month>August</month> <year>1996</year></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r11"><label>11</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Circuits were fabricated through the Bell-Labs/GMU Co-Op for CMOS/SEED devices</article-title>.</mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></book-part></book-part-wrapper>
