<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
<collection-meta collection-type="conf">
<conference content-type="conf-name"><conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name><conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym></conference>
<conference content-type="conf-other-meta"><conf-date content-type="start">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-date content-type="end">
<day>19</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-loc>Nevada, 
<country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc></conference></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
<title-group>
<title>Reprint</title>
<alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/></title-group></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
<title-group>
<title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title></title-group>
<volume-in-collection>
<volume-number>14</volume-number>
<volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title></volume-in-collection></collection-meta>
<book-meta>
<book-title-group>
<book-title>Spatial Light Modulators</book-title></book-title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Burdge</surname><given-names>Geoffrey</given-names></name></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>Sadik C.</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group>
<pub-date publication-format="electronic">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></pub-date></book-meta>
<book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
<book-part-meta>
<title-group>
<title>Spatial Light Modulators: Processing Light in Real Time</title></title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Barbier</surname><given-names>Pierre R.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Moddel</surname><given-names>Garret</given-names></name><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff"><sup>2</sup></xref></contrib>
<aff id="aff1">
<label>1</label>Garret Moddel is a professor in the Electrical &amp; Computer Engineering Department and Optoelectronic Computer System Center at the University of Colorado, Boulder, Colo.</aff>
<aff id="aff2">
<label>2</label>Pierre R. Barbler is assistant research scientist in the Laboratory for Physical Sciences and Electrical Engineering Department, University of Maryland, College Park, Md.</aff></contrib-group>
<elocation-id>2</elocation-id>
<permissions>
<copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
<copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
<copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
<license license-type="open-access">
<license-p>closed</license-p></license></permissions>
<abstract>
<p>Spatial light modulator (SLNI) is the in scrutable name for a device that is making its quiet, vet steady entrance into our daily lives. Also called light valves, SLMs are essentially time-varying masks. An example of their function can be seen in an optical crossbar switch. It can be visualized as a bar consisting of a linear array of light emitters, and another bar consisting of a linear array of light detectors crossed with respect to the first one and at some small distance from it. Each emitter illuminates all of the detectors. As described, the crossbar switch does not appear interesting. If we now insert a mask between the emitter array and the detector array, only those parts of the mask that are transmissive will provide a connection between specific emitters and selected detectors. The mask is an SLNI. The selected interconnects that have been formed may be reconfigured by changing the pattern on the SLM.</p></abstract>
<counts>
<book-page-count count="5"/></counts></book-part-meta>
<body>
<p>Spatial light modulator (SLNI) is the in scrutable name for a device that is making its quiet, vet steady entrance into our daily lives. Also called light valves, SLMs are essentially time-varying masks. An example of their function can be seen in an optical crossbar switch. It can be visualized as a bar consisting of a linear array of light emitters, and another bar consisting of a linear array of light detectors crossed with respect to the first one and at some small distance from it. Each emitter illuminates all of the detectors. As described, the crossbar switch does not appear interesting. If we now insert a mask between the emitter array and the detector array, only those parts of the mask that are transmissive will provide a connection between specific emitters and selected detectors. The mask is an SLNI. The selected interconnects that have been formed may be reconfigured by changing the pattern on the SLM.</p>
<p>SLIs include a large range of devices whose primary function is to spatially modulate a readout beam. The image can be input either electrically or optically. Electrically addressed spatial light modulators (EASLs) can be distinguished from optically addressed spatial light modulators (OASLNls). Liquid crystal displays (LCDs) are a type of EASLM, and photo- graphic film and low-light image intensifiers are types of OASLNIs (see Fig. 1). The dividing line between dis- play technology and SLM technol- ogy is vague. Generally SLM devices provide higher frame rates or resolution than display devices. In many applications, SLMs must exhibit other properties, such as phase flatness and small size (to be compatible with available optics), which are not required of displays. In this article, we include high performance LCDs as SLM s. Because so many different types of SLM~S have been developed over the years, we must limit our discus- sion to some new SLIM tech nologies that have the potential to provide superior perfor mance over video displays, and torecently developed and new potential SLM applications. Although linear arrays may use the same SLM technology, we will imit this discussion to Improvements in spatial light modulators (SLVIs) , are expanding their applications. Barbier and de scribe SLMs work and provide insight into the latest SLM applications of SLs that are starting to affect our everyday and virtual reality, head-mounted displays. Even though these applications were originally developed around the traditional cathodic ray tube (CRIT), recent break throughs in SLM technology have increased their per- formance dramatically. CRT-based video projectors were limited by the brightness of the image formed onto their phosphors and projected onto the screen, restricting the use of these devices to dimly lit rooms. In contrast, in an SLM-based video projector, the image is formed by the SLMs and read out by a high-powNer lamp or by laser beams before being projected onto a screen. Consequently, much Figure 1. Electrically addressed spatial light modulators (left): individual pixels are addressed electrically. Optically addressed spatial light modulator (right): an input image is sent onto the device, which forms a replica in the modu lating medium. Both devices are read out with an external tight beam, which is modulated and reflected by (as shown here) or transmitted through the device. Note that OASLMs may also be pixelated. the input image is absorbed in the photosensor. The photogenerated charges cause the liquid crys- tal molecules to rotate, which in turn affects the polarization-in this example-of the polarized readout light. This polarization replica of the input image is transformed into an intensity replica by filtering through a polarizing beam splitter.3 brighter and larger images can be projected, and are lim- ited mainly by the intensity of the light source. With cur- rent video projectors, images that have a diagonal dimension of a few meters are perfectly visible in a nor- mally illuminated room. Applications of these systems in entertainment include network or traffic-control moni- toring rooms. These systems are manufactured by several companies inciuding Ampro Greyhawk Division, Hughes-JVC, In Focus, Sharp, and Texas Instruments. Head-mounted displays used to be bulky because of the electronics and the high voltages required to control the small CRTs. New liquid crystal SLMs, which are much smaller and require only a few volts, have reduced these constraints considerably, yielding light-weight head- mounted displays that produce a striking stereoscopic effect. Along with applications in 3-D video games, these devices can be used in virtual reality applications. Such devices are manufactured by Kaiser Electro-Optics, Virtual Research Systems, Liquid Image, and so on.</p>
<p>Addressing The light-modulating medium modifies the readout light using an electro-optic effect. The most practical and common approach to make an FASLM is to apply matrix-addressing electrodes to a substrate. The pixels are formed at the intersection of the electrodes, which modulate the voltage dropped across the sandwiched light-modulating medium. To make it possible to address a large number of rows sequentially, a transistor at each pixel transfers and stores the electrical information for that pixel. Therefore, the addressing of the device can be carried out rapidly while the reading can be done more slowly in the remaining frame period. For example, EASLMs used in head-mounted displays incorporate an integrated circuit (IC) silicon substrate addressing matrix, and a liquid crystal light-modulating medium. The pixel size in these ~~ active backplane SLls is limited - ~ to that which can be formed by very large- scale integration (VLSI) IC fabrication. For some coher ent optical processing applications, the current state of the art is not sufficiently small. Technical challenges include increasing the maximum number of pixels, frame rate, fill factor (fraction of an area that is optically usable), number of distinct gray levels, and contrast ratio. In optically addressed active backplane devices, a photodiode, which replaces the control electrode matrix, can be incorporated into each pixel. The optical write-image is directly sensed by the photodiodes and the image is transferred to the modulating layer. Some smarts&#x0201D; can be built into this OASLM in the electronic circuit between the photodiodes and image processing functions such as edge detection or human retina simulation. This forms of smart pixel SLM. Often such optical image processing is not necessary, and the substrate can be coated with a uniform film of photosensing material that absorbs the write-image photons and converts them to electron-hole pairs. These carriers locally alter the electric field across the electro-optic material modu lating the readout light. The light modulating medium may be adjacent to the photosensor film forming a hybrid OASLN. This is the case in liquid crystal-amor phous silicon OASLMs, represented in Figure 2.3 Alternatively, a single material can act as both photosen- sor and light-modulating medium, forming monolithic OASLMs. This is the case in multiple-quantum-well (NIQW) self-electro-optic devices (SEEDs) where the effect is two-dimensional, and photorefractive crystals OASLMs that form volume holograms. The resolution of OASLMs can be quite high, above 100 linepairs/mm, limited only by the physical properties of the photosens ing and modulating layers. In addition to spatial resolu- porating a ferroelectric liquid crystal. The 256 256 array of pixels can be driven at frame rates of up to 3 kHz. response time, contrast ratio, write-light sensitivity, and linearity. (SLM resolution is usually quoted in linepairs per millimeter (lp/mm) and display resolution in lines per millimeter. Therefore, the resolution in linepairs per millimeter of a display used as an SLNI is twice that of its.resolutionexpressedinlinespermillimeter</p>
<p>Devices As shown in Figure 1, the output pattern of an SLl is imposed onto the readout light, which may be a coher ent laser beam or an incoherent filtered or unfiltered white light. SLMs may reflect or transmit the readout light,andmodulateitsintensity,phase,polarization,o angledependingonthe lightmodulatingmedium.We discuss four types of SLNI light modulation approaches: liquid .rsa,'ED .i ~ ~ The spatial frequency expressed in liquidcrystal,SEED,digital micromirror device (DNID), and photorefractive crystal. Note that other devices not discussed in this article have been developed, such as the charge-transfer-plate membrane-mirror OASLIM, the magneto-optic OASLM, and the Si/PLZT OASLM. How they work The application of an electric field across a liquid crystal (LC) film causes the molecules to rotate. The refractive index along the optic axis parallel to the long axis of the liquid crystal is significantly different from the index along a perpendicular short axis. This difference, th birefringence, is quite substantial for liquid crystal miol-ecules, typically about 0.2. By an appropriate choice of the twist of the liquid crystal axis or the thickness of the material, and of the polarization of the readout light, the polarization of the light may be rotated or its phase modulated. Polarization rotation can be converted to intensity modulation by filtering through a polarizer, as is done in most laptop computer screens or in LC SLM-based video projectors (see Fig. 2). Phase modulation can be used for adaptive optics applications or to create thin-film holograms for optical image processing appi cations. Two main types of liquid crystal naterials h,1, been used in SLMs: I Nematic liquid crystals (NLCs) provide ana response, but are limited by the natural relaxation of the material, to a response time of approximately 10 msec. S a t i r es 1&#x0201D; Surface-stabihized ferroelectric liquid crystals (SSFLCs) switch much faster (10 psec), but are inher-entlv binary in their response. Both types of material have been incorporated into EASLs, using IC backplanes to provide the drive cir- cuitry (see Fig. 3), and OASLNIs, using thin film photo- sensors such as hydrogenated amorphous silicon,' poly- crystalline silicon thin film transistors (TFTs), or crys- talline silicon photodiode arrays. LC SLMs were pio- neered by Hughes and are now manufactured by several companies, including Hughes-JVC, CRL, Displaytech (see Fig. 3), and Hammamatsu. Amplitude modulation may be achieved in a SEED through the modulation of the excitonic absorption edge by an electric field (quantum-confined Stark effect) applied across a multiple quantum well (NIQW) structure. )OASLIM have been formed by depositing A spatial light modulator in which a silicon integrated cir- cuit addresses each pixel individually (predominantly implemented with liquid crystal technology). The on-to-off ratio of the output light intensity (ideally infinity). The curve corresponding to the contrast ratio versus the spatial frequency of a periodic one-dimensional pattern expressed in linepairs per millimeter (Ip/mm). The minimum addressable area as defined by patterning. A spatial light modulator in which a silicon VLSI circuit per forms an image processing operation and addresses each pixel. (Ip/mm) at which the MTF reaches 50&#x00025; or 10&#x00025;, depending on the definition. The inverse of the spatial resolution is equivalent to pixel dimension for an unpat- terned OASLM. The spatial resolution is simply the inverse of the pixel dimension divided by two for a patterned SLM. Transistor fabricated in thin semiconductor films, such as hydrogenated amorphous silicon, to drive the pixels of an active matrix liquid crystal display. ias ectronjcorir.e e ectroncs controls tie vertica position of the micrornirror with an electrostatic field. The silicon micromirror array is micrornachined on cantilevers. Using a separate rnicrolenslet array, light is focused onto each micrornirror to modu late the phase. photodiode films on top of the IQWs and by making them semi-insulating. A modified version of this tech nology is the bonding of a GaAs/AlGaAs MQW chip with photodetectors and modulators onto a VLSI silicon chip to improve switching performance.h Because they switch rapidly (on the order of 1 GHz), NIQW SLMs are used predominantly in photonic switching such as in the crossbar switch described earlier. DNIDs Lare fabricated by -icromachining a silicon wafer. Tiny (16 pin X 16 pm) suspended mirrors are micromachined on cantilevers. The mirrors are rotated by an electrostatic field to one of two stable positions. The reflection angle modulation is converted into an intensity modulation after spatial filtering through an aperture. DMDs, with 400 X 600 pixels) can be fabricat ed with their addressing circuitry into a single chip. Their response time is short (0.3 msec), but they are inherently digital, and require multiplexing to achieve grey levels. Texas Instruments has fabricated and incor- porated DMDs into commercial TV projection systems. SY Technology is developing a new generation of micromirrors that can modulate the phase only and could be used in adaptive optics applications (see Fig. 4). Photorefractive crystals use an effect that results from a local modulation of the index of refraction of the crystal after illumination with a write light.' The photorefractive effect can be used for phase conjugation, which is described in the following section. This effect is usually relatively slow (10-100 msec) and requires a single wavelength. To this category belongs the Pockels Readout Optical Modulator (PROM), which uses the longitudinal electro-optic effect and is com- monly made from a Bi ,SiO, (BSO) crystal, and the Russian PRIZ (a Russian acronym for &#x0201C;image trans- former&#x0201D;), which uses the transverse electro-optic effect.</p>
<p>Applications and trends Video projection The most apparent applications of SLMs have been in displays. Liquid crystal EASLMs and OASLMs, as well as DMDs, are at the heart of new video projectors. They are used to modulate a bright white light for projection of video or computer images onto a screen. The picture is sent electronically to the EASLMs, or to CRTs that are imaged onto the photosensor of the OASLMs, which then modulate the readout light. Red, green, and blue images must be generated and combined to reconstitute color images. \'ideo projectors are presently limited by the brightness of the readout source and the insertion loss of the light modulating scheme. Refinements may improve this projection efficiency and larger pixel num- bers should be soon possible to accommodate high defi- nition television.</p>
<p>Image processing Correlators aid machine vision and pattern recognition. Specific optical image processing operations necessary in machine-vision applications include image correla tion using LC or fast NIQW OASIMs at the Fourier plane as an intensity sensor. Image correlation consists of image recognition using Fourier transform process ing. This can be achieved in real time by using an OASLM-based image correlator, which may be much asterthanprocessingtheimages numerically on a desk- top computer. Image correlators can be used for pattern recognition such as for finger print identification. With the development of smart pixel OASLMs other specific machine vision applications may be expected.</p>
<p>Image conversion Optical computing applications also take advantage of SLMs when an incoherent scene needs to be converted in real time to a coherent monochromatic image. This is done using LC OASLNIs, or MQW OASLMs. Other appli- cations include wavelength conversion where a visible scene is converted into an infrared image for simulation purposes, and conversely, for image amplification.</p>
<p>Interconnects EASLMs may be applied to optical interconnects where it is necessary to rapidly interconnect a matrix of differ ent processors to one another. This can be done by using a crossbar switch described in the introduction incorpo rating a fast MQW SLM. The SLM acts as a switch matrix that rapidly controls the interconnection between the outputs and inputs of all the processors.&#x0201D;</p>
<p>Phase conjugation Phase conjugation can be accomplished using OASLMs, such as photorefractive crystals and liquid crystal/amor phous silicon devices. In phase conjugation, the exact com plex conjugate of a laser beam is redirected precisely along the incoming path. A plane wavefront that passes through a distorting medium will return as an unaberrated plane wave after reflection from the phase conjugate mirror and propagation through the same medium. Applications for this include imaging or laser beam propagation through a turbulent medium such as the atmosphere. 0</p>
<p>Optical compensation Photorefractives have found applications as optical compensators where there is a need to clean up a laser beam that is distorted by a mechanism whose character istic time is slower than the photorefractive effect. The Hughes Compensated Laser Ultrasonic Evaluation (CLUE) system employs a BaTiO3 (barium titanate) crystal double-phase conjugate mirror to clean up the spatial information of a laser beam reflected and dis torted from the rough surface of a metal part.&#x0201D; The metal part is excited by ultrasound vibrations and mod ulates the phase of the reflected laser beam. The double- phase conjugate mirror transfers the energy of the dis torted reflected beam to a clean reference beam. The ultrasonic response of the part is recovered by hetero- dyne detection of the cleaned beam and recorded. After raster-scanning a welded metal part, an image of the quality of the weld joint can be obtained in the industri al environment.</p>
<p>Adaptive optics Phase-modulation EASLMs can be used in adaptive optics to compensate for phase distortions of an arriv ing light wavefront after propagation through a distort ing medium.' &#x0201C; This can be used for imaging through the atmosphere in astronomical or terrestrial applica tions or to precompensate a laser beam before sending it through the atmosphere and achieve diffraction-limited performance, i.e., the smallest possible spot size.</p>
<p>Turbulence simulation Finally, an unusual application of SLMs that was devel oped at the Army Research Lab is in an atmospheric turbulence simulator.&#x0201D; This system uses EASLMs and OASLMs in a close-loop configuration. By adjusting the characteristics of the input phase screen generated by the EASLM, the system can be set to a chaotic behavior with characteristics similar to atmospheric turbulence.</p>
<p>Future developments In addition to previously mentioned applications, the next few years will see other emerging applications made feasible by the appearance of new material sys- Inprtiulr~frsmepotoefactvepp tems. In particular, for some photorefractive applica tions, photopolymers will be more practical than pho- torefractive crystals, and biological material, in particu- lar bacteriorhodopsin, may also be used to form practi- cal OASLMs. The commercially driven applications that are more likely to make an immediate entrance are machine vision applications, optical correlators for pattern recog- nitioninmachinevisionandsecurityapplications,and nitin isio inmacine an secrityappicatonsand the use of SLMs as page formatters in holographic stor- age. With improvements in OASLMs, there may be wider application of SLMs in adaptive optics and in optical crossbar switches. Finally, like other technolo- gies, SLM technology might exceed our current expectations with regard to potential applications.</p></body>
<back>
<ref-list>
<ref id="r1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="editor"><name><surname>Efron</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></name></person-group> ed, <source>Spatial Light Modulator Technology: Material, Devices, and Applications</source> (<publisher-name>Marcel Dekker Press</publisher-name>, <publisher-loc>New York, N.Y</publisher-loc>., <year>1995</year>).</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kopp</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Video Projectors: portable wall screen</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Opt.  Phot. News</source> <volume>7</volume> (<issue>11</issue>) <year>1996</year>.</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">See Ch 6 in Ref. 1; <person-group person-group-type="editor"><name><surname>Barbier</surname><given-names>P. R.</given-names></name><etal>et al</etal></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Thin-film photosensor design for liquid crystal spatial light modulators</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Opt. Eng</source>. <volume>33</volume> (<issue>4</issue>), <fpage>1322</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1329</lpage>, (<year>1994</year>).<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1117/12.166935</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Beard</surname><given-names>T.D.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Ac liquid crystal light valve</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Appl Phys Lett</source>, <volume>22</volume> <fpage>90</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>94</lpage>, (<year>1973</year>).<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.1654574</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><source>Ch.5in Ref. 1</source>.</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="confproc">See <person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Lentine</surname><given-names>A.L.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>High throughput optoelectronic VLSI witching chips</article-title>,&#x0201D; to be presented at the <conf-name>OSA Topical Meeting on Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name>, <conf-loc>Lake Tahoe, Nev</conf-loc>., <year>1997</year>.</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r7"><label>7</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Sampeell</surname><given-names>J.B.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>An overview of Texas Instruments digital micromirror device (DM) and its application to projection displays</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Soc. for Information Display, Int. Symp. Digest of Technical Papers</source> <volume>24</volume>, <fpage>1012</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1015</lpage>, (<year>1993</year>).</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r8"><label>8</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Pepper</surname><given-names>D.M.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>The photorefractive effect</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Sci Am</source> <volume>263</volume>(<issue>4</issue>), <fpage>62</fpage> (<year>1990</year>).<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/scientificamerican1090-62</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r9"><label>9</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Love</surname><given-names>G.B.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Adaptive wavefront shaping with liquid crystal</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Opt.  Phot. News</source> <volume>6</volume>(<issue>10</issue>) <fpage>16</fpage>, (<year>1995</year>).<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/OPN.6.10.000016</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r10"><label>10</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><source>See Ch 14 in Ref. 1</source>.</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r11"><label>11</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ing</surname><given-names>R.K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Monchalin</surname><given-names>J.-P</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Broadband optical detection of ultrasound by two-wave mixing</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Appl Phys Lett</source>, <volume>59</volume>, <fpage>3233</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>3235</lpage>, (<year>1991</year>).<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.105742</pub-id></mixed-citation><mixed-citation publication-type="confproc"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Pepper</surname><given-names>D. M.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Materials inspection and process control using compensated laser ultrasound evaluation (CLUE): Demonstration of a low-cost ultrasonic sensor</article-title>,&#x0201D; <conf-name>SPIE Proceedings, 2703A, Photonics West &#x02018;96</conf-name>, (<year>1996</year>).</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r12"><label>12</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Vorontsov</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></name><etal/>., </person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Optical simulation of phase-distorted imaging systems: nonlinear and adaptive optics approach</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Opt Eng</source> <volume>34</volume>(<issue>11</issue>) <fpage>3229</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>3238</lpage>, (<year>1995</year>).<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1117/12.213607</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></book-part></book-part-wrapper>
