<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
<collection-meta collection-type="conf">
<conference content-type="conf-name"><conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name><conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym></conference>
<conference content-type="conf-other-meta"><conf-date content-type="start">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-date content-type="end">
<day>19</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-loc>Nevada, 
<country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc></conference></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
<title-group>
<title>SLM Materials and Sructures</title>
<alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/></title-group></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
<title-group>
<title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title></title-group>
<volume-in-collection>
<volume-number>14</volume-number>
<volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title></volume-in-collection></collection-meta>
<book-meta>
<book-title-group>
<book-title>Spatial Light Modulators</book-title></book-title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Burdge</surname><given-names>Geoffrey</given-names></name></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>Sadik C.</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group>
<pub-date publication-format="electronic">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></pub-date></book-meta>
<book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
<book-part-meta>
<title-group>
<title>Low Voltage Polymer Dispersed Ferroelectric Liquid Crystals</title></title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Pozhidaev</surname><given-names>E. P.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref><xref rid="cor1" ref-type="corresp"><sup>**</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Smorgon</surname><given-names>S. L.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>*</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Andreev</surname><given-names>A. L.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Kompanets</surname><given-names>I. N.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Zyryanov</surname><given-names>V. Ya.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>*</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Shin</surname><given-names>S. T.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff"><sup>#</sup></xref></contrib>
<aff id="aff1">
<label>*</label>L. V. Kierensky Institute of Physics, Krasnoyarsk 660036, 
<country country="RU">Russia</country></aff>
<aff id="aff2">
<label>#</label>Korea University, Jochiwon, Suhchang-Dong 208, Choongnam</aff>
<aff id="aff3">
<label>1</label>P. N. Lebedev Physical Institute, Leninsky pr.53, Moscow 117924 Russia</aff></contrib-group>
<author-notes>
<corresp id="cor1">
<label>**</label>Phone: 007 (095) 132-6116, Fax/Phone: 007 (095) 132-5484, e-mail: <email>evgeni@neur.lpi.msk.su</email></corresp></author-notes>
<elocation-id>94</elocation-id>
<permissions>
<copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
<copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
<copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
<license license-type="open-access">
<license-p>closed</license-p></license></permissions>
<abstract>
<p>Polymer dispersed ferroelectric liquid crystal (PDFLC) films were prepared and investigated. The saturation voltage of 15 V, the electrooptical response time of 15 &#x003BC;s, and the contrast ratio of 100:1 were reached at room temperature.</p></abstract>
<kwd-group kwd-group-type="OCIS">
<title>OCIS codes</title>
<kwd>Polymers</kwd>
<kwd>Ferroelectrics</kwd>
<kwd>Liquid crystals</kwd>
<kwd>Electrooptics</kwd></kwd-group>
<counts>
<book-page-count count="8"/></counts></book-part-meta>
<body>
<p>Introduction .olymer elthe dp Polymer dispersed ferroelectric liquid crystal (PDFLC) films were first developed in 1991 &#x0005B;1,2&#x0005D;. This material provides a fast electrooptical response in addition to the well-known advantages of PDLC. Therefore, one can principally design fast switching electrooptical films for SLM's and displays without glasses, polarizers and special hermetization using PDFLC. These films allow one to increase the light transparency and to simplify the technologyin comparison to the monomeric FLC cells. An A electrooptical incooparso response is exhibited due to the FLC birefringence and polarizers in a transparent mode&#x0005B;3&#x0005D;, or due to the light scattering effect&#x0005B;4&#x0005D;. Now there are available the publications on PDFLC &#x0005B;5-7&#x0005D;, which allow to evaluate their outlook, taking into account especially a significant progress obtained during the last years in both the driving voltage diminishing and the bistability. This work describes different aspects of the PDFLC preparation technology, the modulator design and its investigation (mainly for diminishing the control voltage).</p>
<p>PDFLC films preparation Two stages of the film preparation can be selected: the PDFLC formation in a polymer matrix, and the one- direction orientation of the droplets. Both processes can be produced simultaneously in some cases. Different methods such as mechanical deformation or tension methods, orientation in the flow under extruding through thin draw plate &#x0005B;1&#x0005D;, dispersion under the magnetic field oretdnhflpae8,poooyeiainne oriented in the film plane &#x0005B;8&#x0005D;, photopolymerization under linearlypolarizedlightandtheotherscanbeusedforone- directionFLCdropletorientationasfornematics&#x0005B;5,9. We used thermally induced separation (TIPS) methodand chosed the simplest techniqueof the shift deformation extended usually inlabsto reach theone- directiondropletorientation.Widelyknownthermoplastic - polyvinilbutyral - was used as a polymer matrix in the present work. The weight ratio of FLC materials (##178, 309C, 313, 340 and its modification) and polyvinylbuthiral was 1:2 . The main properties of FLC's whichwereusedarethefollowing: 1.ZhKS-178withphasetransitionstemperatures: Cr-+ (-100C)-+ Sc*-+ (55 0C)-+ SA-+ (69OC)-* I The molecules tilt angle is 270 at 22C, Ps=90-10 Ccm To i-,,=30 iks at E=IOV/mkm, An=0.15 (=633 nm). The helix is compensated over the whole volume. .i 2.ZhKS-309C with ph ase transitions 0 0 C r -- (-1 IoC) --- ) Cr-*~-lC)- S (* -4 (4 2 'C) -~ 42_) )-*S Ss A 5(9 ..1 'C) ~ _)l 91 ). ~ by the The molecules tilt angle is 260 at 200C, Ps=51-10 C cm1- To I.1I nks at E=IOV/mkm, helix pitch po=0.5 mkm. An=O.15 (X=633 nm). S.ZhKS-340 with phase transitions temperatures: Cr-- (7'C) - Sc-* -(53oC) - S,-&gt; (86'C)-&gt; I The molecules tilt angle is 270 at 200C, Ps=86-10 C cu , To (,-23 nks at E=1OV/mkm, An=O.165 (=633 nm). The helix is practically crushed over the whole \olume. 4. ZhKS-313B with phase transition temperatures: Cr - (6 oC) -4 S* - (45 'C) &gt; SA -4 (67 oC) -4 I. T C cn . I-o,=9mks at E=IOV/mkm, helix pitch Po= 3 mkm. An=O.145 (k=633 nm). FLC droplets in polyvinilbutyral have an ellipsoid form of 3+9 mkm average size (depending on the conditions). They are placed at one layer not overlapping eachother(fig.1). Figure 1. Microphoto of the FLC ZhKS-309C droplets group in a polyvinilbutyral film. The droplets are oriented by the shift deformation. The polarizers are crossed, and the shift direction is parallel to one of them. I- droplet with a faint wave deformation of smectic layers: 3-droplets with a confocal domain texture. One can single out two basic structures of the smectic lax ers inside the droplets(fig.2). The first smeetic layers structure corresponds to the texture which looks like a planar-oriented FLC layer with a primarl director orientation along the shift deformation direction (see fig.1. position I). The faint wave deformation of the smeetic layers (fi .2a) takes place in this case. The second structure (fig. 2bJ corresponds to confocal domains (see fig.1. positions 2, 3). Both smectic layers structures were determined through the of FLC droplets image given(as for fig.1) microscope. Figure 2. Two main structures of the smectic layers inside the droplets: a) faint wave deformation of the smectic layers which are almost perpendicular to the long droplet axis; b) deformation of smectic layers corresponding to the confocal domain texture. The structure corresponding to fig. 2a and providing both the high modulation depth and the contrast ratio can be selected due to the technology of PDFLC creation.</p>
<p>PDFLC modulator design The modulators with one or two polarizers were proposed in &#x0005B;1,2&#x0005D;. The PDFLC film can operate as an electrically controlled birefringent plate when the droplet size and the film thickness are of the same order of magnitude, and then at least one polarizer is used (fig. 3). Figure 3. A schematic drawing of the base design of a PDFLC light modulator having at least one polarizer:1, 4 - substrates with transparent electrodes, 2 - polymer film, 3 - FLC-droplets. 5 - polarizers, cx - the angle between the long droplet axis and the incident light polarization. 0 - the tilt anole of molecules in smectic lavers. Quite good optical contrast 100:1 is achieved in such a film of 3-5 mkm thickness for this transparent mode. Only the polarized light can be modulated by PDFLC film. and it is sensitive to the light polarization. Both disadvantages are avoided for the structure based on double PDFLC films &#x0005B;4.Fig.4 shows aschematic drawing of the light valve consisting of two PDFLC cells arrangedinseres. Figure 4. Light modulator based on double PDFLC-cells: 1. 4, 5. 8 - conducting substrates. 2. 6 - polymer films. 3. 7 - FLC-droplets. PDFLC films in the upper and lower cells are identical, but for opposite directions of the electric field supplied. Fig. 4a shows that PDFLC molecules, under the applied field, are oriented so that their long axes in both . films are parallel to each other and lie in the XY-plane. In this case the light with the polarization plane along theY axis is not scattered when it is passing through the device because of the actual absence of the refractive index gradient on the polymer LC-droplet interfaces. So, the described arrangement is essentially a system of parallel oriented scattering polarizers &#x0005B;4&#x0005D;. Fig. 4b shows that the molecules turn at an angle of 20=450 under the electric field polarity change, but still remain in the XY-plane. The molecules in the upper and lower films turn in the opposite directions to the X axis, so the angle between them becomes 40=900. In this position the PDFLC device scatters the light of any polarization, like a nematic PDLC. Double PDFLC films based on the light scattering effect possess not high light transparency (up to 30 percent until now).</p>
<p>Dynamic characteristics It was shown &#x0005B;2&#x0005D; that the normalized to the electric field electrooptical responce time value, under the applied AC voltage,forPDFLCisthesameasformonomericFLC (namely DOBAMBC). The relaxation time of the droplets aftertheelectricvoltageswitchingoffwasseveralorders less than for monomeric FLC. One can see that two types of bistability &#x0005B;5,7&#x0005D; are observed in the PDFLC with different FLC compositions and thickness. It is possible to choose the PDFLC composition and preparation technology to provide the required electrooptical response time: from 10-5 to 10-' seconds of the switch on time, and from 10-seconds to hours (days) for the relaxation time. The switch off time Tff under unipolar driving voltage is practically independent on the electric field tension, like the polymer dispersed nematics, but the value toff is about 100 mks. This is confirmed experimentally for the PDFLCs with the film thickness of 9 mkm, and the droplet size of 3 mkm (Fig.5). 1 Figure 5t 0 . 0 9(U)dependence fortheAC driving voltage (curve 1), 1/Ton(U) for the unipolar driving voltage (curve 2). PDFLC layer thickness is 9 mkm, the dropletsizeis3mkm,thetemperatureis22oC.PDFLC based on the FLC ZhKS-309C was used. It is necessaryto point out especiallythatthe electroopticalresponsetimeT 0 1-09 fortheACdriving voltage slightly depends on the disposition of FLC inside the polymer droplet or inside a monomeric FLC cell. This time was 15 mks at 8.4 Vmkm in optimized PDFLC film with 3 mkm droplet size at room temperature (Fig.6). Figure 6. Temperature dependencies of electro-optical response time To1o., for monomeric FLC cell on the base of ZhKS-309C (curve 2) and PDFLC on the base of ZhKS-309C with droplet size d0=3 mkm (curve 1) for AC driving voltage and the electric field tension E=8.4 V/mkm.</p>
<p>Driving voltage Thedrivingvoltagevalueisacriticalparameterfor PDFLC modulators, especially for the light scattering mode devices. This value must be not less than the sasaturatio saturationvoltageVsa. Thesaturationvoltage strongly dependsonthepolymertypeandtheparametersofFLC, andwas 250&#x000B1;350VwhenthePDFLCinvestigationwas started &#x0005B;1&#x0005D;. Then it was diminished to 40 V &#x0005B;5&#x0005D; and 25 V &#x0005B;6&#x0005D;. Typical electric field/light transmittance dependencies of PDFLC cells in comparison with the monomeric ones are shown in fig.7. Fiure7Electricfield- lighttransmittance characteristics at 20OC: a) PDFLC films of the 9.5 mkm thickness and the droplet size of d,=3 mkm based on different FLC's: ZhKS- 309C (curve 1), ZhKS-340 (curve 2), ZhKS-178 (curve 3). thickness(curve 1), PDFLC film on the base of ZhKS- 340 (curve 2) of 9.5 mkm thickness and the droplet size do=3 mkm. One can see that Usat= 97 V for PDFLC and Usa,=3 V for the corresponding monomeric FLC cell at the same film thickness (Fig. 7b). So, PDFLC saturation voltage is 30 - 35 times higher than for the corresponding monomeric FLC cell. This typical difference always exists for any type of polymers and FLC's, but PDFLC saturationvoltagestronglydependsonFLCtypeandits parameters voltage strngl deed one FLCraio (Fig.7a). type an itsngl The reorientation process is threshold free, the curve is linear up to the saturation region. Such a dependence is convenient for a gray scale in actively addressed displays. The minimal Vsal=15V was reached due to the optimization of FLC compositions only (fig. 8). Figure 8. PDFLC volt - light transmittance characteristic for ZhKS-309C based PDFLC film of 5mkm thickness, 4.5 mkm droplet size at the temperature of22C. The charge mobility role An approach is proposed to diminish the saturation voltage. It takes into account the mobility of polarization charges transferred Z in PDFLC droplets with the polarization reversal current caused by the FLC molecules reorientation under the external electric field. When the interaction energy Ps-E of the electrical field and the spontaneous polarization is much more than the FLC elastic deformation energy in the droplets and much greater than the anchoring energy, the following relation is valid: PsEsinp= -yd/dt , (1) Ps-(5)i where y, is the rotational viscosity. The Ps projection onto the polar axis X (see fig. 9) is written: (2) Pro= Ps-cos , Ficure 9. Structure of a bistable surface stabilized FLC cell with a "bookshelf" geometry of smectic layers. 1 - quartz or glass plates; 2 - transparent conductive electrodes with an orienting polymer layer;R- direction of polymer rubbing; 3 - smectic layers; 4- voltage generator; 6 - tilt angle,p- azimuthal angle; 1, A - polarizer and analyzer; - angle between R and A; N -FLC director; - electric field. The polarization reversal current can be derived from relations (I) and (2): jR-dPIo/dt=d(P-cosp) /dt= Ps-sinp -dp/dt=(Ps sin 2 /y)E=RYER. (3) whereTR is the electroconductivityofthePDFLCfil caused by the polarization reversal current expressed as: CYR =Ps 2 aR=(Ps -sintP)/yr. sin Q~ly (4) The amplitude value R' of the conductivity is: GRa=Ps /Y,P. (5) The electroconductivity and the charge mobility of the conductors and semiconductors are related as: where e-n product is the whreenproductithevolmedensityofthtransferred volume density of the transferred charges. However, the mobility of charges transferred due to the bias current distinguishes " from the carriers' charge. The electroconductivity in PDFLC can be introduced as Ps/do, where do is a droplet diameter. That's why the value oaforPDFLCcanbewrittenlike(6)as: a , (7) (7) CR =Ps-PR/do where pp is a charge mobility in droplets. From equations an (7 it is obvious : (5)and(7)itisobvious (8) PR-Ps-do.y, Thus, the value PR is determined in the limits of our simplest consideration as the product of the droplet diameter do (this is a technological parameter of the PDFLC film), and the value Ps/yep, which is a FLC material characteristic. The ratio (8) can be also used to determinethe charge mobility in monomeric FLC cell if the layer thickness d is substituted in to (8) instead of d. It is necessary to measure the droplet size (or the FLC layer thickness for monomeric cell) and Ps/y, parameter of the liquid crystal in order to evaluate experimentally the charge mobility from (8). The geometry of a monomeric cell is the same as considered in Fig. 9. The relation between the saturation field of the monomeric FLC cells and the mobility PR of the charges transferred with the bias current IR from one electrode to another is considered at first. Fig. 10 shows that the charge mobility increases, and the saturation field with the temperature increase. Figure 10. Temperature dependencies of the charge ty l-L and the saturat Ion field Esat of a monomeric FLC cell with FLC ZhKS-178 (layer thickness is 3.4 mkm), The shape of the observed mobility versus temperature dependence is analogous to the semiconductor one. This similarity seem to be caused by the necessity of the motion over the potential barrier for the charge transfer both in the FLC cell and in the semiconductor. The charge mobility absolute values in FLC cells are approximately seven orders less than for the semiconductors (Fig. 10). Fig. I I shows the dependence Esat(PR') which was plotted using the data of dependencies pR(T) and Esa,(T) Figuire IL Dependence of the saturation field Esa, versus inlerse charge mobilityB -R' which was obtained due to the temperature variation. Monomeric FLC is ZhKS-178, the la\er thickness is 3.4 mkm. It appears that the saturation field is inversely proportional to the charge mobility. Thus, it is possible to state an empirical relation between the saturation field and thechargemobilityinFLCcellaccountingtherelation(8) andexperimentaldependenciesinFig.I1: Esat-k-PR =-k-y,'(Ps-do) (9) \\here k is an experimentally determined proportion coefficient. It is possible to conclude from (9) that the decreasing of';, Ps parameter and the increasing of the liquid crystal la\er thickness d are necessary for the field saturation decrease ina monomeric FLC cell. Let usconsiderdependenceEsa(T) formonomeric FLC cell with a helix pitch po= 0 .5 mkm shown in fig. 12. One can see that the mobility increases and the saturation field decreases when the temperature increases for FLC of this type as for the helix free cells (see Fig. 11). But fig. 12 shows that the dependence Esat(IPR) is not a linear one. Figure 12. Dependence of the saturation field Esat versus inverse charge mobilityPR for the monomeric FLC cell. The dependence was obtained due to the temperature variation. FLC ZhKS-309C. helix pitch po=0.5 mkm, the layer thickness is 6.4 mkm. the relation (9) is not valid when k is constant. However, it was shown experimentally that the saturation field also increases with the mobility decrease and for the case considered. This dependence can be explained with the k dependence on some inhomogeneities of FLC director distribution because of its variations in a general case. For example, this inhomogeneity is a helix twist for the considered case. Within the framework of this hypothesis the equation (9) can be rewritten as: Est=f(lpR-()-YY(Ps-do) . (10) where f(pR) is a function dependent on the charge mobility, which, in its turn, depends on the FLC director distribution inhomogeneity. For PDFLC under this consideration it should be noted that the inhomogeneities of the director distribution in the droplets are always independent of their observation in the monomeric FLC. The comparison of Esat(PR') dependencies for PDFLC in fig. 13 and for the monomeric FLC in fig. 12 shows that they are similar. However, it is necessary to note that the saturation field for PDFLC based on FLC ZhKS-309C is approximately 20 times stronger than the same parameter for monomeric FLC cells. Another difference is a weak temperature dependence of Esat for PDFLC. Fig. 13 shows that the saturation field reaches its maximal value, and becomes independent of the mobility when the charge mobility in the PDFLC is less than a certain critical value. Figure 13. Dependencies of the saturation field Esat versus inverse charge mobility t1 ' for PDFLCs based on FLC ZhKS-309C (curve 1) and FLC: ZhKS-340 (curve 2). PDFLC layer thickness is 9 mkm, the droplet size is 3 mkm. The dependence was obtained due to the temperature variation. The pt R' value depends on the liquid crystal type in the droplets for the same polymer (polyvinilbutyral) (fig. 13,curveIand2).Thep RI valuesregion,whereEsatcan be changed, is limited for PDFLC in contrast to the monomeric FLC. Nevertheless the charge mobility increase causes the saturation field decrease as for the monomeric FLC cells. Fig. 14showsEstl R') dependencies for PDFLCs based n th ws olyvinilutyral based abecause in this case the film on the thickness is polyvinilbutyral and the FLCs withdifferent Pvalues. The dropletsizesdarealsodifferent.Itis Figure 14. Dependence of the saturation field Esat versus inverse charge mobility PR_' for PDFLCs which was obtained due to variation of both the yo/Ps and the droplet sizedo. Experimental pointscorrespondto: 1 - FLC ZhKS-313B, the droplet size do=3 mkm, 2 - FLC ZhKS 309C, do=5 mkm, 3 - FLC ZhKS-309C, do=3 mkm, 4 - FLC ZhKS-340, d0=3 mkm, 5 - FLC ZhKS-178, do=2.5 mkm. evident (see the relation (10)) that the charge mobility is the function of y,/Ps and d. This leads to the saturation field changing in the considered PDFLCs from 3 V/mkm to 15 V/mkm. It should be noted that almost the same value is achieved for the polymer dispersed nematic liquid crystals also &#x0005B;10&#x0005D;. The best results among the published ones for the saturation field in PDFLC are 8 V/mkm &#x0005B;5&#x0005D; and 6 V/mkm &#x0005B;6&#x0005D;. Thus, we succeeded these values more than twice, increasing the charge mobility in PDFLC due to PR diminution (see Fig.14). The further diminution of the saturation field can be achieved, probably, due to the polymer selection. However, the smectic layers structure and the boundary conditions in PDFLC droplet have to be taken into account. Keeping in mind (10) one can write: Usat- y,.L/(Ps-do), (11) where L is a thickness of the PDFLC film. Then, to diminish the PDFLC saturation voltage it is necessary to diminishtheratioy/Psfor theliquidcrystal, and the ratio ofthefilthiknesfothedlesiz of the film thickness L to the droplet that theminimal sizedo. It is evident Ldvalueis: (L/do)min=1 (12) the droplet size. The PDFLC film becomes birefringent when (12) is valid, because the multiple light reflection on droplet-polymer boundaries becomes impossible. That's why PDFLC film with the lowest saturation voltage, when the relation (12) is valid, can be exploited only in two polarizers design. PDFLC important properties such as high light transmission and the ability to work without polarizers are lost for this design as compared to a conventional birefringent display. Actually it is necessary to satisfy the relation: L/do 0 3 (13) for the one polarizer or polarizers free design. The best light transmission is for the last two designs, but the higher driving voltage is necessary in principle in comparison with the two polarizers design. The samples based on ZhKS-309C with droplet size do=4.5 mkm and the film thickness L=5 mkm were developedasthelowestvoltagePDFLC.Thisisadouble refractive film which is placed between two crossed polarizers. The PDFLC film saturation voltage is 15 V (see fig. 8) at the driving voltage frequency of 2000 Hz. The lowest saturation voltage for PDFLC light shutters without polarizers is 57 V (Fig. 15). Figure 15. PDFLC volt - light transmittance characteristic for the ZhKS-309C based film of 9 mkm thickness with droplet size of 3 mkm at the temperature of 22C. The thickness of the film in use is 9 mkm and the droplet size is 3 mkm. Thus, the relation (13) is valid, and makes possible to get the contrast ratio more than 10 : 1 due to the multiple light refraction on the droplet boundaries for the polarizers free design. Thus, the contrast ratio depends mainly on the film preparation technology for both modes (transparency and scattering) of modulators. The modulator light transmittance does not depend on the temperature practically within the whole C* phase interval, except of a narrow region near the transition into the high temperature phase &#x0005B;II&#x0005D;. Bothtpes ofPDFLClightmodulatorsdescribed above can operate under the alternating pulses of 2 kHz frequency when the driving voltage is equal to the saturationone. Conclusion PDFLC composition. textures and modulators design are considered. The influence of the molecular structure and FLC features on to PDFLC saturation field is investigated. The main role of the mobility of charges transferred in PDFLC droplets with the polarization reversal current caused by FLC molecules reorientation under the external electric field is pointed out. PDFLC films modulators with thedrivingvoltageof15Vweredeveloped. The method of further saturation voltage decreasing due to FLC y,Ps parameter is proposed. One can expect further improvement of the PDFLC parameters during optimization of FLC and polymer compositionaswellastheirweightratio</p>
<p>Acknowledgments This work was carried out under Joint Development Program of P.N. Lebedev Physical Institute and Samsung Electronics Co., Ltd. We thank them for this support. We are grateful to Dr. I.P.Revokatova and Mr. S.I.Kompanets for their assistance throughout this work.</p></body>
<back>
<ref-list>
<ref id="r1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="patent"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhuikov</surname><given-names>V.A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zyryanov</surname><given-names>V. Ya</given-names></name><name><surname>Smorgon</surname><given-names>S.L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Shabanov</surname><given-names>V.F.</given-names></name></person-group> <article-title>Electrooptical material, method of producing the electrooptical material and device for modulation of light Russian Patent Application</article-title>, <source>PCT SU</source> <patent>91/00195</patent>, <year>1991</year></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="confproc"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zyryanov</surname><given-names>V. Ya</given-names></name><name><surname>Smorgon</surname><given-names>S.L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Shabanov</surname><given-names>V.F.</given-names></name></person-group> <conf-name>IV th Int. Meet. on Optics of LC, Abstracts</conf-name>, <conf-loc>70 Florida, USA</conf-loc>, (<year>1991</year>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kitzerov</surname><given-names>H.S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Molsen</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Heppke</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>Linear electrooptic effects in polymer dispersed ferroelectric liquid crystal displays</article-title>. <source>Appl Phys Lett</source> <volume>60</volume>(<issue>25</issue>) <fpage>3093</fpage>-<lpage>3095</lpage>, (<year>1992</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.106762</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zyryanov</surname><given-names>V. Ya</given-names></name><name><surname>Smorgon</surname><given-names>S.L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Shabanov</surname><given-names>V.F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Pozhidaev</surname><given-names>E.P.</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>Polymer dispersed ferroelectric liquid crystal light valves</article-title>. <source>SID 94 Digest</source> <volume>25</volume>, <fpage>605</fpage>-<lpage>607</lpage>, (<year>1994</year>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Molsen</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kitzerov</surname><given-names>H.S.</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>Bistability in polymer dispersed ferroelectric liquid crystals</article-title>. <source>J Appl Phys</source> <volume>75</volume>, <issue>#1</issue>, <fpage>317</fpage>-<lpage>320</lpage>, (<year>1994</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.356471</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chu</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>West</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></name></person-group> <article-title>Bistable switching in polymer dispersed smectic C<sup>*</sup> displays</article-title>. <source>SID 94 Digest</source> <volume>25</volume>, <fpage>845</fpage>-<lpage>847</lpage></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r7"><label>7</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zyryanov</surname><given-names>V. Ya</given-names></name><name><surname>Smorgon</surname><given-names>S.L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Shabanov</surname><given-names>V.F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Andreev</surname><given-names>A.L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Pozhidaev</surname><given-names>E.P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kompanets</surname><given-names>I.N.</given-names></name></person-group> <article-title>Volume bistability in ferroelectric liquid crystal droplets</article-title>. <conf-name>16th Intern. Liquid Cryst. Conf., Kent</conf-name>, <conf-loc>USA</conf-loc>, <year>1996</year> Abstracts, 168, (1996)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r8"><label>8</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Nazarchenko</surname><given-names>V.G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Reznikov</surname><given-names>Yu. A</given-names></name><name><surname>Reshetnyak</surname><given-names>V. Yu</given-names></name><name><surname>Sergan</surname><given-names>V.V.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zyryanov</surname><given-names>V. Ya</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>Oriented dispersion of liquid crystal droplets in a polymer matrix with light induced anisotropy</article-title>. <source>Molecular materials</source> <volume>2</volume>, <fpage>295</fpage>-<lpage>299</lpage>, (<year>1993</year>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r9"><label>9</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Margerum</surname><given-names>J.D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jacker</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ramos</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>Effect of off-state alignment in polymer-dispersed liquid crystals</article-title>. <source>LiquidCrystals</source> <volume>5</volume>, <fpage>1477</fpage>-<lpage>1487</lpage>, (<year>1989</year>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r10"><label>10</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Matsumoto</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Houlbert</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hayashi</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kubodera</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>Fine droplets of liquid crystals in a transparent polymer and their response to an electric field</article-title>, <source>Appl Phys Lett</source> <volume>69</volume>(<issue>8</issue>, (<year>1996</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.116925</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r11"><label>11</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Smorgon</surname><given-names>S.L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zyryanov</surname><given-names>V. Ya</given-names></name><name><surname>Shabanov</surname><given-names>V.F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Pozhidaev</surname><given-names>E.P.</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>Light modulators based on polymer dispersed ferroelectric liquid crystals</article-title>. <source>SPIE</source> <volume>2731</volume>, <fpage>188</fpage>-<lpage>194</lpage>, (<year>1996</year>)</mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></book-part></book-part-wrapper>
