<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
<collection-meta collection-type="conf">
<conference content-type="conf-name"><conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name><conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym></conference>
<conference content-type="conf-other-meta"><conf-date content-type="start">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-date content-type="end">
<day>19</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-loc>Nevada, 
<country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc></conference></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
<title-group>
<title>SLM Materials and Sructures</title>
<alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/></title-group></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
<title-group>
<title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title></title-group>
<volume-in-collection>
<volume-number>14</volume-number>
<volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title></volume-in-collection></collection-meta>
<book-meta>
<book-title-group>
<book-title>Spatial Light Modulators</book-title></book-title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Burdge</surname><given-names>Geoffrey</given-names></name></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>Sadik C.</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group>
<pub-date publication-format="electronic">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></pub-date></book-meta>
<book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
<book-part-meta>
<title-group>
<title>Fast response PROM using GaAs single crystal</title></title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Bitou</surname><given-names>Youichi</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Minemoto</surname><given-names>Takumi</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<aff id="aff1">
<label>1</label>The Graduate School of Science and Technology, Kobe University, Rokko-dai, Nada-ku, Kobe 657, 
<country country="JP">Japan</country></aff></contrib-group>
<elocation-id>147</elocation-id>
<permissions>
<copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
<copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
<copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
<license license-type="open-access">
<license-p>closed</license-p></license></permissions>
<abstract>
<p>A new Pockels Readout Optical Modulator (PROM) device using a GaAs single crystal (GaAs-PROM) has been developed for high speed operation. Its fundamental properties were experimentally investigated and the operational technique was given by them. The GaAs-PROM was driven by a sinusoidal alternating high voltage and its high sensitivity and high frame rate (&gt;500 Hz) were experimentally confirmed. This is a extremely high compared with a conventional PROM</p></abstract>
<kwd-group kwd-group-type="OCIS">
<title>OCIS codes</title>
<kwd>Spatial light modulator</kwd>
<kwd>Pockels readout optical modulator</kwd>
<kwd>GaAs</kwd>
<kwd>high speed operation</kwd></kwd-group>
<counts>
<book-page-count count="8"/></counts></book-part-meta>
<body>
<p>1. Introduction The spatial light modulator (SLM) is one of the essential components in optical computing and optical image processing systems. The optical addressing SLM has the advantages of optical parallelism in both input and output plane and so is used for wavelength converter and/or incoherent image to coherent image converter. The main performance requests on SLM are higher sensitivity. higher contrast ratio, higher spatial resolution, and faster response time. Especially, the sensitivity is the most important factor for high speed operation. A low sensitivity device needs high power write-in and erasing light sources. In this paper, we propose a new Pockels readout optical modulator (PROM) device using a GaAs crystal plate (GaAs-PROM) for high speed operation, and its characteristics and an operating system are investigated. The PROM device is well known as the SLM for optical processing system &#x0005B;1-3&#x0005D;. This device consists of a photoconductive and electrooptic (Pockels effect) crystal plate covered with insulating films and transparent electrodes. Usually. Bi 1 2 SiO 2 0 (BSO) crystal is used as the photoconductive and electrooptic crystal, and the device is called as BSO-PROM. Comparing to consumer- product spatial light modulator such as liquid crystal light valves, the PROM device has simple structure. faster response time of electrooptical effect, and higher contrast ratio (larger than 1000:1). However, the BSO-PROM has not so high sensitivity (several tens / /cm2 ) and it is sensitive only to blue to green radiations. These facts are main reasons to prevent realization of high speed optical systems using the BSO-PROM. The GaAs crystal is the attractive material because of its high carriers (electrons and holes) mobilities. wideband sensitivity (from visible to near infrared radiation), and large absorption coefficient. Consequently it has been used as a photoreceptor of the liquid crystal light valve &#x0005B;4-51. When we make a plan to realize a PROM device with fast response, we need a photoconductive material with high carrier mobility and large absorption coefficient for a write-in light. The GaAs single crystal has both electrooptical and photoconductive effect and is considered useful material for the PROM device. Additionally. the GaAs has no optical activity and circular birefringence, although BSO crystal has those troublesome characteristics. Also. it is easy to make uniform plates with large sizes. Using the Pockels effect of a crystal such as PROM devices, an applied voltage of several kilo volts is necessary for useful operations. Therefore. in the conventional use of the PROM device, high speed operations of the devices need high speed ON/OFF of the high voltage. It is not so easy to perform ON/OFF of the high voltage with a high speed. To remove the difficulty, in this paper, GaAs-PROM was driven by externally applying a sinusoidal alternating high voltage. Needless to say, the application of the ac voltage is easier than the ON/OFF operation in a high voltage at a high frequency. In the following, we first describe the device structure of GaAs-PROM and its characteristics of sensitivity. Next, the SLM operation system is investigated and its high sensitivity and frame rate is experimentally confirmed.</p>
<p>2. Device fabrication and basic properties The structure of GaAs-PROM is shown in Fig. 1. A thin plate with (001) surface was cut out from an undoped GaAs single crystal ingot grown by Liquid Encapsulated Czochralski (LEC) method. The dark resistivity of the plate was 4 x 10 Q cm. Thin glass plates were used Figure 1. Structure of GaAs-PROM. Figure 2. Experimental setup to investigate basic properties of GaAs-PROM. as insulators. Each layer was bonded with lens bond. In this work, we prepared two kinds of devices (Device-I and Device-2): the thicknesses of GaAs and glass plates were 400 pm and 10 p m in Device-1, and 600 p m and 100 pm in Device-2, respectively. In this section, only the experimental results in Device-i were mainly described, because the similar properties were also recognized in Device-2. The basic properties of GaAs-PROM were investigated by an experimental setup shown in Fig. 2. A uniform write-in light in visible region was incident on the device by a half mirror. The recorded image (a uniform image) was read out by a near infrared light. The write-in and the readout lights were incident on the device from the same side. GaAs crystal has the symmetry of the point group 43m and the maximum retardation due to the Pockels effect is given in the readout light with linearly polarized light along the axis &lt;100&gt; or &lt;010&gt;. Then, the polarization of the readout light was set along the axis &lt;100&gt; or &lt;010&gt; and the analyzer was set perpendicular to the polarizer. The transparent electrode of the device in this incident side was earthed and an ac high voltages driving the device was supplied from a function generator through a high voltage power amplifier. The intensity of the readout light transmitting the device was measured by a photodetector through an analyser and a lens. The readout light was provided by a laser diode (LD) with the lasing wavelength of 980 nm. In this experiment, a filter isolating only the readout light was not necessary because the visible write-in light (its wavelength was over the band gap energy: 1.43 eV) was mostly absorbed within the surface layer of several P m thick in GaAs plate. This absorption property is associated with high sensitivity over a wider region of the wavelength comparing to that of the BSO-PROM. First, the basic properties were investigated under no write-in light and continuous illumination of the readout Under the conditions, the readout light was modulated by the Pockels effect of GaAS crystal plate due to only the externally applied electric field. Then the output light intensity from the device was modulated with the twice frequency of applied ac voltage. An example of time variations in the output light intensities are shown in Fig. 3(a) together with the waveform of applied ac voltage</p>
<p>V. The result in the figure was obtained using the readout of 940 p W/cm 2 and the ac voltage with the amplitude of 3 kV and frequency of 500 Hz. It is seen that the output light intensity was modulated with the twice frequency of the ac voltage. However, the peak height of output light intensity when V&gt;0 is slightly different from that when V&lt;0. Theoretically, the two peaks should be similarly independent of the direction of Figure 3. Observed signals of the Pockels effect in GaAs-PROM. These signals were observed under the following conditions. Externally applied ac voltage; amplitude of 3 kV at 500 Hz, uniform readout light; wavelength of 980 nm and intensity of 940 u W/cm 2 . and uniform write-in light; wavelength of 780 nm and intensity of 2.2 mW/cm 2 , respectively. Upper and lower signals in each figure show the waveforms of applied ac voltage and the output signal, respectively. The signals in (a) and (b) were observed under no and continuous illuminations of the write-in light, respectively. the electric field in GaAs crystal because the crystal is ideally optically isotropic. The actual GaAs crystal or wafer cut out from an ingot grown by the LEC method has two dimensional distributions of a small amount of birefringence &#x0005B;6&#x0005D;. Unfortunately, it seems that the GsAs plate in Device-I had a small amount of birefringence. Figure 4. -Dependence of the Pockels effect in Device-1 on frequency of externally applied ac voltage. The amplitude of ac voltages were kept to 3 kV. and the magnitudes of the Pockels effect were represented b\ the optical transmission T of the device. Consequently, the extinction ratio of this device became approximately 1000 ~ 500:1, on the contrary that of BSO-PROM is over 10 ' :1, and the difference of two peaks might be caused by the birefringence. To realize a high contrast GaAs-PROM, we have to choose a GaAs crystal plate with very small birefringence. From the results of the Pockels effect in V&lt;0, the half-wave voltage of Device-i was determined as 7.5 kV. The half-wave voltage of Device-2 was also determined as 12.4 kV from the similar experiment. The dependence of the Pockels effect on the frequency of the applied ac voltage was measured in Device-1. The results are shown in Fig. 4 as the variation of optical transmission T of the device versus the frequency of ac voltage, where the amplitude of external voltage was constantly kept to 3 kV. The transmission T was defined as the ratio of the peak value of output intensity to the output intensity when V=0 and the analyzer was set parallel to the polarizer. The transmission T increased as the frequency of ac voltage increased and saturated at the frequencies larger than 100 Hz. It is seen from the results that the conductivity of the GaAs plate can be ignored in the frequencies larger than around 100 Hz at V=3 kV and the GaAs-PROM can be considered as the series circuit of the capasiters which are made from GaAs plate and insulators, respectively. The time variation of the output light intensity coincides with the applied ac voltage in that situation. The electro-static relaxation time of Device-1 was estimated as 6.5 ms at V=3 kV from the results shown in Fig. 4. Next, the sensitivity characteristics of GaAs-PROM for the write-in light, (1) asymmetric characteristics due to the mutual relations between the incident direction of write-in light and the direction of applied electric field and (2) the dependence of sensitivity on the wavelength of\wite-in light, were experimentally investigated. 2.1 Asymmetric characteristics of sensitivity The write-in light generates photo carriers (electrons and holes). the carriers migrate in the GaAs crystal along the electric field and consequently negate the electric field in the crystal. The Pockels effect in the crystal plate decreases as the write-in light intensity increases. Then, the GaAs-PROM converts an input image to its negative image. Here. the characteristics relating to the intensity and the incident direction of write-in light are investigated. The Device-i was continuously illuminated by the uniform readout light (intensity: 940 u W/cm2 and wavelength: 980 nm) and a uniform write-in light (wavelength: 780 nm and various intensity levels) at the same time and driven by applying ac voltage with the amplitude of 3 kV and the frequency of 500 Hz. The readout signals were observed on various intensity levels of the write-in light. An example of the readout signals is shown in Fig 3(b). The readout signal decayed strongly and hardly when V&lt;0 and V&gt;0. respectively. comparing the readout signals obtained by no write-in light (Fig. 3(a)). The write-in light and the electric field due to the applied ac field were codirectional when V&lt;0. and they were contradirectional when V&gt;0. In the following, we refer the former and the latter to the codirectional and the contradirectional write-ins, respectively. The variations of peak values ofthe readout signals versus the write-in light intensity were summarized in Fig. 5. for the codirectional and the contradirectional write-ins. The codirectional write-in is high sensitive but the contradirectional write-in has almost no sensitivity. That is, the sensitivity of GaAs-PROM is asymmetric. The write-in light is almost absorbed in the thin surface layer with thickness of about 4 i m. The photo carriers are generated in the thin layer on the side where the write-in light comes incident and move along the electric field in the crystal. The holes and electrons become the effective carriers for the codirectional and the contradirectional write-ins, respectively. It is known that in low electric field, the mobilities of the electron and the hole in the GaAs are around 6000 cm2 /(V . s) and 400 cm2 /(V . s), respectively. From this fact, it is expected that the contradirectional write-in becomes more sensitive than the codirectional write-in. However, the experimental results were contrary to the expectation. The influence of Figure 5. Asymmetric characteristics of sensitivity in Device-I driven by a high ac voltage (3 kV). The sensitivity curves for the codirectional write-in and the contradirectional write-in versus there intensities are plotted by marks 0 (solid curve) and 0 (dashed curve), respectively. The sensitivities were represented by the peak values ofthe output signals and the peak values are normalized by that for no write-in light intensity. the electrons seems to cause this contrary results. In the semiconductors, the electron's mobility has a negative differential in the electric field larger than the threshold field. Those electrons are called as hot electrons and the threshold value of electric field is around 3 kV/cm in GaAs crystal &#x0005B;7-8&#x0005D;. The maximum electric field strength in GaAs crystal was estimated as 55 kV/cm when the applied ac voltage became 3 kV in the experiments. In such strong electric field. it seems that the drift velocity of holes is larger than that of electrons. To confirm these facts. the experiment in which variation of the readout signal versus the applied ac voltage was observed at the write-in light intensity of 400 ,uW/cm The peak values ofthe signals in both cases ofthe codirectional and the contradirectional write-ins became almost same at the maximum electric field strength of around 25 kV/cm, that was made by V 1.5 kV, and at V&lt;1.5 kV the peak value in the latter case became smaller than the former. that is, the contradirectional write-in became more sensitive than the codirectional wATite-in. These experimental results indicate that the holes become effective carriers when V&gt;1.5 kV and the codirectional write-in is useful to realize the high sensitive and high contrast when the GaAs-PROM is derived by a higher ac voltage.</p>
<p>2.2 Dependence of sensitivity on write-in light wavelength The characteristics of Device-1 for the wavelength of write-in light were investigated by the similar experimental setup as shown in Fig. 2. In the experiments. the output signals were read out using a uniform radiation (wavelength: 1300 nm and intensity: 55 i W/cm2 ) from an incandescent lamp through an interference filter. The write-in lights were provided by using lasers (wavelengths: 780 nm, 980 nm, and 1064 nm) and LEDs (wavelength: 660 nm, 850 nm, and 950nm), and their intensities were kept a constant (940 9 W/cm )The applied ac voltage was 3kV. and the device was always illuminated by both the readout and the write-in lights. The variations of peak values of the output signals versus the wavelength of write-in light are shown in Fig. 6. where the peak values are normalized by that for no write-in light. When the write-in light wavelength is longer than 900 nm, the sensitivities for both the codirectional and the contradirectional write-ins have almost same values and became lower with the increase of the wavelength. But when the wavelength is shorter than the band gap of GaAs (around 850 nm), the sensitivities for the codirectional write-in and the contradirectional write-in became extremely different because of just described above. The sensitivity for the contradirectional write-in became highest around 900 nm. This might be because of that the absorption layer of the write-in light became moderately thick and the separation efficiency of holes and electrons became higher consequently. Conversely, the sensitivity for the codirectional write-in became higher as the wavelength decreased. It is seen that the highest sensitivity is attained by using the write-in light with wavelength of around 820 nm. From the results in the above, it is known that the GaAs-PROM is (1) high sensitive to the codirectional write-in light but (2) hardly sensitive to the contradirectional write-in light, and (3) useful to transform a visible light image to its negative image in the near infrared region.</p>
<p>3. SLM operation system From the above results, in order to organize a higher quality SLM using a GaAs-PROM, the following items were used for the SLM operation system. (1) the codirectional write-in should be introduced, (2) the recorded image should be read out by a short pulse illumination of infrared light at the peak of the applied ac voltage in V&lt;0 because the effect of the write-in light on the contrast of the readout signals becomes maximum at the peak in V&lt;0 as seen from the results in the previous section. and (3) it is desired that the erasing light prepares a uniform electric field in the GaAs crystal plate just before the write-in process. The third item is satisfied by introducing the erasing light as follows. From the characteristics shown in Fig. 5, GaAs-PROM is almost insensitive to a visible incident light in the sense of the contradirectional write-in, that is. in the write-in process the visible light is only useful in the sense of the codirectional write-in and is almost innocent in the sense of the contradirectional write-in. Then, a visible light illuminating the device contradirectional to the write-in light usefully acts as erasing light. An optical setup for SLM is schematically shown in Fig. 7. The write-in light is imaged on GaAS-PROM by a lens L i . the readout light from the PROM is also imaged on a CCD camera by a lens L 2 . an erasing light is newly introduced behind the PROM. and the others are the same as Fig. 2. As a result of the following Figure 6. Variations of output signals versus wavelength of write-in light in Device-I. Figure 7. Optical setup for SLM operation. A, analyzer; P, polarizer; L iand L2 , lenses. experiments, in an operation cycle of GaAS-PROM, the erasing of the image recorded in its previous cycle is performed in the first half period of the applied ac voltage (when V&gt;0), a new image is recorded in the third quarter period (when V&lt;0), and the recorded image is readout just after the third quarter period (at the negative peak of ac voltage) by a pulse of readout light, respectively. In the following experiments, a pulse light from a LD (wavelength: 980 nm) was used as the readout light and synchronized to the negative peak of ac voltage. The pulse width was 0.2 ms and its peak intensity was 9.4 mW/cm 2 , which was needed to obtain enough bright readout images using the CCD TV camera. The pulse light had weaken the Pockels effect in GaAs because the light has weakly absorbed by GaAs and the pulse had large peak intensity. But this fact did not affect the investigations of erasing, recording, and readout characteristics in the SLM system.</p>
<p>3.1 Effects of erasing light and frame rate An incoherent uniform erasing light (wavelength: 660 nm from LED) continuously illuminated on the GaAs-PROM from its rear side. It provided faster erasing of the recorded image. The waveforms of readout signals shown in the Fig. 8(a) were obtained from Device-i with no write-in light and the continuous illumination of the erasing light (intensity: 1.3 mW/cm2), where the amplitude of ac voltage was 3kV (at frequency of 500 Hz). The erasing light was mostly absorbed within several _L m thick and generated electrons and holes near the rear side surface of GaAs plate. The effects of the continuous erasing light are described as follows. When V&gt;0 the light erases the electric field distribution in GaAs plate because the holes become the effective carrier corresponding the codirectional wite-in. When V&lt;0 the erasing light corresponds to the contradirectional write-in and the photocarriers do not erase the electric field so much because the electrons near the rear surface must move to near the front surface in order to effectively erase the electric field. The erasing light must uniformize the electric field in GaAs plate and erase the recorded image within the half period in V&gt;0. To confirm whether the requirement is satisfied or not, a uniform write-in light (wavelength: 850 nm from LED) was illuminated only at the third quarter period in every alternate periods of the ac voltage, the uniform erasing light was also continuously illuminated, and the uniform images recorded in Device-1 were read out every periods of ac voltage. The readout signals are shown in Fig. 8(b). The top signal in the figure shows the time variation of the write-in light intensity: the pulse signals with the third quarter period appeared only in Figure 8. Readout signals from Device-I with (a) no rite-in light and (b) synchronously intermittent write-in light. Upper signals in (a) and (b) show waveforms of extemally applied ac voltage (3 Kv) and write-in light, respectively. Lower signals in (a) and (b) show readout signals. every alternate periods of ac voltage. The bottom signal shows the readout signal intensity from Device-1. The readout signal intensities in the periods with no write-in light recovered to the same as those shown the bottom in Fig. 8(a). On the other hand, due to the effect of the write-in light, the readout signal intensities just after the write-in light pulse became lower than those in the periods with no write-in light. Thus, it has been confirmed that the recorded images can be completely erased in the half period in V&gt;0. Furthermore, the above experimental results suggest that the GaAs-PROM can be operated with a larger cycle than 500 Hz. 3.2 Dependence of sensitivity on write-in light intensity First, it is shown by the following experiments that the continuous illumination of the write-in light is accepted. The write-in light pulses (wavelength: 850 rim and peak intensity: 940 P W/cm2 with two kinds of width were separately illuminated on Device-i delaying their starting times t , from the starting time t of the negative ac voltage, under continuous illumination of the erasing light. The widths of the write-in pulses were the quarter and the half periods of the applied ac voltage. respectively. The variations of the readout signal intensities versus the delay time of t w from t were measured and are shown in Fig. 9, where the delay times are expressed using the phase differences. From the results in the figure, it is seen that (1) the readout signal intensity monotonically decreased as the increase of the write-in light energy exposed on the device between the time t and the starting time t of the readout light pulse, (2) the write-in lights before tn and after t hardly affected the readout signal intensity, and (3) the recorded signal fairly decayed from the end time of the write-in pulse until the time t . Then the continuous illumination of the write-in light realizes the efficient write-in and simplifies the control of SLM system. The sensitivity curves of GaAs-PROMs were measured under the continuous illuminations of the erasing light and the write-in lights (wavelength: 780 nm and various intensities) from a LD by applying ac voltages with amplitude of 3 kV and 6 kV to Device-I and Device-2, respectively. The variations of the readout signal intensities versus the write-in light intensity are shown in Fig. 10, where the vertical axis is normalized by the maximum output signal intensity obtained with zero intensity of the write-in light. The experimental results when Device-1 was driven by ac voltages with 500 Hz and 250 Hz are shown by the marks * and C. respectively, and the results when Device-2 driven with ac voltage with 500 Hz are shown by the markU. When the frequency of ac voltage was 500 Hz, the write-in light of intensities 400 and 130 W/cm2 were required to reduce the output signal intensity to 1/e for Device-i and Device-2, respectively. Device-2 with thicker GaAs crystal plate became more sensitive. The effective exposures corresponding these write-in light are 200 nJ/cm and 65 nJ/cm , respectively. and these devices are very high sensitive. When Device-i was driven by the ac voltage of 250 Hz, the write-in light intensity of 230 p W/cm2 was required to reduce the output signal intensity to 1/e. This required write-in light intensity became around a half of that at the frequency of 500 Hz, because the effective exposure time of the write-in light became the two times. Figure 9. The sensitivity dependence of the phase difference between starting time t of negative ac voltage and starting time tw of write-in pulse. The zero phase difference corresponded that the write-in light pulse started at the time tn . The experimental results for the write-in light pulses with widths of T/2 and T/4 are shown by ( * and solid curve) and ( 0 and dashed curve), respectively. Vertical axis was normalized by the peak intensity with no write-in light. Figure 10. Sensitivity curve of GaAs-PROM versus write-in light intensity under continuous illumination of the erasing and the write-in lights. The experimental results of Device-I driven by ac voltages of 3 kV with frequency of 500 Hz and 250 Hz are shown by marks 0 and 0 , respectively, and the results of Device-2 driven by ac voltage of 6 kV with frequency of 500 Hz are shown by mark U . Vertical axis was normalized by the peak intensity with no write-in light. Figure 11. Example of readout images from Device-1. In the experiments, we obtained the maximum contrast ratio of lager than 200:1 in the devices. The maximum contrast ratio would be improved by removing the birefringence in GaAs plate. 3.3 Resolution of readout image An image of the US air force resolution test chart was recorded in Device-1 and Device-2, and read out by the pulse light described above. The applied ac voltage was 3 kV at 500 Hz and the write-in light (wavelength: 780 nm) was continuously illuminated. An example of the readout images from Device-I is shown in Fig. 11. The image was taken by a CCD TV camera without an infrared filter and was a result of summarizing up about eight images sequentially read out. The limiting resolutions of readout images were about 10 lp/mm in both Device-1 and Deice-2. The value of resolution is smaller than that in BSO-PROM. This weak point will be recovered by the possibility of a GaAs-PROM with a large useful image area. The modulation transfer characteristics will be searched in near future.</p>
<p>4. Conclusion A PROM device using GaAs for high speed operation was proposed, and following properties were experimentally confirmed: a higher frame rate operation (over than 500 Hz), higher sensitivity (required exposure smaller than 200 nJ/cm2 ), and a limiting spatial resolution (about 10 lp/mm). In addition, the GaAs-PROM becomes equivalent to a simple capacitively coupled structure and is enable to construct inexpensive and compact size optical systems because we can use LDs and/or LEDs as all light sources in the systems. If a LD lasing at 1300 nm for a readout light source and GaAs plate with no birefringence were used, a higher performance system with higher contrast ratio of the readout image would be realized. The detailed mechanism which limits the frame rate in the GaAs-PROM could not be investigated because of complexity of the influence of carrier mobility in GaAs in a strong electric field. But, this problem is the intrinsic problem in the GaAs-PROM requiring a strong electric field. GaAs has a negative differential mobility and this is not always the best semiconductor material for making a PROM device. So, we will further investigate other semiconductor materials, such as InP, which have the larger threshold than that of GaAs in the negative differential mobility. Lastly, this study was partially supported by Special Coordination Funds for Promoting Science and Technology from Japanese Science and Technology Agency through its program of " Research on new material development based on nano-space lab."</p></body>
<back>
<ref-list>
<ref id="r1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Nisenson</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Iwasa</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name></person-group>, "<article-title>Real time optical processing with Bi<sub>12</sub> SiO<sub>20</sub></article-title>," <source>Appl Opt</source> <volume>11</volume>, <fpage>2760</fpage>-<lpage>2767</lpage>, (<year>1972</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/AO.11.002760</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Iwasa</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Feinleib</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>The PROM device in optical processing system</article-title>, <source>Opt Eng</source>, <volume>13</volume>, <fpage>235</fpage>-<lpage>242</lpage>, (<year>1974</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1117/12.7971700</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Sparague</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Nisenson</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>The PROM-A status report</article-title>, <source>Opt Eng</source>, <volume>17</volume>, <fpage>256</fpage>-<lpage>266</lpage>, (<year>1978</year>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Hebbron</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Makh</surname><given-names>S.S.</given-names></name></person-group>, "<article-title>Development of gallium arsenide-based spatial light modulators</article-title>," <source>Proc SPIE</source> <volume>825</volume>, <fpage>19</fpage>-<lpage>23</lpage>, (<year>1987</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1117/12.941980</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Armitage</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Thackara</surname><given-names>J.I.</given-names></name><name><surname>Eades</surname><given-names>W.D.</given-names></name></person-group>, "<article-title>Gallium arsenide photoaddressed liquid-crystal spatial light modulator</article-title>," <source>Proc SPIE</source> <volume>936</volume>, <fpage>56</fpage>-<lpage>67</lpage>, (<year>1988</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1117/12.946920</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="confproc"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Fukuzawa</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yamada</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>Birefringence induced by residual strain in optically isotropic III - V compound crystals</article-title> in <conf-name>Technical Digest of International Symposium on Polarization Analysis and Applications to Device Technology</conf-name> (<conf-loc>Yokohama</conf-loc>, <year>1996</year>), <fpage>146</fpage>-<lpage>147</lpage></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r7"><label>7</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ruch</surname><given-names>J.G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kino</surname><given-names>G.S.</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>Measurement of the velocity-field characteristics of Gallium Arsenide</article-title>, <source>Appl Phys Lett</source>, <volume>10</volume>, <fpage>40</fpage>-<lpage>42</lpage>, (<year>1967</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.1754837</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r8"><label>8</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Smith</surname><given-names>P.M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Inoue</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Frey</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>Electron velocity in Si and GaAs at very high electric field</article-title>, <source>Appl Phys Lett</source>, <volume>37</volume>, <fpage>797</fpage>-<lpage>798</lpage>, (<year>1980</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.92078</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></book-part></book-part-wrapper>
