<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
<collection-meta collection-type="conf">
<conference content-type="conf-name"><conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name><conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym></conference>
<conference content-type="conf-other-meta"><conf-date content-type="start">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-date content-type="end">
<day>19</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-loc>Nevada, 
<country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc></conference></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
<title-group>
<title>Integration and Packaging Techniques</title>
<alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/></title-group></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
<title-group>
<title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title></title-group>
<volume-in-collection>
<volume-number>14</volume-number>
<volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title></volume-in-collection></collection-meta>
<book-meta>
<book-title-group>
<book-title>Spatial Light Modulators</book-title></book-title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Burdge</surname><given-names>Geoffrey</given-names></name></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>Sadik C.</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group>
<pub-date publication-format="electronic">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></pub-date></book-meta>
<book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
<book-part-meta>
<title-group>
<title>Packaging Optics for Smart Pixels</title></title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Ford</surname><given-names>Joseph E.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Fainman</surname><given-names>Yeshayahu</given-names></name><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff"><sup>2</sup></xref></contrib>
<aff id="aff1">
<label>1</label>Bell Laboratories, Lucent Technologies, 101 Crawfords Corner Road, Holmdel NJ 07733</aff>
<aff id="aff2">
<label>2</label>University of California San Diego, Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, La Jolla CA 92073</aff></contrib-group>
<elocation-id>72</elocation-id>
<permissions>
<copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
<copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
<copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
<license license-type="open-access">
<license-p>closed</license-p></license></permissions>
<abstract>
<p>As optoelectronic devices move from the research laboratory towards the factory, optical packaging issues become increasingly important in developing a viable technology. Practical optoelectronic systems will have to be simple, inexpensive and reliable.</p></abstract>
<counts>
<book-page-count count="3"/></counts></book-part-meta>
<body>
<p>Introduction As optoelectronic devices move from the research laboratory towards the factory, optical packaging issues become increasingly important in developing a viable technology. Practical optoelectronic systems will have to be simple, inexpensive and reliable. Holographicopticalelements(HOE),andespecially computergeneratedHOE(CGH),offerunprecedented controloverthephaseprofileofanincidentbeam, allowing the creation arbitrary aspheres and multiple beamsplitting. CGH have proven their use in optoelectronic systems for spot array generation and interconnection. But this technology has already made it out of the lab: hybrid refractive and diffractive optics are starting to be manufactured for products such as lightweight binoculars, laser collimators, and others. Here we will discuss the next generation of holographic optics, which add selectivity in polarization or wavelength and allows great flexibility in optical system design.</p>
<p>CGH Design and Fabrication A conventional kinoform CGH is a 2-D phase profile which transforms the input light (e.g., a plane wave) into the desired output (e.g. an array of points). The desired continuous phase profile is first computed, then reduced to a minimum of data by pixellation, truncation to modulo 2t, and quantization into discrete values. This data array is then used to fabricate the hologram. Apolarization-orcolor-selectiveCGHissimilarin functiontoacon nalphase-only kinoformi GH, except that the element must create a different phase profile for each of the two orthogonal linear polarizations or colors that illuminate the hologram. This is made possible by use ofmaterialbirefringence, for polarization selective uGH, orchromatic dispersion, for color-selectiveU GH. Polarization-selective CGH were first fabricated in birefringent lithium niobate using a two-substrate design. described in reference 1. Both substrates are patterned and etched, then joined face-to-face, aligned, and joined with UV-curing epoxy to yield an element like that shown in Figure 1. The independent etch profile of the two substrates allows control of the relative phase between orthogonal polarizations transmitted through each pixel, and the absolute phase of the pixel with respect to its neighbors. Fig.1:Assembled2substratepolarizationselectiveCGH Binary holograms fabricated with this technique yielded a diffraction efficiency of 25&#x00025; and polarization contrast ratio off10:1.A four-level phase hologramsproduced a diffraction efficienc f 4or rao o 0: The theoretical diffraction efficiencies of, for example, 80&#x00025; for a four-level phase hologram have not been demonstrated due to fabrication errors, especially in the alignment between the two substrates. An alternative fabrication technique uses a single birefringent substrate with a multiple order delay (MOD) kinoform CGH. The concept is simple. Suppose a phase delay of 7 is required for horizontal (H) polarization, and 0 for the vertical (V) polarization. In a birefringent substrate, an etch depth sufficient to achieve a delay of exactly i for H polarization would produce a delay of t- for V polarization. Tripling the etch depth yields 3i for H and 3(n-6) for V, but the modulus of this delay is 1 for H and -36 for V. If the material is such that (m+1)6 is approximately t, where m is an even integer, then a binary phase hologram visible only for H-polarized light can be fabricated. Such a hologram, fabricated in YVO4, produced a close-to-theoretically-limited diffraction efficiency of 39&#x00025; and a polarization contrast ratio of 33:1 &#x0005B;2&#x0005D;. An entirely different approach to a single-substrate polarization-selective CGH is to use artificial form birefringence, where a surface relief profile with features much smaller than the optical wavelength creates a polarization-dependent index. &#x0005B;3&#x0005D; The concepts of polarization-selective CGH can all be directly translated to obtain color-selective CGH by substituting material dispersion for birefringence. For example, a MOD binary-phase CGH designed to separate 1.3 and 1.55 im light was fabricated with a 8 am deep binary grating etched into BK7 glass &#x0005B;4&#x0005D;. The grating diffracted 1.55 jm light with 39&#x00025; in the +1 and -1 orders and transmitted less than 1&#x00025; in the zeroth order. The same element, illuminated at 1.3 pm, transmitted 83&#x00025; in the zeroth order and diffracted less than 1.2&#x00025; in any one of the diffraction orders.</p>
<p>Optoelectronic Packaging To illustrate the potential application of polarization- and color-selective CGH in optoelectronic systems, we will describe three specific examples. OE-VLSI Modulator Optics To see how such elements can dramatically reduce the size, complexity and cost of packaged optoelectronic systems, consider a modulator-based OE-VLSI device &#x0005B;5&#x0005D; with quantum well modulators integrated onto silicon electronics. Typical optics for efficient operation of such devices is showninFigure2.ACGHspotarraygeneratoris illuminated by a collimated, linearly polarized power beam. The diffracted beams are focused by a lens onto modulators on the chip surface through a polarizing beam splitter and a quarter wave plate. Light reflecting from the modulators is deflected on the second pass through the beam splitter and senttotheoutput. Fig. 2: Smart pixel with CGH spot array generator Figure3showshowthesamefunctionalityisobtained with a polarization-selective CGH which acts as an off-axis lenslet array for one polarization yet is transparent to the orthogonal polarization. On the forward pass, the CGH creates an array of spots focused straight into each modulator. The reflected output, however, with polarization rotated by two passes through a quarter wave plate, is unperturbed by the CGH and heads straight out from the device. This package can be integrated directly onto the OE- VLSI chip to produce a robust and convenient component. Fig. 3: Smart pixel with pol-selective CGH lenslets Multistage Interconnection Network In a passive optical network, data is carried from end to end without conversion to electronics by setting up an optical circuit-switchedpath.Thedatarateisnotlimitedbythe network switch response time, since it flows through the open path. Figure 4 shows the topology of an optical multistage interconnection network (MIN) which uses layers of binary switching elements interconnected by a predetermined network architecture. The potential of role for polarization selective CGH in building optoelectronic MINs is discussed in detail in reference 6. The basic concept is that each layer of the networkisimplementedwithasmartpixelarray,where each pixel includes a modulator which can rotate the polarization of an incident data beam. Such modulators have been fabricated using liquid crystals as well as ferroelectric PLZT as the electro-optic medium. Figure 5 shows how polarization selective CGH are used to make a self-routing 2x2 MIN switch. A transmissive modulator array has CGH on each side. Two optical inputs enter with orthogonal polarizations. The first CGH combines the inputs and focuses them into the modulator. The modulator either exchanges polarizations, or not, depending on the switch setting. The output is then routed to the appropriate destination in the next stage by a second CGH. A small-scale system demonstration of a 4x4 switch using three cascaded stages of arrayed polarization-selective CGH is described in reference 6. Fig. 4: Multistage interconnection network topology Modulator Fig. 5: Polarization-based 2x2 switch Coarse Wavelength Division Multiplexing Coarsedemultiplexingofdatatransmittedatboththe telecommunications wavelengths 1.3 and 1.55 tm is often accomplished using a dielectric notch filter placed between collimating and focus lenses. The resulting package, however, directs the demultiplexed output into two separate locations. For some applications, the demultiplexed beams can be routed into a single optoelectronic chip. Figure 6 shows an experimental result from &#x0005B;4&#x0005D; which demonstrates how a simple optical system with a color- selective CGH can direct the demultiplexed output onto the same output plane. With micro-optics, such a system can be made extremely compact, simple and inexpensive, because only a single chip alignment is necessary Fig. 6: Coarse A-denultiplexing with color-selective CGH</p>
<p>Conclusions We described the basic concepts of polarization- and color- selective CGH components, and described examples to illustrate their potential role in optoelectronic smart pixel' packaging. Such components represent a valuable new tool for developing compact and reliable optoelectronic systems.</p>
<p>Acknowlegdments The authors appreciate the contributions of Dr. Ashok Krishnamoorthy of Bell Laboratories for architecture and systems and Dr. Fang Xu of UCSD for CGH fabrication.</p></body>
<back>
<ref-list>
<ref id="r1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ford</surname><given-names>J.E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Urquhart</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Fainman</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Polarization selective computer generated holograms</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Optics Letters</source> <volume>18</volume>, <fpage>456</fpage>-<lpage>458</lpage>, (<year>1992</year>).<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/OL.18.000456</pub-id></mixed-citation><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ford</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Fainman</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Polarization selective computer generated holograms: Design, fabrication and applications</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Applied Optics</source> <volume>34</volume>, <fpage>256</fpage>-<lpage>266</lpage>, (<year>1995</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/AO.34.000256</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Tyan</surname><given-names>R-C F. Xu</given-names></name><name><surname>Fainman</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ford</surname><given-names>J.E.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Single-substrate birefringent computer generated holograms</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Optics Letters</source> <volume>21</volume>, <fpage>516</fpage>-<lpage>518</lpage>, (<year>1996</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/OL.21.000516</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Tyan</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>P.C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Fainman</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Cheng</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Scherer</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Form birefringence of periodic dielectric nanostructures</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Optics Letters</source> <volume>20</volume>, <fpage>2457</fpage>-<lpage>59</lpage>, (<year>1995</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/OL.20.002457</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ford</surname><given-names>J.E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Fainman</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Wavelength-selective planar holograms</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Optics Letters</source> <volume>21</volume>, <fpage>80</fpage>-<lpage>82</lpage>, (<year>1996</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/OL.21.000080</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Goossen</surname><given-names>K.W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Cunningham</surname><given-names>J.E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jan</surname><given-names>W. Y</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>GaAs 850 nm modulators solder-bonded to silicon</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>IEEE Photonics Letters</source> <volume>5</volume>, <fpage>776</fpage>-<lpage>778</lpage>, (<year>1993</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1109/68.229803</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Krishnamoorthy</surname><given-names>A.V.</given-names></name><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ford</surname><given-names>J.E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Fainman</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Polarization-controlled multistage switch based on polarization-selective birefringent computer generated holograms</article-title>&#x0201D; <source>Applied Optics</source> <volume>36</volume>(<issue>5</issue>), <month>Feb</month> <day>10</day>th, <year>1997</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/AO.36.000997</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></book-part></book-part-wrapper>
