<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
<collection-meta collection-type="conf">
<conference content-type="conf-name"><conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name><conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym></conference>
<conference content-type="conf-other-meta"><conf-date content-type="start">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-date content-type="end">
<day>19</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-loc>Nevada, 
<country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc></conference></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
<title-group>
<title>VLSI-based SLMs</title>
<alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/></title-group></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
<title-group>
<title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title></title-group>
<volume-in-collection>
<volume-number>14</volume-number>
<volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title></volume-in-collection></collection-meta>
<book-meta>
<book-title-group>
<book-title>Spatial Light Modulators</book-title></book-title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Burdge</surname><given-names>Geoffrey</given-names></name></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>Sadik C.</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group>
<pub-date publication-format="electronic">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></pub-date></book-meta>
<book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
<book-part-meta>
<title-group>
<title>Hybrid Electronic/Photonic 2D Neural Array Using InGaAs/AlGaAs Multiple Quantum Well Modulators Flip-Chip Bonded to a CMOS Si Analog Control Chip</title></title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Cartland</surname><given-names>Robert F.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Madhukar</surname><given-names>Anupam</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Ananthanarayanan</surname><given-names>Kartik</given-names></name><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff"><sup>2</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Nasiatka</surname><given-names>Patrick</given-names></name><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff"><sup>2</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Su</surname><given-names>Dennis</given-names></name><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff"><sup>2</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Tanguay</surname><given-names>Armand R.</given-names><suffix>Jr.</suffix></name><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff"><sup>2</sup></xref></contrib>
<aff id="aff1">
<label>1</label>Photonic Materials and Devices Laboratory</aff>
<aff id="aff2">
<label>2</label>Optical Materials and Devices Laboratory University of Southern California Los Angeles, CA 90089</aff></contrib-group>
<elocation-id>51</elocation-id>
<permissions>
<copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
<copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
<copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
<license license-type="open-access">
<license-p>closed</license-p></license></permissions>
<abstract>
<p>A hybrid, flip-chip bonded, III-V/Si 2D <italic>smart </italic>spatial light modulator (SLM) has been designed and fabricated for use in photonic neural networks. The SLM consists of a 16 &#x000D7; 16 array of <italic>neuron units </italic>spaced with a 100 &#x003BC;m pitch. Each <italic>neuron unit </italic>contains Si CMOS control electronics, two Si photodiode detectors and two III-V multiple quantum well modulators, for dual input/dual output. The 2D arrays of InGaAs/AlGaAs multiple quantum well modulators operate at 980 &#x000B1; 1 nm (with a 2D uniformity of &#x000B1; 0.3 nm) and show an average contrast ratio of 13:1 at &#x02212;9 V applied bias. The analog Si detection/modulator control chip provides a &#x02212;2 to &#x02212;9 V nonlinear sigmoidal response to the difference in light intensity at the two detectors. The III-V/Si hybrid device is flip-chip bonded using a nondeleterious <italic>cold weld </italic>indium bump process. The device is an important component for high performance photonic artificial neural networks.</p></abstract>
<kwd-group kwd-group-type="OCIS">
<title>OCIS codes</title>
<kwd>Spatial light modulators</kwd>
<kwd>Smart Pixels</kwd>
<kwd>Semiconductor MQW</kwd>
<kwd>Flip-chip bonding</kwd>
<kwd>Optical neural networks</kwd></kwd-group>
<counts>
<book-page-count count="6"/></counts></book-part-meta>
<body>
<p>Introduction Artificial neural networks (ANNs) have been used to solve problems not easily addressed via traditional algorithmic programming. Example problems include pattern recognition in noisy environments and system optimization under difficult-to-predict conditions. Artificial neural Artiicil networks neralnetwrksbase based on on a a hybrid. hyrid electronic/photonic technology can potentially benefit from the weighted interconnection of large numbers of neuron units. Photonic neural network architectures have been designed that incorporate vertical cavity surface emitting laser arrays for parallel input, hybrid electronic/photonic SLMs for implementation of neuron unit arrays with optical I/O, and photorefractive volume holographic optical elements for adaptive weighted interconnections &#x0005B;1&#x0005D;. Within such architectures, the hybrid SLM must be capable of the parallel detection of the weighted and summed input signals followed by a nonlinear neural-like transformation. Figure 1. Hybrid InGaAs/AlGaAs MQW SLM with silicon drive electronic chip. A single dual input/dual output neuron unit pixel is also shown. The hybrid neuron unit array described herein consistsofa16x16arrayofneuron-likepixels. Each pixelhastwoIll-Vsemiconductormultiplequantumwell modulators, two Si photodiode detectors, and associated Si CMOS VLSI signal processing and modulator drive circuitry &#x0005B;1&#x0005D;. The modulators are fabricated via molecular crutyMTEoulators bratevaoecla beaeitxythogae was ssbstr fabricated Teichip through the MOSIS foundry service &#x0005B;21 using the 1.2 gm HP scalable CMOS n-well process. The GaAs modulator chip is flip-chip bonded to the Si detection/control chip using a cold weld indium bump process. In the current front-side-illuminated implementation, the detectors are addressed and the modulators readout through the GaAs substrate of the hybridized structure (Fig. 1). The device is designed to operate at 980 nm to allow transparency of the GaAs substrate, sufficient detection by the Si photodiodes, and compatibility with available semiconductor laser sources. For the neuron unit array to function properly, the operating wavelength of 980 nm must be uniform over all of the individual modulators within the 2D array. The choice of 980 nm also allows for a back-side-illuminated implementation, with detector addressing through the Si substrate.</p>
<p>Modulator Design and Fabrication The GaAs chip contains the 2D array of light modulators. The design of the modulators has been optimized for use in the flip-chip bonded hybrid Si/GaAs neuron unit array. However, the device is also potentially useful in other photonic systems employing SLMs such as joint transform correlators and optical crossbar switches. Figure. 2 The structure of a single electrically-driven InGaAs/AGaAs MQW light modulator. The light modulators employ III-V semiconductor materials grown using molecular beam epitaxy (MBE) on GaAs substrates. The structure includes an InGaAs/AlGaAs p-i-n multiple quantum well (MQW) region (980 nm operation) within an inverted asymmetric Fabry-Perot cavity (I-AFPC) (Fig. 2). The I-AFPC consists of an MBE-grown low-reflectance front mirror and a post-growth-fabricated high-reflectance back mirror. Such I-AFPC modulators are known to offer high contrast modulation, but fabrication of large 2D arrays has been a challenge &#x0005B;3&#x0005D;. Large 2D arrays of high contrast I-AFPC modulators have been demonstrated in the lattice-matched GaAs/AlGaAs system typically operating at 860 nm &#x0005B;4&#x0005D;. At this wavelength, the GaAs substrate is not transparent, and additional post growth processing steps such as substrate removal and/or device lift off are required. We have recently demonstrated high contrast uniform 2D arrays operating at 980 nm using strained InGaAs/AlGaAs MQWs &#x0005B;5&#x0005D;. The I-AFPC is designed to create incomplete destructive interference at the Fabry-Perot operating wavelength of 980 nm by means of unequal mirror reflectances. Voltage-controlled absorption modulation in the InGaAs/AlGaAs MQW region occurs at the operating wavelength via the well-understood quantum confined Stark effect &#x0005B;6&#x0005D;. By increasing the absorption in the cavity, the back mirror reflectance is effectively &#x0201C;matched&#x0201D; to the front mirror reflectance, switching the net device reflectance from a high to a low value. To optimize the design of the modulator, isolated versions of the InxGal-xAs/AlGal-yAs p-i(MQW)-n region (typically 30 or 35 pairs) using 8.8 nm In0.20Ga 8oAs wells and 8.1 nm Al 0.26 Ga0.74As barriers were grown. Absorption spectra of the p-i(MQW)-n structure under various reverse biases were studied. These layer thickness values and compositions were found to show high quality electro-absorption modulation behavior near 980 nm &#x0005B;7&#x0005D;. The isolated MQW shows optimal absorption modulation behavior at a wavelength 17.5 nm longer than the unbiased exciton wavelength. At this operating wavelength, the absorption strength per well (the product of the absorption coefficient and the well thickness) is observed to be 0.0045 at an applied bias of 0.26 V per well. 'To keep the operating voltage below 10V, 35 quantum wells are used. Keeping the number of wells to a minimum also reduces the total strain in the lattice- mismatched InGaAs/AlGaAs system. This results in a reduction in threading misfit dislocations that degrade deviceperformance. Thelimitednumberofquantum wells, however, implies that the difference in reflectance values between the front and back mirrors in the I-AFPC cannot be made too large or the device will not completely turn off. For a back mirror reflectance of 97&#x00025;, the front mirror reflectance must be at least 70&#x00025; to achieve high contrast modulation. A 6.5 pair AAs/GaAs distributed Bragg reflector (DBR) was selected for the front mirror that was theoretically and experimentally determined to give a reflectance of over 70&#x00025; across a 70 nm wavelength range. A thin film silver layer is used for the back mirror/electrical contact, giving a theoretical maximum reflectance of 97&#x00025;. Metal coatings allow combining the function of mirror/electrical contact within a single structure. Combining these functions within a single structure eliminates processing steps, eases hybridization, and increases the device fill-factor compared to the alternative of a separate mirror and electrical contact. Control of the operating wavelength associated with the Fabry-Perot cavity to within I nm cannot be reproducibly achieved using MBE growth without in-situ monitoring. To overcome this difficulty, we have developed methods of post-growth tuning of the Fabry- Perot cavity. One method uses a slow wet etch to tune the cavity to the desired operating wavelength. Etch tuning is done before deposition of the back mirror; thus, phase effects associated with the back mirror must be carefully considered during the tuning process &#x0005B;7&#x0005D;. An alternative method we have explored is unique to the use of dielectric DBRs as the back high-reflectance mirror. By adjusting the thickness of the DBR layers, the overall phase of the I-AFPC can be adjusted &#x0005B;8&#x0005D;.</p>
<p>Modulator Array Results Uniform 2D light modulator arrays have been fabricated showing 13:1 &#x000B1; 4:1 contrast ratios, at -9.0 V applied bias (Fig. 3). The typical contrast ratio FWHM is about 3 nm and the FW at 90&#x00025; of maximum is about 2 nm (Fig. 4). Figure 3. On-state and off-state spectra of a typical light modulating pixel. The operating wavelength is 980.7 nm with an overall one-sigma uniformity of 0.3 nm over an area of 2.5 x 2.5 mm 2 (Fig. 4). Thus, all of the devices show high contrast modulation at a single common wavelength, Despite the strained MQW, no reliability problems such as a large number of shorted devices have been observed. We attribute this to using the fairly low number of 35 quantum wells. Figure 4. Typical contrast ratio and optical bandwidth of a pixel within the 2D array. Some devices show a CR over 30:1. Figure 5. The wavelength at the minimum reflectance under a fixed -9 V applied bias is plotted across the 2D device area. An evenly distributed subset (about 25&#x00025;) of the pixels were characterized. The on-state reflectance is 35 + 5&#x00025; over the 2D array. Experimental and theoretical evidence indicates that the optical insertion loss within the device is due to three causes: absorption in the GaAs substrate, transmission through the GaAs/silver mirror interface, and residual absorption within the MQW region. In this case, the separation between the zero-biased exciton wavelength and the 980 nm operating wavelength was smaller than the desired 17.5 nm. The slight fluctuation (&#x000B1; 3 nm) in the exciton wavelength is limited by our ability to control the InGaAs alloy composition (&#x000B1; 0.5&#x00025;). Theoretical and experimental investigations are underway to explore the tradeoffs associated with metal and dielectric DBR back mirrors to improve device performance. Metal mirrors offer the advantage of playing the dual role of mirror/electrical contact, thus simplifying device processing and maximizing the modulator fill factor. Dielectric mirrors offer the advantage of post-growth cavity tuning as mentioned above. Dielectric DBRs could also raise the back mirror reflectance to higher values, reducing the optical insertion loss. If the mirror reflectance is too high, however, it becomes difficult to turn the device off by biasing only 35 wells. Additional quantum wells and slightly higher drive voltages might be required. Si Analog Control Chip The analog Si IC performs a nonlinear sigmoidal input/output transformation similar to the transfer characteristics of biological neurons. Each pixel in the 16 x 16 array contains a pair of photodetectors to detect the dual-rail input signal. The control circuit produces a pair of sigmoidal modulator drive voltages in responses to the difference in intensity received by the two photodetectors. When the intensity at detector one is high compared to detector two (large intensity difference), modulator two receives a large drive voltage. The sigmoidal voltage response saturates at -9V, turning off the normally-on modulator. Similarly, when the intensity at detector two is sufficiently high compared to detector one, modulator one is switched off. The dual-rail input intensity undergoes a sigmoidal transformation that is read out at the two modulators as a dual-rail output optical amplitude. The operational theory of the Si IC follows. The Si control chip converts low-level optical signals incident on the two integrated photodiode detectors into large amplitude differential output voltages that drive the modulators &#x0005B;1&#x0005D;. The circuit performs the differencing as a current; cascoded current mirrors are used for high accuracy. The disadvantage of this design is that the power consumption can be large for high input signals, as multiple copies of the input current are created throughout the circuit. The advantage, however, is that the circuit has the potential for high-speed operation, because the voltage levels at most internal nodes do not vary significantly. The few nodes with wide voltage swings also have large currents to quickly charge/discharge the capacitance. Figure 6. Schematic of the operational stages of a single processing element. Each element contains two cross-connected differential input/single-ended output comparator circuits. The optoelectronic processing elements contain two cross-connected differential input/single-ended output comparator circuits. A schematic diagram of the operational stages of a single pixel is shown in Fig. 6. The circuit consists of five stages: a photodiode stage, a &#x0201C;keep-alive&#x0201D; current source, a current mirroring stage, a current-to-voltage conversion stage, and an output buffering stage. The photodiode stage provides detection of the two optical input signals. The stage contains a pair of reverse- biased photodiodes consisting of an n-diffusion region in the p-substrate material. This photodiode design is different from the more commonly used p-diffused n-well design. The n-diffused p-well design allows for increased photocurrent collection efficiency within the p-type bulk substrate. Increased collection efficiency is necessary, as the responsivity of silicon is not optimally efficient at the 980 nm operating wavelength. Since the detectors are not electrically isolated from each other, the amount of crosstalk between adjacent detectors is a concern. A p+ guard ring surrounding the n-diffusion layer of each photodiode region is used to reduce the amount of crosstalk between detectors. The &#x0201C;keep-alive&#x0201D; current source stage is used to keep the current mirror stage &#x0201C;alive&#x0201D; when no input signal is present on the photodiodes. This is achieved by keeping a small amount of current present in the current mirrors, thus preventing the current mirrors from shutting off. Shutting off the current mirrors would result in a significant speed penalty. The current mirror stage consists of groups of current mirrors that generate two opposite sign copies of the input current. One copy goes to the channel I input and the other to the channel 2 input of the summing node of the current-to-voltage stage. At the current-to-voltage stage, copies of input currents generated from the photodetector stage are differenced and compared to a threshold value. The voltage at this node swings high or low, with a nearly ideal sigmoidal response characteristic, depending on whether the input difference is above or below threshold. The final stage is an output buffer stage. The wide voltage swing node of the previous stage has a high impedance and is unsuitable for driving a load. This stage buffers the output voltage to provide a low driving impedance. The analog artificial neuron integrated circuit was fabricated through the MOSIS foundry service &#x0005B;2&#x0005D; using the 1.2 pm HP scalable CMOS n-well process. The chip has demonstrated a 2 to 9 V sigmoidal large-signal response at frequencies up to 100 kHz, and a small-signal response in excess of I MHz test equipment limited. Spice simulations indicate a small-signal response in excess of 4 MHz. The estimated chip power dissipation is 2 mW per pixel or about 0.5 W per chip.</p>
<p>Hybrid Device Integration A cold weld indium bump flip-chip bonding process has been developed and used for the hybrid integration of the GaAs modulator and the Si control chip with indium bumps fabricated on both chips. First, the chips are coated with a thick ( 14 im) photoresist. The thick photoresist is patterned using a contact mask aligner with standard photolithographic processing techniques. The die are placed in a vacuum chamber, where thermally evaporated indium is deposited on the surface. When the photoresist is lifted off, an array of indium bumps approximately 8 pm high is left on the surface of the silicon die. The indium bumps form the contacts between the Si die and the corresponding indium bumps on the GaAs modulator array. A visible flip-chip bonder-aligner (Research Devices, Model M8A, Piscataway, NJ) is employed to mate the indium-bumped silicon CMOS die and the GaAs modulators. Figure 7 shows the 16 x 16 neuron unit array analog Si IC with indium bumps. The flip chip bonding is performed using a near-room-temperature cold weld bonding procedure that avoids heating the modulator and Si substrates. No deleterious effects associated with the flip-chip bonding procedure on the Si chip or modulator performance have been observed.</p>
<p>Conclusion We have fabricated a hybrid III-V/Si flip-chip bonded 2D smart spatial light modulator array for use in photonic artificial neural networks. Each pixel in the 16 x 16 array contains two Si photodiode detectors and two InGaAs/AIGaAs MQW light modulators for dual input/output. In addition, each pixel contains two cross- connected differential input/single-ended output comparator circuits. The circuit provides a nonlinear sigmoidal response to the difference in intensity at the two detectors. The 2D array of InGaAs/AlGaAs multiple quantum well modulators operates at 980 &#x000B1; rnm (with a 2D uniformity of &#x000B1;0.3 nm) and shows an average contrast ratio of 13:1 at -9 V applied bias. The III-V/Si hybridized device is flip-chip bonded using a cold weld indium bump process. Work is underway to assess the performance of the hybrid device. Figure 7. The 16 x 16 neuron array analog Si IC with indium bumps. The lower micrograph shows indium bumps on the light modulator array prior to flipchipbonding. Acknowledgments This research program has been supported in part by the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency (ANNT and ULTRA programs), National Science Foundation Engineering Research Center program (Integrated Media Systems Center), TRW, Inc., and Xerox Corporation.</p></body>
<back>
<ref-list>
<ref id="r1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Jenkins</surname><given-names>B.K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Tanguay</surname><given-names>A.R.</given-names><suffix>Jr</suffix></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Photonic Implementations of Neural Networks</article-title>&#x0201D;, Chapter 9 in <source>Neural Networks for Signal Processing</source>, <person-group person-group-type="editor"><name><surname>Kosko</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name></person-group>, Ed, <publisher-name>Prentice Hall</publisher-name>, <publisher-loc>Englewood Cliffs, NJ</publisher-loc>, (<year>1992</year>)<fpage>287</fpage>-<lpage>382</lpage></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r2"><label>21</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Oxide</surname><given-names>Metal</given-names></name></person-group> <source>Semiconductor Information Service Users Manual University of Southern California</source>/ <publisher-name>Information Sciences Institute</publisher-name>, <publisher-loc>Marina del Rey, CA</publisher-loc>.</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Law</surname><given-names>K-K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Merz</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Coldren</surname><given-names>L. A.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Effect of layer thickness variations on the performance of asymmetric Fabry-Perot reflection modulators</article-title>&#x0201D; <source>J Appl Phys</source> <volume>72</volume>(<issue>3</issue>), (<year>1992</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.351758</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Worchesky</surname><given-names>T.L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ritter</surname><given-names>K.J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Martin</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lane</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Large arrays of spatial light modulators hybridized to silicon integrated circuits</article-title>&#x0201D; <source>Appl Opt</source> <volume>35</volume>(<issue>8</issue>), (<year>1996</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/AO.35.001180</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="confproc"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Cartland</surname><given-names>R.F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Madhukar</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>High contrast, large area, inverted, 2D spatial light modulators for flip-chip bonding to silicon microelectronic driver chips</article-title>&#x0201D;, Paper <fpage content-type="conf-paper">TuCC3</fpage>, <conf-name>Optical Society of America Annual Meeting</conf-name>, <conf-loc>Rochester, NY</conf-loc>, (<year>1996</year>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Boyd</surname><given-names>G.D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Miller</surname><given-names>D.A.B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chemla</surname><given-names>D.S.</given-names></name><name><surname>McCall</surname><given-names>S.L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Gossard</surname><given-names>A.C.</given-names></name><name><surname>English</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Multiple quantum well reflection modulator</article-title>&#x0201D; <source>Appl Phys Lett</source> <volume>50</volume>(<issue>17</issue>, (<year>1987</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.97935</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r7"><label>7</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Hu</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Cartland</surname><given-names>R.F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kaviani</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Madhukar</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Ex-situ cavity phase tuning of InGaAs/AGaAs multiple quantum well based inverted asymmetric Fabry-Perot reflection modulators</article-title>&#x0201D;, <series>OSA Technical Digest</series>, <day>6</day>, <month>March</month> <year>1993</year></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r8"><label>8</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Karim</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kyriakakis</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Tanguay</surname><given-names>A.R.</given-names><suffix>Jr</suffix></name><name><surname>Cartland</surname><given-names>R.F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hu</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Madhukar</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Post-growth tuning of inverted cavity InGaAs/AlGaAs spatial light modulators using phase compensating dielectric mirrors</article-title>&#x0201D; <source>Appl Phys Lett</source> <volume>66</volume>(<issue>21</issue>), (<year>1995</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.113471</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></book-part></book-part-wrapper>
