<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
<collection-meta collection-type="conf">
<conference content-type="conf-name"><conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name><conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym></conference>
<conference content-type="conf-other-meta"><conf-date content-type="start">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-date content-type="end">
<day>19</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-loc>Nevada, 
<country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc></conference></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
<title-group>
<title>VLSI-based SLMs</title>
<alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/></title-group></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
<title-group>
<title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title></title-group>
<volume-in-collection>
<volume-number>14</volume-number>
<volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title></volume-in-collection></collection-meta>
<book-meta>
<book-title-group>
<book-title>Spatial Light Modulators</book-title></book-title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Burdge</surname><given-names>Geoffrey</given-names></name></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>Sadik C.</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group>
<pub-date publication-format="electronic">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></pub-date></book-meta>
<book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
<book-part-meta>
<title-group>
<title>Design and Partitioning of a Free-space Optical Interconnection FFT Processor</title></title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Rozier</surname><given-names>Richard G.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Kiamilev</surname><given-names>Fouad E.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Krishnamoorthy</surname><given-names>Ashok V.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>*</sup></xref></contrib>
<aff id="aff1">
<label>*</label>Lucent Technologies, Bell Labs Innovations, Holmdel, NJ 077733</aff>
<aff id="aff2">
<label>1</label>UNC Charlotte, Charlotte, NC 28223</aff></contrib-group>
<elocation-id>27</elocation-id>
<permissions>
<copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
<copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
<copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
<license license-type="open-access">
<license-p>closed</license-p></license></permissions>
<abstract>
<p>We describe the design of a high-performance chipset for computing 1-D complex fast-fourier transforms (FFT). Our chip technology is based on flip-chip integration of submicron CMOS ICs with GaAs chips containing 2-D arrays of multiple-quantum wells (MQW) diode optical receivers and transmitters. Our system technology is based on free-space optical interconnection. Compared to an electronic implementation, the proposed design offers increased performance and a reduced chip count. Since our design uses direct, one-to-one interconnections between chips, it is compatible with a number of emerging three-dimensional free-space optoelectronic packaging technologies.</p></abstract>
<kwd-group kwd-group-type="OCIS">
<title>OCIS codes</title>
<kwd>FFT</kwd>
<kwd>optical interconnects</kwd>
<kwd>optical SRAM</kwd>
<kwd>smart-pixels</kwd>
<kwd>array processing parallel processing</kwd></kwd-group>
<counts>
<book-page-count count="12"/></counts></book-part-meta>
<body>
<p>1. Introduction Free-space optical interconnection (FSOI) of integrated circuits shows great potential for efficient implementation of high-performance parallel computing and signal pro- cessing systems &#x0005B;1,2&#x0005D;. On the implementation front, several FSOI technologies are now under development and proto- type FSOI systems have been demonstrated &#x0005B;3,4,56,7,8&#x0005D;. On the theoretical front, a number of papers have been pub- lished that describe architectures and system designs for application specific FSOI systems. However, with the exception of switching and backplane interconnect applica tions &#x0005B;9.10,11,121, there has been relatively little published work that includes detailed integrated circuit (IC) design and accounts for the impact ofcIC layout constraints on FSOI system architecture, design and performance. Such a detailed design study is the objective of this paper. We focus on a specific problem ofdesigning a high-speed FSOI FFT processor. Our FSOI technology is based on the hybrid CMOS-SEED platform that integrates GaAs MQW photo- detectors and modulators with high-volume commodity CMOS VLSI processes&#x0005B;13&#x0005D;. For CMOS technology we use the 0.5 micron HP/MOSIS CMOS14 process &#x0005B;14&#x0005D;. This is a high-speed, high-density 3.3V/5V CMOS process with tight-pitch(1.4 micron) planarized interconnect system that allows three levels of metallized interconnect. Our optical interconnect technology is based on free-space holographic interconnect technology that has previously been used in several FSOI demonstrators &#x0005B; 15&#x0005D;. The result of this work is the design of a chipset for building FSOI FFT processors consisting of the Photonic FFT (PFEET) chip and the Photonic RAM (PRAM) chip -- essentially an optical SRAM. The PRAM chip integrates over 2.5 million transistors in an estimated Icm x Icm die area. The PFFT chip integrates over 1.4 million transistors in an estimated 1.2cm x 1.2cm die area. Each chip has 768 optical inputs and 768 optical outputs, providing a chip-to- chip bandwidth of 29 Gbytes/sec at 150 Mhz clock speed. A complete 8,192 point (or smaller) FFT processor can be built using just three chips, while larger and faster systems can be built using additional chips. It is shown that the pro posed design offers significant advantages over purely elec tronic implementations in terms of increased performance and reduced chip count. In section 2, we discuss electronic and FSOI technologies. Section 3 discusses the FFT algorithm and its partitioning for an FSOI implementation. In section 4, we present detailed IC design for the PFFT and the PRAM chips and a discussion of the optical system. Performance evaluation and comparison with existing elec tronic implementations is provided in section 5. Section 6 winds up with some conclusions about our design.</p>
<p>2. Background Thefast-fouriertransform(FFT)isanimportantopera tion in many applications such as signal processing. tele communications, speech processing, high-speed control, and instrumentation &#x0005B;16&#x0005D;. As a result of this, a number of hardware implementations for fast-fourier transform pro cessors have been developed. These processors are built using multiple processor and memory chips packaged using multichip modules (MCMs), printed-circuit boards (PCBs) and backplanes. The FSOI approach is based on the integration of low- power surface-normal optical interconnect technology with ligh-volumecommodityVLSIprocesses.Thisapproach provides fast and low-latency inter-chip interconnects effectively eliminating several levels of the electronic pack aging hierarchy. In this paper, we will quantify the potential advantagesoftheFSOIapproachforbuildingFFTproces- sors. To achieve this, we perform a detailed architecture, system, chipset and optical system design for an FFT pro- cessor using the hybrid SEED FSOI technology platform. The hybrid CMOS-SEED technology was chosen based on its performance, availability and maturity &#x0005B;171. The hybrid CMOS-SEED technology integrates optical inputs and outputs with standard silicon CMOS circuitry. Quantum well diodes can operate either as optical reflec tion modulators (outputs) or as photodetectors (inputs). These diodes are bonded and electrically connected in a regular grid directly over the silicon circuits. This technol . ogy offers optical inputs and outputs that can run at the speed of the underlying silicon technology, with small areas. low powers, and large densities of inputs and outputs. Since the quantum well diodes can operate either as modu- lators or detectors, the user can choose to use them either as inputs or outputs.</p>
<p>3. FFT Algorithm Mapping 3.1 Fourier Theory The Discrete Fourier Transform (DFT) of an N-point sequence is given as: X(k) = , xv(n)e~ ik k = 0, .. , N- 1 (3.1) 0 Since this formula leads to a large amount of computa tions (N complex multiplications and N(N-1) complex additions). some means of decreasing these time-consum ing calculations is desired. The FFT algorithm is such a method of reduction and was developed from the DFT by Cooley and Tukey &#x0005B;18&#x0005D;. The efficiency of the FFT algo- rithm lies in its elimination of the repetitive computations of the exponential term in the DFT. As a result, there are only (N/2)log2N multiplications and Nlog2 N additions. By comparison, a 1,024-point FFT requires only 1&#x00025; of the calculations that a 1,024-point DFT does.</p>
<p>3.2 The FFT Algorithm The FFT algorithm is a series of multiplications and additions which is performed in stages. It can be imple- inented using the butterfly processor (BP) as shown in Fig- ure 3-1. The butterfly diagram can show graphically the FIGURE 3-1. The butterfly processor flow of data as the calculations are performed. For an N- point FFT, the FFT is calculated with N/radix# butterflies per stage and logradix#N stages. The radix-number tells how many inputs and outputs the BP will have. Using radix-2 butterflies, there will be N/2 BPs per stage and log 2 N stages where each BP has two inputs and two outputs. For exam ple, Figure 3-2 shows a 16-point FFT having four stages with eight BPs per stage. The inputs of the FFT are data FIGURE 3-2. A 16-point FFT points sampled in the time domain. The outputs are discrete frequency-domain data points. The equations that result for a radix-2 BP are as follows: k (3.2) A' = A + W B k (3.3) B' = A-W B k whereAandBarecomplexnumbers. W iscalledthe &#x0201C;twiddle factor&#x0201D; and is expressed as: 2nk eN k (3.4) For actual hardware implementation, these equations should be broken down into real and imaginary compo nents: (3.5) A' R R+BRWR-B W 1 A' 1 = + BR WI + B IWR (3.6) B = A-(BWRBW) (3.7) R R R R (3.8) B' = Al-(BRWI + BI R) The above equations can be implemented in a straightfor ward fashion using four multipliers and six adders as shown in Figure 3-3 (where subtraction can be performed by 2's- complement conversion utilizing inverters and the carry-in bit on the adder). To improve the computational efficiency of the hard ware, higher-radix butterfly processors could be imple- FIGURE 3-3. Radix-2 BP mented. The concept here is that the higher radix BPs are more computationally efficient in that they have fewer mul- tipliers per number of points processed. For example, a radix-4 processor uses twelve multipliers while an equiva . requires sixteen multipliers to radix-2 implementation lent process four data points. However, this efficiency comes at the price of design complexity. In the radix-2 BP. a simple hit-reversal scheme is used to determine the one twiddle factor for .each . BP. In higher radix BPs, a more complex algorithm is required to supply multiple twiddle factors for a single each BP. When multiple BPs are integrated on ZIN7B chip, as done in our approach, the generation and distribu tion of twiddle factors becomes an even more difficult problem. In addition, using higher radix BPs, leads to increased interconnection complexity for both the memory and the processor ICs. In this paper, we focus on the design of a radix-2 FFT processor. The design presented in this paper makes use of the radix-2 butterfly processor as described above. Ideally, the quickest approach to computing the FFT would be a fully- parallel system with (N/2)logN BPs. For an 8192-point FFT, that would be 53,248 BPs. Assuming that each BP is 1.8mmn . x xmThe 2.5mm in a 0.5pm CMOS technology, then only sixteen could feasibly it on one die. In this case, there would be 3,328 die. With this many die. a single ws Multi- athe Chip hip Module (MCM) implementation would be impossi- muleMCMimplementationwouldbeimpossi-. ble. Amultiple MCM implementation would be possible. However, the butterfly architecture must be maintained, which means that eachi B3P would be connected to four other BPs (212,992 connections). The partitioning of this .! massive design would be difficult and the physical realiza tion on printed circuit boards would mean timing ? losses and therefore, a slower system. Alternatively, a free-spaceopti cal butterfly configuration is also possible. Assuming that there are still sixteen B31s on a die, then nby there would have to be 13,312 optical connections between the die. For a high- speed design, every optical connection would have to be parallel, meaning at least 32 bits per connection. Fully real- ized, this yields 425,984 beams of light being transmitted simultaneously and in a configuration that preserves the butterfly structure. Again, the logistics of an undertaking of this size renders it impractical. On the other hand, the most compact solution would be a serial implementation. This would include only one BP and the memory sufficient to keep track of the data. While this is an inexpensive setup, for an 8192-point FFT, there would have to be 53,248 passes, where a pass is a complete radix-2 calculation, of the BP, which would be too slow for real-time applications. Our scheme is a compromise between these two approaches. It is a semi-parallel implementation that places eight radix-2 BPs on one chip, called the Photonic FFT (PFFT). The PFFT as a system-level block, with the A and B inputs to the eight BPs, is shown in Figure 3-4. It takes FIGURE 3-4. PFFT block diagram advantage of both electronic implementations as well as optical. Eight butterfly calculations are performed electron ically per clock cycle and data storage communication is accomplished through optical interconnects.</p>
<p>3.3 Butterfly Processor Operation inputs and outputs of the BPs are connected to opti- calreceiversandtransmittersthatwillbedescribedlaterin paper. The twiddle factor generator will be discussed also. The processors operate c in parallel and are loaded later wihaaroaeaatmmrchpTeigt- wl always work on data from one stage. The FFT procedure is as asflo: Ife follows: I 1. All of the data for one stage is entered into the eight B1ssixteenpointsatatime,whereeachretrievalof sixteen points is executed during one clock cycle. A perfect shuffleisrequiredfortheFF1andisachieved by re istohth aresaceN d reading in 2 points to each BP that are spaced N/2 apart as seen in Figure 3-5. FIGURE 3-5. Data flow for the PFFT 2. The data that comes out of the BPs is stored in memory until it is needed for calculation in the next stage. As with the data input, each sixteen points of output is stored in one clock cycle. And, unlike the input, the output is cached as consecutive data points. 3. The procedure continues with data being read from one memory unit and stored in another until all the data from one stage has been processed. The next stage of data is then calculated in the same fashion using those numbers that were just stored from the previous stage. The fact that eight BPs are operating in parallel along with the need for a perfect shuffle of the data requires a spe- cial data storage scheme. This memory configuration, called the Photonic RAM (PRAM), is shown at the system level in Figure 3-6. In order to get proper shuffle operation. the PRAM is divided into four banks of RAM, as shown in Figure 3-7. Each bank of RAM is further subdivided into four units representing the physical blocks of storage as indicated by the dashed lines in Figure 3-7. When reading data from the PRAM into the BPs, banks 0 and 2 will be read from at the same address, first. Then, banks I and3 will be accessed from the same address also. This insures that all the BPs are supplied with data simultaneously and that each BP gets data that is N/2 points apart. For example, in reading from address 0 on banks 0 and 2, points 0 FIGURE 3-6. PRAM block diagram FIGURE 3-7. PRAM configuration through 7 and N/2 through N/2+7 are supplied to the BPs just as shown in Figure 3-5. The operation continues, read ing data from banks 0 and 2 followed by banks I and 3 at consecutive addresses until all the data for one stage has been read. When storing data, on each pass, sixteen consecutive points of data have to be written simultaneously, seen in Figure 3-5. Therefore, the outputs are stored in the same address in banks 0 and I as shown in Figure 3-7. For exam- ple. on pass number 1, data points 0 through 15 will result from the BP computations and are stored in address 0 of banks 0 and 1. On the next pass, the outputs are stored in the next address of banks 0 and 1. This repeats until banks O and I are full. Then, the routine proceeds to write to the same successive addresses of banks 2 and 3. When banks 2 and 3 are full, another stage has been completed. This memory retrieval and storage method has the added benefit that the data from the previous stage can be read directly into the current stage with no transformations. In other words, the data shuffle between stages is achieved without any physical reorganization of the data.</p>
<p>3.4 The Twiddle Factor Generator The tw iddle factor generator is a unit that was specially designed to work with the PFFT configuration ofeight BPs on one chip shown in Figure 3-8. Twiddle factor generation is an important part of the FFT which is derived from a bit- reversal scheme based on the stage of the FFT calculation. For a single BP system, this is not a difficult task. Challenges arise, though. when trying to supplye ight twiddle factors at a time. The data patterns that are discussed in the proceeding section are demanding to produce eight at a k time. From the twiddle factor expression. W , the value of N k is what is determined by the bit-reversal scheme. k ranges from 0 to N/2-I. This relates to the fact that there are N/2 BPs per stage. The bit-reversal algorithm for determiningk goes as follows: I. For stage I. k is always 0. 2. The numbers between 0 and N/2-1 are written out in hinary. Then, each number is rewritten with the bits rev ersed. revrse. 3. Forthe second stage, the bit-reversed numbers that were just written are taken as the values of k for each BP in the stage, except that the magnitude of the number will be determined from the most significant bit (MSB). For example. Table #1 shows the first six val- ues for k that would be generated in a 64-point FFT for the second stage. So only the first bit is kept and the restofthebitsinthenumberaresettozero.Ingeneral. the values for k from the second stage will toggle between 0 and N/4. 4. For the subsequent stages. the value of k is determined FIGURE 3-8. Twiddle factor generator in a similar fashion. The number of bits that is kept is equal to the stage number minus 1. As an example. for the fourth stage, the 3 most significant bits would decidethemagnitudeofk. Once all the values for k have been established, then the twiddle factors can be calculated and stored in the static RAM, shown in Figure 3-8. N/2 twiddle factors are stored in the SRAM. They are stored in bit-reversed order in con secutive positions (0 through 7 in Figure 3-8) and in con- secutive addresses, such that there are enough twiddle factors in one address to fill all eight BPs, if necessary. By only storing N/2 twiddle factors and not (N/2)log 2 N, a large quantity of storage space is saved. Although if (N/2)log 2 N twiddle factors were stored, then the patterns necessary for each stage could be read out of the RAM directly, thus avoidingthe need for extra circuitry to manipulate the twiddle factor data. However, the manipulation circuitry created . .. for this design is extremely minimal compared to the exces- sive amount of area needed for the extra RAMs. It turns out that there is a nice regular pattern to the fashion in which tw\iddle factors are needed for the BPs. Eight different twid-dle factors are not always needed for the eight different BPs. Fortunately, either only one twiddle factor is needed, or two, or four, or all four have to be different. Therefore, eight different ones are stored in one address of the RAM. And the multiplexers, shown in Figure 3-8, are selected such that the required number of different twiddle factors are sent to the BPs. So the combination of selecting the right address and setting the multiplexer select lines prop- erly will provide the correct twiddle factors to the BPs.</p>
<p>3.5 The FFT System The two basic elements of the FFT design are the PFFT and the PRAM. These two form a cascadable chip set. The system designer can choose however many are necessary for his system. The numbers can range from the fastest and largest design, which would be a pipelined system with logN PFFTs and PRAMs, to the smallest and slowest con- iguration, which would be a single PFFT and two PRAMs. Any number of PFFTs and PRAMs in between those two extremes is also possible. The smallest system would operate as follows, shown in Figure 3-9. FIGURE 3-9. The low-cost system I. PRAM 0 is filled with the initial data set. 2. The first stage of the FFT is calculated, sixteen points at a time through the PFFT, and the data is stored in PRAM 1. 3. The second stage of the FFT is performed, this time with data being read from PRAM 1 and the output stored in PRAM 0. 4. Steps 2 and 3 are repeated in a ping-pong fashion until enough passes have been completed to finish the FFT. The multiple PFFT system is a variable sized pipelined structure as shown in Figure 3-10. It requires n PFFTs and FIGURE 3-10. The high-performance system n+1 PRAMs formaximum performance. where in logN. The initial data set is stored in PRAM 0, and the final data is stored in PRAM m+1 or can be read directly from PFFT in. If, however, fewer than in PFFTs are chosen for the system, the data from the last PFFT will have to be &#x0201C;wrapped around&#x0201D; and stored in PRAM 0, as indicated by the dashed feedback line in Figure 3-10. The FFT process will continue in the original fashion, cycling through the available PFFTs as many times as are required for the suc cessful completion of the calculation. Normally, in the pipelined mode, the next stage will have to wait for the current stage to completely finish stor ing its data before the next stage can access that data. This will cause a bit of a lag in the flow of data. Be that as it may, maximum throughput and pipeline effectiveness can still be achieved in this setup by modifying the PRAM arrangement. In addition to the four subdivisions of RAM in each bank that was mentioned previously, an extra parti tion is needed. The odd-numbered addresses have to be separated from the even addresses. Since two different addresses in the same RAM cannot be accessed at the same time, a split is needed in order for the next stage to read data from the same RAM bank to which the current stage is writing data. In this fashion, the current stage can write data to the odd address while the next stage is reading data from the even address. And vice-versa. As a result, the next stage of the FFT doesn't have to wait for the current stage to complete its calculations before the next stage can start its own processing.</p>
<p>4. Chipset Design Having established the theoretical operation of the but- tertly processor and the FFT system, we now focus on the physical realization of the electronic circuitry and the optics. The following subsections describe the analog and digital integrated circuits and the optical setup.</p>
<p>4.1 Optical Transmitter and Receiver Circuits AnumberofhybridSEEDreceivercircuitshavebeen A n e f b S D designed and tested recently &#x0005B;19,20&#x0005D;. Experimental mea- surements on single-ended and two-beam transimpedance recei\ers have confirmed switching energies less than6(f and operation at data-rates in excess of 800Mb/s. The area of a simple transimpedance receiver circuit that uses one gain-stage and two parallel MOS transistors as the feed- back element, is approximately 300pm2 in a 0.8pm CM~tcholgy19. Current hybrid CMOS-SEED transimpedance receiver circuit designs typically consume 3-4mW of power operat ing at 5V with speeds in excess of 300Mb/s &#x0005B;19&#x0005D;. When large numbers of receivers Snb orerrnsgc. are integrated on asingle chip. this power dissipation - must be accounted for .in the power budget. For example, the 768 two-beam receivers used in the FFT chipset would dissipate 2.7W on-chip. If neces- sary, this value can be reduced by several means. First, the power consumption can be reduced by operating the receivercircuitsatlowervoltages(e.g.3.3V).Becausethe FFT chip-set calls for 150Mb/s receivers, the receiver band \idth can be traded-in for reduced power consumption. Finally. novel receiver designs may significantlv reduce the consumption withonlyasma i ihol mll penalty in sensitivity t &#x0005B;1.C &#x0005B;21 TheopticaltransmittercircuitisaCMOSinverteroper- ating at 5V. The output of this inverter sees a pair of reverse-biased quantum well diode modulators as the capacitive load. With present the hybrid SEED process this capacitance is approximately 100fF &#x0005B;221. which is an order of magnitude smaller than the capacitance of flip-chip or perimeter pads used for electronic packaging. Lower capac- itance translates directly into low on-chip power consump tion. The dynamic power consumption per transmitter for the proposed chipset can be estimated using the following: P, = CV f = (100fF)(5V)(150MHz) (4.1) P1 = 200pW In addition, there will be an extra 200-300pW of power dissipation per transmitter due to the photocurrent flowing through the output driver when the modulator is in the absorbing stage. This leads to about 350mW of power con- sumption for the 768 transmitters used in our chipsets. In summary, the chipset calls for 768 dual-beam optical receivers and 768 dual-beam optical transmitters per chip. These are arranged in a 48x64 array of quantum well diodes corresponding to a 48x32 array of transmitters and receivrs. The floorplan for the proposed chipsets puts the quantum well diode array in the middle of the chip. The diode array uses a 96x64 array of pads which requires 3.8mm x 2.5mm of silicon area assuming 40pm pad pitch. Receiver amplifier and transmitter driver circuits are placed directly under the quantum well diode array. The power consumption of the entire receiver/transmitter section is approximately 3W per chip using existing transimpedance This can be reduced to 1-2W with receivers opti- f</p>
<p>4.2OpticsConfiguration For typical smart pixel applications such as photonic switching, the cascaded optical connections between chips are strictly feedforward. Feedforward multi-chip optical systems have previously been demonstrated by combining polarization with space-division multiplexing &#x0005B;3&#x0005D; and polar- pizationwithp-divisionmultiplexing &#x0005B;3&#x0005D;otholar ization with pupil-division multiplexing &#x0005B;3&#x0005D;. Both of these optical systems are applicable to the multi-chip pipelined PFFT processor (system 2) and readers are referred to these papers prusoadtimlederip for a detailed description. Because tion the theF PFFT proces-epofes sorusesonly simple one-to-oneconnection, theuse ofa holographicopticalinterconnectisnotrequired;thissim- plifiesthesystemandreducesloss. Most feedforward optical systems lack the flexibility to accomplish feedback or bi-directional communication. The three-chipsmart-pixel PFFT processor (system )requires connectionsto(write cycle)and from (readcycle)the smart-pixel PRAM memory chip. Here we present one pos sible arrangement that uses polarization and space-division multiplexing, and can provide the required feedback as well as feedforward optical connectivity between photonic chips. Note that the connections are simple point-to-point optical connections between the FFT processors and corre sponding RAM cells. No complex interconnect structure is necessary. Figure 4-1 shows an example of a telecentric optical system that can achieve this connectivity. Chips are FIGURE 4-1. Optics system connected using one path to place the arrayed optical read out beams from a PFFT chip onto the detectors of two ofits associated PRAM chips, and a separate shared path to image the outputs of the PRAM chips onto the PFFT chip. Simultaneously, the outputs of the chips are also split to their respective data I/O ports; these outputs can be used to feed another pair of PFFT-PRAM chips.</p>
<p>4.3 CMOS Building Blocks . . . All of the CMOS digital IC components used in our designs and discussed in this paper are from existing tech- nology libraries. The PFFT chip design makes extensive use of 24-bit adder circuits. Each radix-2 butterfly proces- sor in the PFFT chip uses six adders. With eight radix-2 BPs per chip. a total of 48 adders are used on the PFFT chip. Our adder design uses a carry-select architecture with a Manchester carry chain and can add two 24-bit fixed point numbers in 3ns 123,24&#x0005D;. It also determines an overflow condition automatically. Operating at 150MHZ, the adder consumes 6,980ptW and requiresI26,000pm 2 of chip area, with 1053 transistors. The edge-triggered flip-flop (or register) is another important building block of the PFFT chip. Each radix-2 BP in the PFFT chip uses 368 registers to pipeline the com- putation. With eight BPs per chip, a total of 2.944 registers are used on the PFFT chip. Operating at 150MHZ, the reg- ister consumes 150pW and requires 740pm of chip area. xith 34 transistors. The mostsimportant circuit on the PFFT chip is the 24- bit multiplier circuit. Each radix-2 butterfly processor in the PFFT chip uses four multipliers. With eight radix-2 butter- fly processors per chip, a total of 32 multipliers are used on the PFFT chip. Our multiplier design is a 2's complement pipelined multiplier that can multiply a 24-bit and a 16-bit fixed point number in under 5ns &#x0005B;23,24&#x0005D;. A modified Booth algorithm is used to produce a series of partial products, which are summed by a Wallace tree adder circuit. A Manchester carry chain is then used to generate the final product. A register is placed near the middle of the multi- plication, allowing the multiplier module to produce results at a higher clock rate. The product is then produced one clock cycle later. Operating at 150MHZ, the multiplier con- sumes 46.90 W and takes up 600, m2 of chip area with 12786transistors. High-speedstaticRAM(SRAM)circuitsareusedin both the PFFT and the PRAM chips. The PRAM chip uses sixteen banks of static RAM modules organized as 256 words, each word being 96 bits (256x96), to store the data pt c uses points during the FFT computation. t The PFFT chips two SRAM banks to store the twiddle coefficients, each bank bakenszea5218OuSA being sized as 512xl128. Our SRAM dsgnssttc t, design uses static address decoding for fast access times, reduced power consumption and high density &#x0005B;25&#x0005D;. Bit storage is performed using conventional six-transistor circuit and current-mode amplifiers are used to amplify bit line signals. Tristate out- put drivers are used on the data output lines and they are controlled with an output enable signal. The cycle time is 5.5ns for the 512x128 (twiddle storage) SRAM and 5.Ins for the 256x96 (data storage) SRAM. Operating at 150MHZ, the 512x128 SRAM consumes 560mW and has the dimensions of 2.5mm x 3.3mm, with 406,628 transis tors. The 256x96 SRAM consumes 328mW and has dimen sions 1.8mm x1.8mm, with 155,738 transistors.</p>
<p>4.4 Photonic RAM chip The photonic RAM (PRAM) chip functions as an opti cal SRAM. It integrates sixteen 256x96 SRAMs on a single chip whose floorplan is shown in Figure 4-2. This yields a FIGURE 4-2. PRAM floorplan sum of over 2.5 million transistors in an estimated Icm x cm die area. The 768 optical inputs and 768 optical out puts are arranged as a 48x32 transmitter-receiver array in the center of the PRAM chip. The receiver amplifier and transmitter driver circuits are placed directly under the quantum well diode array. This floorplan allows for effi cient wire routing between the SRAMs and the transmitter- receiver array. The PRAM chip supports simultaneous READ and WRITEaccesstoenable single-FFand multi-EFproces- sor systems. In the single-FFT . mode, the power consump tion is reduced since only eight SRAMs out of sixteen are .ti educesinc eoeight otofsiteer active at any single time. We estimate the on-chip power at: = P optic +8 P(256x96SRAM)= 5.72W(4.2) In the multi-FFT mode, twelve of the sixteen SRAMs are being accessed at the time. The on-chip power consumption would then be: Pdiss P opti + 12 P(256x96SRAM) = 7.04W (4.3)</p>
<p>4.5 Photonic FFT chip The architecture of the radix-2 butterfly processor was described in section 3. The implementation uses a fixed- point 2's complement numeric format. It requires 70,136 transistors in a 1.9mm x 2.8mm area. A snapshot of the 0.5lm layout is shown in Figure 4-3. Power consumption is FIGURE 4-3. BP layout estimated at 474mW operating at 150MHZ with 50&#x00025; switching factor. The design is fully pipelined and can compute a new radix-2 butterfly in every clock cycle. The pipeline latency is 3 clock cycles. The processor has 96 inputs for two 48-bit complex numbers with 24-bit real and 24-bit imaginary parts. Similarly, 96 outputs are used for two 48-bit complex numbers. There are 32 input ports to bring in one 32-bit fixed-point complex twiddle coefficients wAith 16-bit real and 16-bit imaginary parts. The photonic FFT (PFFT) chip integrates eight radix-2 butterfly processors and two 512xl28 twiddle-storage SRAMs on a single chip. The floorplan of this chip is shown in Figure 4-4. The PFFT chip integrates over 1.4 million transistors in an estimated 1.2cm x 1.2cm die area. FIGURE 4-4. PFFT floorplan The 768 optical inputs and 768 optical outputs are arranged as a 48x32 transmitter-receiver array in the center of the PFFT chip. The receiver amplifier and transmitter driver circuits are placed directly under the quantum well diode array. This floorplan allows for efficient wire routing between the eight processor modules and the diode array. The PFFT chip operates in pipelined mode computing cight radix-2 butterflies every clock cycle. Thus on every clock cycle, 768 optical inputs are received and 768 optical outputs are transmitted. The twiddle coefficients required to compute the FFT are stored directly on the PFFT chip in two banks of 512x128 SRAMs. This memory capacity allows FFT sizes of up to 8,192 points to be computed. Twiddle coefficients are loaded electrically prior to com puting the FFT. The power consumption for the PFFT chip is estimated at: 8PBP2P5l2x28SRAM (44) Rapt) s +8(P()+P()) Pdiss = 8W</p>
<p>5. Performance Evaluation Compared with electronic implementations, the photo- nic design described in this paper, provides higher chip pin- count and off-chip 1/O bandwidth. Specifically, the PFFT and the PRAM chips have the following: PINOUT=8(PEs) x &#x0005B;48*2(inputs)+48*2(outputs)&#x0005D; PINOUT=1,536 BANDWIDTH= 1,536x150MHZ= 230,400Mbit/s BANDWIDTH = 29Gbytes/s which is an order of magnitude increase in off-chip band- width over conventional silicon ICs &#x0005B;26&#x0005D;. On-chip power density is less than 10 Watts/cm 2 and it is dominated by the switching of the internal electronic circuits. The single PFFT system described in section 3.5 will now be referred to as system 1. Let us discuss the 8,192- point complex FFT, which is the maximum our design can handle. It requires 53,248 ((N/2)log-N) radix-2 butterflies. Using our eight-processor FFT chip. we need a total of 53.248/8 passes, each taking up 6.7 ns (1/150MHz). This adds up to a total computation time of 44ps. For a 1.024- point FFT, 4.3s is required. Table 2 compares the perfor- mance of our design with electronic FFT processors &#x0005B;27.28,2930,3132.33&#x0005D;. At the chip-level. the PFFT chip TABLE 2. Performance comparison of FFT processors clearly outperforms electronic designs. At the board level, the performance advantage is not as clear. Since electronic systems have difficulty achieving 29Gbyte/sec interchip communication, they partition FFT computation to achieve maximum performance while keeping off-chip I/O within bounds ofelectronic packaging &#x0005B;27&#x0005D;. Typically, a radix-2 or higher butterly is implemented on a single chip and data is fed to it from an SRAM. Then, to achieve higher perfor- mance. processors are arranged in pipelined fashion to exe- cute the logN stages of the FFT computation &#x0005B;29&#x0005D;. The performance of an electronic board-level FFT pro- cessor can equal and even exceed our system I design. However, the electronic solution requires many more chips to achieve this. For example. an 8.192-point electronic FFT processor takes thirteen radix-2 processor chips (log8192=13) and 26 SRAM chips (using 48-bit wide SRAMs). This means that we are reducing system chip count from 39+ chips down to three chips by utilizing smart pixels. This reduction in chip count leads to systems with smaller size and lower power consumption. To build a higher-performance smart pixel FFT proces sor, we can operate multiple photonic FFT and RAM chips in a pipelined fashion, as described in section 3.5. In this approach. the latency remains the same. while the through put increases dramatically. This system, called system 2. canachieveanorder-of-magnitudeperformanceincrease with a corresponding increase in hardware cost. For the 8.192-point complex FFT. there would be thirteen PFFTs and fourteen PRAMs for a total of 27 chips. Unlike system I. where it is necessary to wait for the data to 'ping-pong back and forth before a new FFT can be calculated, svstem 2is a straight-through pipeline, in which a new FFT is cal culated every time a complete pass is made on the last stage. The resulting throughput is given by &#x0005B;(# of butterflies per stage)/8&#x0005D; * 6.7ns = (4096/8) * 6.7ns= 3.4ps. Which means that a new FFT is computed every 3.4ps. For a 1,024-point complex FFT, 0. 4 4ps is required. The perfor- inance of this system exceeds all electronic FFT processor designs. Z One important consideration for pipelined systems is that their external bandwidth requirements are increased these types of systems are useful in focal plane arra s where sensor data can be captured and passed to the processor array without creating a bottleneck.</p>
<p>6. Discussion and Conclusions The design presented in this paper offers a greatly flexi ble. high-performance. low chip-count solution to the numerous applications that require a high-speed FFT calcu lation. Our design uses fixed-point complex number arith metic. To increase precision, a simple modification, called block-floating point, can be added to our chipset &#x0005B;27&#x0005D;. On the other hand, a true floating-point implementation would significantly increase the complexity and transistor count of the PFFT chip. The performance benchmarks show our design (system I) to be the fastest in the lower cost and chip count catego ries. Specifically, we can compute a 1,024-point complex FFT in 4.3ps using a system with one PFFT chip and two PRAM chips. An electronic implementation that combines a single Sharp LH9124 processor chip with SRAM and glue-logic chips requires 87ts for the same computation &#x0005B;27&#x0005D;. The performance of our design (system 2) improves as pute a new 1,024-point complex FFT in every 0.44ps using a fully pipelined system with ten PFFT chips and eleven PRAM chips. A high-performance electronic system that uses four Sharp LH9124 FFT processor chips. twelve Sharp LH9320 address generator chips, twelve SRAM chips, and various glue-logic chips requires 31is for the same compu- tation &#x0005B;30&#x0005D;. More importantly, when multiple chips are con- nected to compute large FFTs, our chipset offers much higher performance than electronic solutions due to higher inter-chip bandwidth that is made possible with optical interconnects. In addition, the designer can tailor the PFFT/PRAM chipset to fit his needs for speed and size. As it stands now, systems I and 2 can compute from a minimum of a 16- point FFT all the way to an 8.192-point FFT, with any power of 2 value between these extremes. Larger-point FFTs can be achieved without modifying the PFFT chip. Only enhancements to the PRAM are necessary with the appropriate scaling. For example, a 16,384-point FFT is possible by doubling the memory capacity. One way to achieve order-of-magnitude higher capacity PRAM chips is by usinge lectronic 3-D memory stacking technology &#x0005B;341. Higher performance FFTs can be achieved by increasing the number of radix-2 BPs on the PFFT chip. For example, doubling the number ofradix-2 BPs on the PFFT chip, dou- bles the performance while doubling the number of off- chip optical IOs. We have presented an implementation of our design using hybrid CMOS-SEED technology. Since our design uses direct. one-to-one interconnections between the PRAM and the PFFT chips, it is compatible with a number of emerging three-dimensional free-space optoelectronic packaging and device technologies &#x0005B;5,6,8&#x0005D;. Other partition ing choices to perform the FFT are possible and were not considered here &#x0005B;35.361.</p>
<p>Acknowledgments The work at UNC Charlotte was funded by a research erant from AFOSR (F49620-95-1-0257).</p></body>
<back>
<ref-list>
<ref id="r1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Forrest</surname><given-names>S.R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hinton</surname><given-names>H.S.</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>editors, Special issue on smart pixels</article-title>. <source>IEEE J Quantum Electronics</source> <volume>29</volume>, <fpage>2</fpage><month>March</month> <year>1993</year></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Hinton</surname><given-names>H.S.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>An Introduction to Photonic Switching Fabrics</source>,<publisher-name>Plenum</publisher-name>, <publisher-loc>New York</publisher-loc>, (<year>1993</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/978-1-4757-9171-6</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>McCormick</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Five-stage free-space optical switching network with field-effect transistor self electro-optic effect device smart-pixel arrays</article-title>.&#x0201D; <source>Applied Optics</source> <volume>33</volume>, <day>8</day> <month>March</month> (<year>1994</year>) <fpage>1601</fpage>-<lpage>1618</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/AO.33.001601</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>McCormick</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Six-stage digital free-space optical switching network using symmetric self electro-optic effect devices</article-title>&#x0201D;, <source>Applied Optics</source> <volume>32</volume>, <issue>26</issue>(<month>September</month> <year>1993</year>, <fpage>5153</fpage>-<lpage>5171</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/AO.32.005153</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Tsang</surname><given-names>D.Z.</given-names></name><name><surname>Goblick</surname><given-names>T.J.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Free-space optical inter connect technology in parallel processing systems</article-title>.&#x0201D; <source>Optical Engineering</source> <volume>33</volume>, <issue>5</issue>, <month>May</month>, <year>1994</year>, <fpage>1524</fpage>-<lpage>1531</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1117/12.170723</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Jokerst</surname><given-names>N.M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Camperi-Ginestet</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Buchanan</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wilkenson</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Brooke</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Communication through stacked silicon circuitry using integrated thin film InP-based emitters and detectors&#x0201D; </article-title>, <source>IEEE Photonics Technology Letters</source>&#x0201D;, <volume>79</volume>, <month>September</month> <year>1995</year>, <fpage>1028</fpage>-<lpage>1030</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1109/68.414691</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r7"><label>7</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yala</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Krishnamoorthy</surname><given-names>A.V.</given-names></name><name><surname>Marsden</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>S.C.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>A Prototype 3-D Optically Interconnected Neural Network</article-title>&#x0201D;, <source>Proc of the IEEE</source> <volume>82</volume>, <day>11</day> <month>November</month> <year>1994</year>, <fpage>1749</fpage>-<lpage>1762</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1109/5.333752</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r8"><label>8</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Jewell</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Olbright</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Vertical Cavity Surface Emitting Lasers</article-title>.&#x0201D; <source>IEEE Journal of Quantum Electronics</source> <volume>27</volume>, (<year>1991</year>)<fpage>1332</fpage>-<lpage>1346</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1109/3.89950</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r9"><label>9</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Cloonan</surname><given-names>T.J.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Comparative study of optical and electronic interconnection technologies for large asynchronous transfer mode packet switching applications</article-title>.&#x0201D; <source>Optical Engineering</source> <volume>33</volume>, <issue>5</issue>, <month>May</month> <year>1994</year>, <fpage>1512</fpage>-<lpage>1523</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1117/12.166527</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r10"><label>10</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Szymanski</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hinton</surname><given-names>H.S.</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>Architecture Of A Terabit Free-Space Photonic Backplane</article-title>&#x0201D;, <source>Institute Of Physics Conference Series Journal</source> <volume>139</volume>, (<year>1995</year>)<fpage>141</fpage>-<lpage>144</lpage></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r11"><label>11</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Krishnamoorthy</surname><given-names>A.V.</given-names></name><name><surname>Marchand</surname><given-names>P.J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kiamiley</surname><given-names>F.E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>S.C.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Grain-Size Considerations For Optoelectronic Multistage Interconnection Networks</article-title>.&#x0201D; <source>Applied Optics</source> <volume>3126</volume>, <month>September</month> <year>1992</year>, <fpage>5480</fpage>-<lpage>5507</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/AO.31.005480</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r12"><label>12</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kiamilev</surname><given-names>F.E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Marchand</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Krishnamoorthy</surname><given-names>A.V.</given-names></name><name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>S.C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></name></person-group>; &#x0201C;<article-title>Performance Comparison Between Optoelectronic and VLSI Multistage Interconnection Networks</article-title>&#x0201D;. <source>IEEE Journal Of Lightwave Technology</source>, (<year>1991</year>)<volume>9</volume>(<issue>12</issue>) <fpage>1674</fpage>-<lpage>1692</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1109/50.108713</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r13"><label>13</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Goossen</surname><given-names>K.W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Walker</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></name><name><surname>DAsaro</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hui</surname><given-names>S. P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Tseng</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Leibenguth</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kossives</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bacon</surname><given-names>D. D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Dahringer</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chirovsky</surname><given-names>L. M. F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lentine</surname><given-names>A. L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Miller</surname><given-names>D. A. B.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>GaAs MQW modulators integrated with silicon CMOS</article-title>&#x0201D;, <source>IEEE Photonics Technology Letters</source> <volume>7</volume>, <day>4</day> <month>April</month> <year>1995</year>, <fpage>360</fpage>-<lpage>362</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1109/68.376802</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r14"><label>14</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">CMOS14TB Design Reference Manual. Hewlett-Packard ICBD Division, <year>1995</year></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r15"><label>15</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>McCormick</surname><given-names>F.B.</given-names></name></person-group> <source>Free Space Interconnection Techniques. in Photonics in Switching</source>. <person-group person-group-type="editor"><name><surname>Midwinter</surname><given-names>J.E.</given-names></name></person-group>, editor, <publisher-name>Academic</publisher-name>, <publisher-loc>New York</publisher-loc>, <year>1993</year> Volume <volume>II</volume>, <fpage>169</fpage>-<lpage>250</lpage></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r16"><label>16</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ifeachor</surname><given-names>E C</given-names></name><name><surname>Jervis</surname><given-names>B W</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>Digital Signal Processing A Practical Approach</source>, <publisher-name>Addison-Wesley Publishing Co</publisher-name>, <publisher-loc>Reading, MA</publisher-loc>, (<year>1993</year>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r17"><label>17</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">Hybrid SEED Workshop Notes, George Mason Univ., Washington D.C. (<month>July</month> <year>1995</year></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r18"><label>18</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Cooley</surname><given-names>J.W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Tukey</surname><given-names>J.W.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>An algorithm for the machine calculation of complex Fourier series</article-title>,&#x0201D;<source>Mathematics Computation</source> <volume>19</volume>, (<year>1965</year>)<fpage>297</fpage>-<lpage>301</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1090/S0025-5718-1965-0178586-1</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r19"><label>19</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Krishnamoorthy</surname><given-names>A.V.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lentine</surname><given-names>A.L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Goossen</surname><given-names>K.W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Walker</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Woodward</surname><given-names>T K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ford</surname><given-names>J. E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Aplin</surname><given-names>G. F.</given-names></name><name><surname>DAsaro</surname><given-names>L. A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hui</surname><given-names>S. P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Tseng</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Leibenguth</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kossives</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Dahringer</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chirovsky</surname><given-names>L. M. F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Miller</surname><given-names>D. A. B</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>3-Dintegration of MQW modulators over active sub-micron CMOS circuits:375Mb/s transimpedance receiver-transmitter circuit</article-title>&#x0201D;, <source>IEEE Photonics Technology Letters</source> <volume>7</volume>, <day>11</day> <month>November</month> <year>1995</year>, <fpage>1288</fpage>-<lpage>1290</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1109/68.473474</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r20"><label>20</label><mixed-citation publication-type="confproc"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Lentine</surname><given-names>A.L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Goossen</surname><given-names>K.W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Walker</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chirosky</surname><given-names>L.M.F.</given-names></name><name><surname>DAsaro</surname><given-names>LA.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hui</surname><given-names>S. P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Tseng</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Leibenguth</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kossives</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Dahringer</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kiamilev</surname><given-names>F. E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Woodward</surname><given-names>T. K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Miller</surname><given-names>D. A. B</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>700Mb/s operation of optoelectronic switching nodes comprised of flip-chip-bonded GaAs/AlGaAs MQW modulators and detectors on silcon CMOS circuitry</article-title>&#x0201D;, <source>Proc. Conference on Lasers and Electro-optics (CLEO)</source>, <conf-loc>Baltimore</conf-loc>, Paper <fpage content-type="conf-paper">CPD-11</fpage>, (<conf-date>May1995</conf-date>).</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r21"><label>21</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Krishnamoorthy</surname><given-names>A.V.</given-names></name><name><surname>Woodward</surname><given-names>T.K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Goossen</surname><given-names>K.W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Walker</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lentine</surname><given-names>A.L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chirovsky</surname><given-names>L.M.F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hui</surname><given-names>S.P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Tseng</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Cunningham</surname><given-names>J.E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jan</surname><given-names>W.Y.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Operation of a single-ended 550Mbits/sec, 41-fJ hybrid CMOS/MQW receiver-transmitter</article-title>.&#x0201D; <source>Electronics Letters</source>, <volume>32</volume>(<issue>8</issue>) <month>April</month>, <year>1996</year>, <fpage>764</fpage>-<lpage>765</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1049/el:19960539</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r22"><label>22</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Krishnamoorthy</surname><given-names>A.V.</given-names></name><name><surname>Woodward</surname><given-names>T.K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Novotny</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Goossen</surname><given-names>K.W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Walker</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lentine</surname><given-names>A.L.</given-names></name><name><surname>DAsaro</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hui</surname><given-names>S. P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Tseng</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Leibenguth</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kossives</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Dahringer</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chirovsky</surname><given-names>L. M. F.</given-names></name>Aplin. G. F.<name><surname>Rozier</surname><given-names>R. G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kiamilev</surname><given-names>F. E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Miller</surname><given-names>D. A. B.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Ring Oscillators with Optical and Electrical Readout based on Hybrid GaAs MQW Modulators Bonded to 0.8micron Silicon VLSI circuits</article-title>&#x0201D;, <source>Electronics Letters</source> <volume>31</volume> <issue>22</issue>, <fpage>1917</fpage>-<lpage>1918</lpage>(<month>October</month> <day>26</day>, <year>1995</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1049/el:19951342</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r23"><label>23</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Waser</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Flynn</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></name></person-group> <source>Introduction to Arithmetic for Digital Systems Designers</source>, <publisher-name>HBJ Publishing</publisher-name>, <publisher-loc>Orlando, Florida</publisher-loc>. <year>1982</year></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r24"><label>24</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wolf</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Modern</surname><given-names>VLSI</given-names></name><name><surname>Design</surname><given-names>Prentice</given-names></name><name><surname>Hall</surname><given-names>Engle-wood</given-names></name><name><surname>Cliffs</surname><given-names>N.J.</given-names></name></person-group>, (<year>1994</year>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r25"><label>25</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Bellaouar</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Elmasry</surname><given-names>M.I.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>Low-Power Digital VLSI Design</source>, <publisher-name>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher-name>, <publisher-loc>Norwell, MA</publisher-loc>, (<year>1995</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/978-1-4615-2355-0</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r26"><label>26</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Tummala</surname><given-names>R.R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Rymaszewski</surname><given-names>E.J.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>Microelectronics Packaging Handbook, Van Norstrand</source> <publisher-name>Reinhold</publisher-name>, <publisher-loc>New York</publisher-loc>, (<year>1989</year>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r27"><label>27</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><article-title>LH9124 Digital Signal Processor User&#x02019;s Guide</article-title>, <source>Sharp Electronics</source>, <publisher-loc>Camas, WA</publisher-loc>. <year>1992</year></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r28"><label>28</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><source>Digital Signal Processing IC Handbook</source>, <publisher-name>GEC Plessey Semiconductors</publisher-name>, <publisher-loc>Longwood, FL</publisher-loc>, <year>1988</year></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r29"><label>29</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Fleming</surname><given-names>Mike</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Record Setting, High Performance, Modular DSP Chip Set</article-title>&#x0201D;, <source>DSP  Multimedia Technology</source> <month>December</month> <year>1994</year>/January 1995, <fpage>19</fpage>-<lpage>33</lpage></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r30"><label>30</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><source>CRCV1M40-64K-P4Futurebus 24 Block Floating Point DSP Based on Sharp LH9124/LH9320 Chip Set (Product Specification)</source>, <publisher-name>Catalina Research, Inc., Colorado Springs, CO</publisher-name>.</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r31"><label>31</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book">&#x0201C;<source>Valley Technologies&#x02019; Ultra Series -- Sharp-based DSP and High-Speed I/O</source>&#x02019;, <publisher-name>DSP Applications</publisher-name>, <month>March</month>, <year>1994</year>, <fpage>63</fpage>-<lpage>64</lpage></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r32"><label>32</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Child</surname><given-names>Jeff</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Higher levels of integration come to DSPs</article-title>&#x0201D;, <source>Computer Design</source>, <month>May</month>, <year>1994</year>, <fpage>91</fpage>-<lpage>99</lpage></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r33"><label>33</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book">&#x0201C;<article-title>World&#x02019;s Most Powerful DSP Redefines Industry Land scape</article-title>&#x0201D;, <source>Semiconductor News Releases. Texas Instruments</source>, <publisher-loc>Dallas. TX</publisher-loc>, <month>May</month>, <year>1997</year></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r34"><label>34</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Carson</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>Memory stacking drives 3-D packaging.(Interconnects  Packaging: Part 2: Advanced Packages special section)</article-title>, <source>Electronic Engineering Times</source> <volume>854</volume>, <fpage>58</fpage>(<month>June</month>, <year>1995</year></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r35"><label>35</label><mixed-citation publication-type="confproc"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Drabik</surname><given-names>T.J.</given-names></name></person-group> <article-title>Optoelectronic integrated systems based on free-space interconnects with an arbitrary degree of space variance</article-title>, in <source>Proc. of the IEEE 82</source>, <conf-date>11 November 1994</conf-date>, <fpage>1595</fpage>-<lpage>622</lpage></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r36"><label>36</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ozaktas</surname><given-names>H.M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Miller</surname><given-names>D.A.B.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Digital Fourier Optics</article-title>.&#x0201D; <source>Applied Optics</source> <volume>38</volume>, <day>8</day> <month>March</month> 10, <year>1995</year>, <fpage>1212</fpage>-<lpage>1219</lpage></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></book-part></book-part-wrapper>
