<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
<collection-meta collection-type="conf">
<conference content-type="conf-name"><conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name><conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym></conference>
<conference content-type="conf-other-meta"><conf-date content-type="start">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-date content-type="end">
<day>19</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-loc>Nevada, 
<country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc></conference></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
<title-group>
<title>SLM Applications</title>
<alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/></title-group></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
<title-group>
<title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title></title-group>
<volume-in-collection>
<volume-number>14</volume-number>
<volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title></volume-in-collection></collection-meta>
<book-meta>
<book-title-group>
<book-title>Spatial Light Modulators</book-title></book-title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Burdge</surname><given-names>Geoffrey</given-names></name></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>Sadik C.</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group>
<pub-date publication-format="electronic">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></pub-date></book-meta>
<book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
<book-part-meta>
<title-group>
<title>High - resolution LCTV-SLM and its application to holography</title></title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Hashimoto</surname><given-names>Nobuyuki</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref><xref rid="cor1" ref-type="corresp"><sup>*</sup></xref></contrib>
<aff id="aff1">CITIZEN WATCH CO., LTD. Technical Laboratory 840 Shimotomi Tokorozawa Saitama 359, 
<country country="JP">Japan</country></aff></contrib-group>
<author-notes>
<corresp id="cor1">
<label>*</label><email>hashimotono@citizen.co.jp</email>, Phone 81-429-43-5170, Fax 81-429-43-3891</corresp></author-notes>
<elocation-id>227</elocation-id>
<permissions>
<copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
<copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
<copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
<license license-type="open-access">
<license-p>closed</license-p></license></permissions>
<abstract>
<p>This figure shows a schematic diagram of light modulation using a unit LC cell. LC molecules are surface aligned by surface anchoring method between two glass substrates and the directions of LC molecules are gradually twisted along the Z axis. LC molecules has dielectric anisotropy so that the refractive index between long and short axis is different.</p></abstract>
<counts>
<book-page-count count="23"/></counts></book-part-meta>
<body>
<p>Comments for viewgraphs Fig. 1 This figure shows a schematic diagram of light modulation using a unit LC cell. LC molecules are surface aligned by surface anchoring method between two glass substrates and the directions of LC molecules are gradually twisted along the Z axis. LC molecules has dielectric anisotropy so that the refractive index between long and short axis is different. The direction of the linearly polarized light will rotate along the LC molecules after passing through the LC cell. In this case, optical pass becomes ned. As LC molecules are very sensitive to electric fields, they are aligned along the fields while sufficient voltage is applied to the cell and no rotation of the incident light will occur and then the optical pass becomes nod. With the precise control of the applied field, intermediates states can be realized. Therefore, this cell can works as an amplitude modulator combined with polarizers and as a phase modulator without an output polarizer. Please note that as an amplitude modulator, phase should be also modulated. As phase modulators, it is ideal to use homogeneous LC cell that the LC molecules are not twisted. Fig. 2 This figure shows the classification of LCDs and they are mainly classified as matrix addressing and optical addressing that incorporates the photo-conductive material. Our interests are matrix addressing and it classified to TFT with independent switching gates and TFD without independent gates. We are focused on TN and Homogeneous LCDs with MIM diodes as TFD. This figure shows the matrix addressing of each pixel. The timing pulse comes serial to row electrodes and data signals come parallel to column electrodes and each intersection point contacted through LCs works as a pixel. To use the switching devices, we can drive the each pixel more independently compared to passive addressing without SW devices. Fig. 3 This figure shows the structure and electrical characteristics of MIM diodes. The MIM structure is a thin film insulator sandwiched between conductive layers and then work as bi-direction diodes. This is an equivalent circuit connected serial with LC cell. To inject charges sufficiently and then hold them in the LC cell, the low capacitance and high charge transfer rates of the MIM and high impedance of the LCs are important factors. This graph is a V-I characteristics of MIM. We consider this Vth as switching voltage. Fig. 4 This figure shows the LC cell structure with MIM diodes and its fabrication process using only two masks. Fist Ta sputtering and mask patterning to fabricate conductor, then anodic oxidation to fabricate insulator and ITO sputtering and masking to fabricate electrodes with additional function of the conductor. So the MIM bi -diodes fabricated in this process has non symmetric characteristics so we have to compensate using double MIM or non symmetric driving. In case of 3 mask process. Ta sputterring and masking before ITO patterning. Fig. 5, 6 This is a photograph of a pixel with an MIM diode. This circled area is a MIM area. This graph shows the typical VI characteristics of 2 and 3 mask MIM diodes. Please note that the Y axis is a log scale. We can see that Vth. of 2 mask process is non symmetric but higher than that of 3 mask process that will lead the high driving abilities. Fig. 7, Table 1 This is a photograph of our typical SLMs and its specifications are shown in the table. Type B has a more fine pixel but type A has a more large number of pixels. We can drive the SLM easily by composite video signals from CCD or VCR. From the photo that we can see the ICs are directly bounded on the glass substrates called COG technology. To use this technology, the number of FPC connectors are dramatically reduced. Fig. 8, Table 2 This photo is one portion of driving ICs and these are contact point arrays. This is a sectional view of the contact point. The ICs and ITO electrodes of an LC cell are electrically contact through these points. This table shows the data IC specifications and we can realize 22 um connection pitches in other words 22 pm pixel pitches. Fig. 9 This is a typical sectional diagram of our LCDs. We can see from the diagram that the optical flatness is very good. In case of 1 inch diagonal panels, the flatness is A /4. The problem is that the XY matrix electrodes works as diffraction gratings due to the index mismatching between ITO and alignment layer. These are power spectrum of the LCDs. We can see the spectrum of matrix electrodes. Fig. 10 To investigate the difference between TN and Homogeneous LCDs for holograms, we measure the beam spot profiles of power spectrum of LCD gratings with binary modulations. This is an measuring optics. From the results, the spot size become small and side lobe are increased using the 90 deg. TN LCDs. In case of homogeneous LCDs, the spot profile is same as optics itself because of no modulation of incident linear polarization. Fig. 11 This figure shows the rectangle phase grating with a phase delay of 0 and it is mathematically represented as eq. (1) and (2). Eq. (3) is its Fourier spectrum. From eq. (3), main factors of 0 and 1 st order are represented by these equations. Both orders are modulated to the phase of, but I st order has a component of ; modulation. This is the key to the polarization modulations. Fig. 12, 13 This is a sectional diagram of binary phase gratings using TN LCDs. Voltages are applied according to the grating patterns. The direction of the polarization vector rotate to 0 according to the intensity of the applied voltage. Naturally, maximum value of 0 is 90 deg. 0 means a phase delay. These are graphs of the polarization vector of 1 st and 0 order. In 1 st order, the phase of one component jumps to 7 . We can clearly see that the result polarization vector becomes different. In case of 0 order, the result starts from linear polarization of the X and then rotate and become elliptic. In case of 1 st order, it started from linear polarization of Y states and rotate and become elliptic quickly. Please not that this phenomena will not occur in homogeneous LCDs. Fig. 14 Those are experimental results of polarization modulation between 1 st and 0 order light. As expected, 0 order start from X and linear and 1 st order start from Y and liner. With voltage increases, both rotate and 1 st order become elliptic quickly. Fig. 15 Those are simulated results and they are almost fit to the experiments. But we neglect the influence of birefringent effects of LCDs. From these results, we can remove the 0 order light using polarization filtering and show its result later. Fig. 16 This figure shows the optics for electro-holography. The optics is almost equal to the conventional optical holography but the CCD and the LCTV-SLM are used instead for photographic films. As recording, the laser beams divided into two beams, one is called a reference beam and it travels CCD directly. The other beam called an object beam hit the object and then diffracted to the CCD. Those two beams will interfere on the CCD and make the holograms that incorporates 3D information of the object. The angle between these two beams on the CCD is set almost zero so that the career spatial frequency of the hologram is very low according to the resolution limit of the CCD and LCTV-SLM. The object is imaged on the CCD by this imaging lens making this hologram as an image hologram that can reconstruct by incoherent light. The bandwidth of the holograms are limited by this aperture. On reconstruction, the holograms are transferred and displayed on the LCTV-SLM that is illuminated by collimated laser beam. Because of the low career spatial frequency of the hologram, the direction of the 1 st and 0 order light is almost the same. So the spatial filtering technique is used to remove 0 order light that has no information of the objects. Power spectrum of the LCTV-SLM is recorded on this mask. We can see reconstructed image through this mask. Fig. 17 This figure shows typical spatial frequency response of our electro-holography. Please note that this includes the overall response of the CCD, LCTV-SLM, and their driving electronics. X axis shows spatial frequency of the LCTV SLM and Y axis shows normalized diffraction efficiency. According to the pure phase modulation characteristics, the efficiency using the homogeneous LCD is the best. Fig. 18 This is a photo of the object. Its size is about 10 mm. This is a hologram displayed on the CRT monitor. This is an image hologram, so that we can see the shape of the object. The career spatial frequency is set to 5 Jlp/mml and its bandwidth is set to 30 lp/mm&#x0005D;. This is a reconstructed image using homogeneous LCD and this is its binary modulation. We can see the brighter image. This is using a TN LCD. We can see clear images thank to the spatial filtering technique. But the low limit of the spatial frequency of the hologram, image quality is not so good. So that it is difficult to catch the substantial difference of each image. Further more, it is also difficult to catch the 3D information. As electro-holography, while object is moving also the image is moving in real time. But the image is disappeared during the moving periods. Importance of the results is that our SLM has an ability to apply 3D holograms and this is a first step to electro -holography using the LCTV-SLM. Fig. 19, 20, 21, Table 3 Fig. 19 shows the result of polarization filtering to TN LCD gratings. We can see that the 0 order light is almost removed. We apply this technique to our electro holography system and results are on fig. 20. We can see the image with polarization filtering. Fig. 21 and table 3 show our latest research products. Fig. 1 A schematic diagram of complex amplitude modulation of light using a 90 deg. TN liquid crystal cell. Fig. 2 Classification of LCDs Fig. 3 MIM diode and its characteristics Fig. 4 LC cell structures with MIM and MIM fabrication process using only two masks. Fig. 5 Photograph of a pixel with an MIM diode Fig. 6 V-1 characteristics of 2 and 3 mask MIM diode Fig. 7 A photograph of the LCTV-SLM Table 1 Specifications of the LCTV-SLMs Fig. 8 COG technology Table 2 Data IC specifications Fig. 9 Optical properties of Matrix LCDs Fig. 10 Beam spot profiles of power spectrum using LCD gratings (Binary modulation) and its measuring optics Fig. 12 Binary phase gratings using 90 deg. TN - LCDs (Sectional diagram) Fig. 13 Polarization vector of the diffracted light Fig. 14 Experimental results of polarization vector modulated by TN - LCD gratings Fig. 15 Simulated results of polarization vector modulated by TN - LCD gratings CL 0 1 &#x00025;o 0. (D Fig. 17 Typical spatial frequency responce of the electro-holography system using an LCTV-SLM Fig. 18 Experimental results of erectro holography using LCTV - SLMs Fig. 19 Power spectrum of TN - LCD gratings using polarization filtering Fig. 20 Reconstructed images from LCD holograms (a) with polarization filtering and (b) without polarization filtering Fig. 21 A photograph of the LCTV - SLM Table 3 Specifications of the LCTV-SLM</p>
<p>Summary Liquid crytal devices are suitable devices for SLMs because of thier strong dielectric anisotoropy and high - sensitivity to electric fields The high - resolution LCTV - SLMs using MIM active matrix technology have developed and they could apply 3D - holographic devices Properties of LCD gratings were investigated and the results could apply polarization filtering to remove 0 order light 3 M-pixel LCTVs using MIM technology were demonstrated</p></body></book-part></book-part-wrapper>
