<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
<collection-meta collection-type="conf">
<conference content-type="conf-name"><conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name><conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym></conference>
<conference content-type="conf-other-meta"><conf-date content-type="start">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-date content-type="end">
<day>19</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-loc>Nevada, 
<country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc></conference></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
<title-group>
<title>SLM Applications</title>
<alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/></title-group></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
<title-group>
<title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title></title-group>
<volume-in-collection>
<volume-number>14</volume-number>
<volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title></volume-in-collection></collection-meta>
<book-meta>
<book-title-group>
<book-title>Spatial Light Modulators</book-title></book-title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Burdge</surname><given-names>Geoffrey</given-names></name></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>Sadik C.</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group>
<pub-date publication-format="electronic">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></pub-date></book-meta>
<book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
<book-part-meta>
<title-group>
<title>Silicon Spatial Light Modulators for Atmospheric Aberration Compensation</title></title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Grasso</surname><given-names>Robert J.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Burns</surname><given-names>Brent E.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<aff id="aff1">
<label>1</label>Northrop Grumman Corporation Electronic and Systems Integration Division Electronic Systems 600 Hicks Road Rolling Meadows, IL 60008</aff></contrib-group>
<elocation-id>210</elocation-id>
<permissions>
<copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
<copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
<copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
<license license-type="open-access">
<license-p>closed</license-p></license></permissions>
<abstract>
<p>Northrop Grumman reports on a program utilizing a Silicon Light Modulator combined with Linear Phase Conjugation to compensate for atmospheric induced aberrations that severely limit laser performance. In a program to improve both the beam quality and laser energy delivered to the target, Northrop Grumman has developed a novel aberration compensation technique. This technique, hereafter referred to as Active Tracking System, utilizes a silicon Spatial Light Modulator as a dynamic wavefront reversing element to undo aberrations induced by the atmosphere, platform motion, or both. Northrop Grumman&#x02019;s aberration compensation technique results in a high fidelity, near-diffraction limited laser beam delivered to the target.</p></abstract>
<counts>
<book-page-count count="5"/></counts></book-part-meta>
<body>
<p>Introduction Atmospheric induced aberrations can seriously degrade laser performance, greatl affecting the beam that finally reaches the target. This is especially true for propagation over long distances in the atmosphere. Lasers propagated over any distance in the atmosphere suffer from a significant decrease in fluence at the target due to atmospheric aberrations. This is primarily due to fluctuations in the atmosphere over the propagation path. and fromthemotionoftheplatformrelativetothe intended aimpoint. Also, delivery of high fluence to the targettypicallyrequiresalowdivergencebeam,thus, atmospheric turbulence or platform motion results in a lack of fine aimpoint control to effectively keep the beam directed at the target. Northrop Grumman's Active Tracking System (ATS) continually tracks the target as well as compensates for atmospheric and platform motion inducedaberrations.Thisresultsinahighfidelity,near- diffraction limited beam delivered to the target. Energy deposited on target depends upon several factors including atmospheric turbulence strength, signal-to-noise ratio, and system latency time. With ATS, gains of one to several orders of magnitude increase in laser fluence at the targethavebeendemonstrated.Additionally,amultitude ofoperationalwavelengthsmaybeaddressedduetothe linear system architecture, and powers well in excess of I kW can be routinely handled with the use of silicon-based SLMs. With ATS, and as a result of the aberration compensationandtargettrackingcapability,laserswith very low divergence may be utilized. In this manner, a greater amount of laser energy is able to be delivered to the target. Some areas that can benefit from ATS include IRCM, EOCM, LIDAR, and laser radar.</p>
<p>Aberration Compensation Concept The ATS concept is illustrated in Figure 1: its operation consists of two discrete steps. In the acquisition step, a low power illumination laser transmits a highly diverging beam to the target. Ideally. the divergence of this acquisition beam is matched to the uncertainty of the target direction. An OA return is received. This return is collected and interfered with a reference beam from the local oscillator (LO) on an integrating focal plane array (FPA) detector to form an electronic hologram. The hologram isreadfromthe FPA. processed. andthe conjugate written to the spatial light modulator (SLM). In the engagement step, a beam from a second laser is reflected off the SLM. The SLM acts as a phase modulator and the reflected energy is contained in a beam that is the phase-conjugate of the target return. Now, this beam, which is the conjugate of the original beam, retracesthepathtothetarget. Duringthistime,any wavefront distortions are undone, thus resulting in near- diffraction limitedenergydeliveredtothetarget. By continually repeating the acquisition and engagement steps, moving targets can be tracked (whether the target is movingrelativetotheplatformortheplatformismoving relative to the target) and compensation performed for time varying aberrations in the atmosphere. Figure 1. ATS Operation The maximum energy-on-target enhancement factor for the high energy laser is equal to the number of SLM pixels multiplied by the hologram efficiency. . . .Figure 2. Bootstrapping Thus, Process for 64 x 64 pixel devices, and with a 0.4 hologram efficiency (the maximumefficiencyforaplane,binaryphasehologram) the enhancement factor is about 1640. Hence. the greater the number of SLM pixels, the greater the performance improvement that will be realized. Energy deposited at the target depends upon several factors including, atmospheric turbulence strength, signal-to-noise ratio, and system latency time, but gains of one to several orders of mantd. a eepceId . ATS provides automatic target acquisition within its field- of-view, as well as atmospheric aberration compensation. When compared Whencomare to conventional to onvntinaladapiveoptcal adaptive optical targets can schemes, no wavefront reconstruction algorithms are required. Additionally, when compared to all-optical phase conjugation schemes that require very high optical amplification factors, up to 105, amplification of the target return is not required. The energy of the propagated beam is limited only by the laser's maximum energy and the SLM damage limit. The homodyne process utilized in ATS exhibits the high gain of a coherent detection process without the field- of-view limitation characteristic of the heterodyne process. If desired, even greater sensitivity may be attained using a multiple-step "bootstrapping" process, whereby targets with a signal-to-noise ratio of much less thanunitycanbedetected.Itallowstargetacquisition with low initial photon counts. Bootstrapping is an iterative process that utilizes a sequence of pulses. each pulse corrected by the return from the preceding pulse. Here, the illumination laser is reflected off the SLM; even very noisy holograms will slightly increase the illumination energy on the target, resulting in a higher signal-to-noise ratio in the subsequent hologram. This iterative process typically converges to a maximum energy-on-target in three to four pulses. This bootstrapping process is depicted in Figure 2. An advantage of ATS, when compared to all-optical phase techniques. .is that the hologram that contains informationaboutthetargetandtheinterveningmedium iniso is available in electromic form. This information can be storedincomputermemoryandprocessedtoextract information aboutthetarget.Withtheveryhighprocessor ve . speeds available, this may be performed vry quickly. As an example, by computing the Fourier transform of the target direction relative to the optical axis is hotae.naese reltipetteta snt tagescanb ereed inte Fourierdoma n t aloigeunatreeggmn. in the Fourier domain, thus allowing sequential target engagement.</p>
<p>Subsystem Northrop Grumman has developed a novel silicon SLM capable of displaying the phase information required for atmospheric correction. This SLM behaves as a dynamic wavefront reversing element to undo aberrations induced by the atmosphere, platform motion, or both. A hologram formed on an FPA camera is transferred, pixel-by-pixel, to theSLM.Thishologram,theconjugateofthatformedon the FPA, contains both intensity and phase information abouttheinterveningmediumbetweentheSLMandthe target. Due to their close interaction, the FPA, hologram processor, and SLM form a single subsystem. Their interrelationshipisshowninFigure3. Figure 3. Camera. Hologram Processor.SLM Subsystem The SLM is fabricated using silicon micromachining techniques. Figure 4 shows a diagram of the SLM constructed of a movable (deformable) diaphragm and a backplate to which an interconnect board and driver electronics are connected. The diaphragm is subdivided into N by N pixels: each supported from the backplate by an oxide grid. Individual pixels are etched with a flexure region, thus deflecting in a piston-like motion. In practice, the SLM behaves in much the same manner as a phased array antenna. The backplate, constructed from a flat, thick piece of silicon, serves as a support for the pixelated diaphragm and a structural surface to maintain device rigidity. Electrostatic attraction between the conductive silicon diaphragm (ground potential) and a deflection electrode requires a modest voltage (~ 20 volts) to achieve deflection. The electrical connection from a deflection electrode to the X-Y addressable electronics through the interconnect passes through a via under each element. Additionally. this via serves as a vent for critical (fluid) dampingofthediaphragm. Figure 4. Design for N by N Pixel Silicon SLM The N rows of the FPA are read-out in parallel, converted from analog to digital signals, and written to the SLM. The detected hologram (digital FPA output) and the processed hologram (written to the SLM) are stored electronically for post-processing, if desired. Mathematically, an expression for the intensity forming the hologram pattern is givenby: H(i,j)- R(i,j 2 +co(i,j)R(i,j)-+-o(i,j)*R(i,j)+o(i,j 2 (1) where R(i,j) and o(i,j) are the complex electric fields ofhrfrneemnteojcbaapxli. of the reference beam and the object beam at pixel (i,j) . The reference beam profile, the first term on the right, must be nearly uniform across the FPA array while the object intensity, the fourth term on the right, must be small compared to the reference intensity. The second and third terms contain information about the target and the intervening medium. The homodyne detection SNR is given by the expression: 2nnorms o TR) (2) 2 SNR = nR +norms +n B +nD +n where nR, norms, nt, n), and n1 are the number of photoelectrons due to the reference beam, the object beam, the background, the detector dark-current, and the Johnson/readout noise, respectively. T and T, are the pulse width of the reference beam pulse and the object beam pulse, respectively. Ideally, these two pulse widths would be equal, but, in practice. T &gt; T, in order to reduce the required accuracy of the target-return arrival time. The primary function of the hologram processor is to subtract the reference intensity term as shown in Equation 1. This term represents the bias and can be subtracted since it does not contain any useful information. However, since its value is considerably larger than that of the information containing terms, this subtraction must be performed with a high degree of accuracy. The dynamic range of the FPA array and, hence, the number of bits in the analog-to-digital (A/D) converter is dictated primarily by the requirement to keep the object which acts as a noise term, small when compared to the other terms in the hologram expression. The magnitude of this term varies both spatially and temporally because of atmospheric scintillation. Analysis indicates that the minimum number of bits is about eight, with higher numbers desirable to improve performance and reduce the accuracy to which the target range must be known. The minimum FPA bucket size is primarily determined by the requirement that the Shot noise count due to the reference beam be greater than the noise count due to the other noise sources.</p>
<p>Performance ATS presents several distinct advantages as compared to a conventional approach: 1) since most targets are found using OA, bootstrapping can permit a system utilizing this concept to lock onto targets incorporating significant cross section reducing counter countermeasures (CCM); 2) ATS acquisition beam may be several times wider than with a system not utilizing this technique, thus reducing pointing accuracy requirements with regard to the search beam; 3) there is a significant increase in the energy-on-target, thus minimizing engagement laser energy requirements (delivering a high fidelity, near-diffraction limited beam over the laser propagation path is essential to laser damage applications): 4) the automatic. vibration-insensitive. pointing capabilitN eliminates the necessity for complex and expensive gimbals used in conventional pointing systems, and; 5) provision for sequential engagement of multiple targets within its field-of-view. Therefore, the output energy of the engagement laser may be significantly reduced, or, for a given engagement laser energy, the energy-on-target can be increased and the engagement range extended. Figure 5 and Figure 6 show the fraction of energy-on-target without ATS and with ATS, respectively, for various degrees of atmospheric turbulence, Cn2 . Here, the transmit aperture is 10 cm and the target has a 5 cm receive aperture: the wavelength selected is 0.85 pm. Notice in Figure 5, the non-compensated case, that the energy-on-target decreases rapidly as the Co increases. Thus, for a Cn of 1014 at a 3 km range, the energy-on-target would be about 0.015 of that from the engagement laser. Now, for the compensated case, Figure 6. and identical conditions for a Cn 2of 10 at a 3 KM range, the energy-on-target would be nearly 0.4 of that from the engagement laser. Therefore, if 10 mJ ofenergy is required on target, the non-ATS case would require a 670 mJ laser, while the compensated case would require only a 25 mJ laser; twenty-seven times more laser energy would be required for non-compensated laser case. Indeed, this would have a significant impact on system performance, size, weight, and cost, especially if greater energy or range performance is required. Figure6.TypicalPerformanceWithCompensation</p>
<p>TestResults Analytical,simulated,andexperimentalresultsofStrehl ratio (peak intensity to diffraction limited peak intensity) as a function of SNR is shown in Figure 7. Here, excellent agreement was obtained between theory and experiment, even at SNRs as low as 0.1. The difference between the analytical results and the computer simulations is due to the statistical nature of the noise. Figures 8 and 9 show computer simulations and experimental data, respectively, for bootstrapped operation. The top row in each figure shows the hologram written to the SLM and the bottom row.shows the resulting intensity distribution at the target plane. Experimental results are shown as an intensity profile through the peak intensity. Figure 7. Simulated and Measured Target Intensity versus SNR Figure 8. Bootstrapped Operation Model Predictions Figure 9. Bootstrapped Operation Experimental Results Performance tests were carried out both during the datime and at niht to a range of 3 km; target acquisition tests were performed to a range of 5 km. Test objectives were to compare the performance of ATS with the performance of a non-ATS system, without aberration compensation. The goal was to demonstrate a five-fold increase in energy-on-target as compared to the non-ATS system. In actuality, more than a seventy-five-fold increase in energy-on-target was demonstrated. Figure 10a shows the variance in energy-on-target without ATS. It is important to notice how distorted the beam appears over 3 km path. Figure 10b shows the improvement realized with ATS. Here, the near diffraction limited beam is clearly observed. Figure 10. Performance Improvement Realized with ATS</p>
<p>Summary It is quite apparent that ATS can provide tremendous gains in increasing the laser energy delivered to a target. When coupled with a laser radar, IRCM, or EOCM system, a high fidelity, near diffraction limited beam is delivered to the target. In most cases, this translates into either an increase in energy on target for a given laser energy, or a reduction in laser energy required to deliver a specific amount of energy to the target. With ATS, laser size, weight, and cost may be reduced therefore making certain IRCM, EOCM, and LIDAR, and laser radar applications feasible.</p></body></book-part></book-part-wrapper>
