<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
<collection-meta collection-type="conf">
<conference content-type="conf-name"><conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name><conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym></conference>
<conference content-type="conf-other-meta"><conf-date content-type="start">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-date content-type="end">
<day>19</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-loc>Nevada, 
<country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc></conference></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
<title-group>
<title>SLM Applications</title>
<alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/></title-group></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
<title-group>
<title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title></title-group>
<volume-in-collection>
<volume-number>14</volume-number>
<volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title></volume-in-collection></collection-meta>
<book-meta>
<book-title-group>
<book-title>Spatial Light Modulators</book-title></book-title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Burdge</surname><given-names>Geoffrey</given-names></name></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>Sadik C.</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group>
<pub-date publication-format="electronic">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></pub-date></book-meta>
<book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
<book-part-meta>
<title-group>
<title>A planarized LCOS display for projection applications</title></title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Schuck</surname><given-names>Miller H.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>McKnight</surname><given-names>Douglas J.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>Kristina M.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<aff id="aff1">
<label>1</label>University of Colorado at Boulder Optoelectronic Computing Systems Center Engineering Building Campus Box 525 Boulder, Colorado 80309-0525 (303) 492-3260</aff></contrib-group>
<elocation-id>250</elocation-id>
<permissions>
<copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
<copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
<copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
<license license-type="open-access">
<license-p>closed</license-p></license></permissions>
<abstract>
<p>We have constructed a 640 &#x000D7; 512 pixel Liquid Crystal on Silicon microdisplay. We shall describe the application driving the device development, the display device and the technology enhancements implemented for this application.</p></abstract>
<kwd-group kwd-group-type="OCIS">
<title>OCIS codes</title>
<kwd>Active-Matrix Liquid-Crystal Displays</kwd>
<kwd>Display Systems</kwd>
<kwd>Planarization</kwd></kwd-group>
<counts>
<book-page-count count="5"/></counts></book-part-meta>
<body>
<p>Introduction Liquid Crystal on Silicon (LCOS) spatial light modulators (SLMfs) and microdisplays are made by placing a thin layer of liquid crystal directly on top of a silicon chip. We have constructed a high speed 256 by 256 binary SLM which uses a ferroelectric liquid crystal as thelight modulatinglayer &#x0005B;I&#x0005D;. \Ve ha iso recentlyconstructed a high speed distorted helix effect analog 128 by 128 SliM &#x0005B;2&#x0005D; and a high voltaoe 128 by 128 analog SLM using the electrocinic effect in DHI1764E &#x0005B;3&#x0005D;. This workhas been motivated by the performance requirements of coherent applications which typically include high frane rate. small pixel pitch and good diffiaction efficiency into a single (zeroth) diffracted order. These devices have been successfilly used in optical correlators and holographic interconnect systems &#x0005B;4&#x0005D;. Liquid Crystal on Silicon Microdisplays The requirements for a projection displav system emlphasise different aspects of the device design. For example. in the automotive Iead Vp Display (HUD) application which is motivating our current device development &#x0005B;5&#x0005D;. we illuminate the liquid crystal on silicon device with over two orders of magnitude more optical power than in an optical correlator. This difference is important for the device design since photogenerated charges in the silicon substrate cause leakage currents which in turn lead to loss of image contrast. On our binary 256 by 256 device, which was optimized for single-order diffraction efficiency rather than optical power handling. the image begins to degrade at ~ 30mlV/cm2 of visible light illumination at 25.000 frames per second electronic refresh rate. In other respects. LCOS technology is well suited to display applications. The small size of the device can lead to a compact image engine for systems with packaging constraints and the high frame rates (kfz) available lend themselves for use in time-sequentil color and/or grey-scale schemes. We present results from a 6-10 x 512 color microdisplaY designed for this HD ap)plication.</p>
<p>Active-matrix backplane The mnicrodisplay's active-matrix backplane contains 640 x 512 DRAM-style pixels fabricated in a 1.2 pnm CMOS process. The pixel pitch is 21.4 un. giving the display a 0.7T diagonal active area. C(MOS circuitry was used for on-chip clocking and control. shift registers, and test structures. The backplane was designed for a nominal electronic refresh rate of 8,000 frames per second. The display is intended for field sequential color operation and was designed to operate in either digital or analog image display mode. In digital mode, the display is igutre 1: Photograph ofthe upper right corner of a planarized 640 x 512 pixel LCOS iicrodispla. capable of 9-bit total (3-bit per color) color at 100 Hz frame rate. In analog mode, the device provides 16 gray levels at 60 Hz frame rate. Alignment marks were also fabricated on the wafer to facilitate the planarization post-processing. The first die have been packaged and electrical testing of the devices is Underway. Figure 1 is a photograph of a corner of a planarized 640 x 512 pixel LCOS device. Backplane post-processing in planarizinga siliconbackplaine.a flat dielectric laveris forned above tlie device circuitry. The flat dielectric layer provides several benefits for image display levices. Finer resolution lithography is possible on the flatter surface, thus reducing the separation between pixel mirrors and increasing the pixel aperture ratio. High reflectivity metal can be deposited on top of the dielectric layer to form the device's mirrors. Increases in pixel aperture ratio and reflectivity improve the device's optical efficiency while simultaneously creating better light shielding of'the iiderlying pixel circuitry. In addition, the extra metal layer allows for underlying metal layers to be utilized as overlapping. interpixel shielding as well as low resistance addressing lines. Low resistance address lines are important for increasing display resolution while maintaining the frame rate and pixel pitch. For example, metal2 (sheet resistance 0.036 9 per square) can be used for pixel data and select addressing Iiieslin this three-mnetal processin place of pol ysilicon (sheet resistance 22 Q per square). The signal propagation delay, tt, along a long transmission wire is approximated by, Table 1: BCB planarization results summary where H, is tIIe iaterial sheet resistance, c is the line capacitance per unit length, I is the length of the wire. and uo is tIe width of the wire &#x0005B;6&#x0005D;. For sinlar line capacitances, this implies a reduction in signal delay for metal aldress lines of two orders in magnitude as compared to identically sized polysihicon address lines. The use ofmetal address and data lines allows larger hilher resolution displays to maintain high frame rates. The planarizing dielectric layer also hides complex pixel structures (e.g. SRAM el-enents, see &#x0005B;9&#x0005D;). providing enhanced display functionality without contributing to light scattering by nonuniform pixel structures. Finall., planarization appears to improve liquid crystal alignment layer uniformity, thus presenting a more uniform image to the observer's The planarization method we have pursued employs spin-coating Benzocyclobutene (13CB or Cyclotene by tradename &#x0005B;7&#x0005D;), a polymeric resin from the Dow Chemical Company, onto the silicon substrate. The resin is therinally cured. vias are dry etched. metal is deposited. and then patterned to produce upper layer mirrors. Thermal curing of the 13('13 can be rapidly performed (in 5 minutes). The local planarity of BCB is very good (a singole BCH coat can reduce the substrate step height by an order of magnitude) an( global planaritY is acceptable for HVD applications. Post-processing of the backplane was performed under the NSF-sponsored National Nanofabrication Users Network program at Stanford niversitY. Test wafers with via chains and large mirror arrays were fabricated first to verify tI plroces param eres a( unifornuity. Table I sunnarizes the results of our planarizationeflorts. lie average coating thickness measured at five points per wafer over six metal-on-silicon test wafers is 2.2-18 +/-0.039 pmi. Vias are drv etched in tle ICB layer usin(' 1 + 02 (average etcli rate 0.21 pm per minute) or SF- + 02 gas chemistries (0.25 pim per minute). For a 2 pm patterned via diameter, the resulting via diameter after dry etcing is 3.6pin. The average resistance measured over 1000 vias in a via chain is 0.75 per via. 5.000 angstroms of pure aluminumis then deposited as the upper mirror layer. The aluminum is dryetchedin a chlorine-based gas chemistry. The resulting mirror separation is 1.8pm, resulting in an 84 / fill-factor for 21. Ipm pixels.</p>
<p>Conclusions We presented results on a 610 x .512 pixelliquid-crystal-over-silicon (LCOS) microdisplay intended for projection applications. The backplane was designed to operate in digital (9-bit total field sequential color at 100 Hz frame rate) or analou modes (16 ray levels per color at 60 Hz frame rate). Electrical testing of the backplane is underway. A spin-cast resin method of planarizing LCOS backplanes was developed. The method provides excellent dielectric layer uniformity, reasonable dry etch rates, good via diameters, low via resistances, and high pixel fill-factor. The planarization and post-processing improves device parameters such as optical efficiency and light shielding while maintainiig high frame rates with increasing device resolution and size.</p>
<p>Acknowledgements This work is supported by the National Science Foundation and Ford Motor Company through the Optoelectronic Computing Systems Center at the University of Colorado at Boulder and the Nanofabrication Facility at Stanford University. The authors would like to thank the Dow Chemical Company for supplying materials and technical assistance in the planarization work. We would also like to thank the staff at the Stanford Nanofabrication Facility for their support and technical expertise during the post-processing.</p></body>
<back>
<ref-list>
<ref id="r1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>McKnight</surname><given-names>D. J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>K. M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Serati</surname><given-names>R. A.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>Applied Optics</source> <volume>33</volume>(<issue>14</issue>), <fpage>2775</fpage>-<lpage>2784</lpage>(<fpage>199</fpage>-<lpage>1</lpage>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>McKnight</surname><given-names>D. J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>K. M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Follet</surname><given-names>M. A.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>Optics Letters</source> <volume>20</volume>, <fpage>5</fpage>, (<year>1994</year>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>McKnight</surname><given-names>D. J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Serati</surname><given-names>S. A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>K. M.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>Ferroelectrics</source> <volume>181</volume>, <fpage>171</fpage>-<lpage>177</lpage>, (<year>1996</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/00150193.1996.10399415</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="confproc"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>O&#x02019;Brien</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>McKnight</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name></person-group> <conf-name>International Conference on Optical Computing Technical Digest IOPP 1555</conf-name>, <fpage>245</fpage>-<lpage>246</lpage>, (<year>1994</year>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="confproc"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Schuck</surname><given-names>M. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>McKnight</surname><given-names>D. J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>K. M.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>Proc. of SID International Symposium</source>, <conf-loc>San Diego</conf-loc>, (<year>1996</year>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Weste</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name><name><surname>Eshraghian Principles</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source> of CMOS VLSI Design</source> <publisher-name>Addison-Wesley</publisher-name>, (<year>1993</year>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r7"><label>7</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><source>Cyclotene 3022 advanced electronic resins. Technical Data Manual</source>, <publisher-name>Dow Chemical Company</publisher-name>, (<year>1994</year>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r8"><label>8</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Underwood</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></name><name><surname>Vass</surname><given-names>D. G.</given-names></name><name><surname>O&#x02019;Hara</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Burns</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>McOwan</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Gourlay</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>Applied Optics</source> <volume>33</volume>(<issue>14</issue>), <fpage>2768</fpage>-<lpage>2774</lpage>, (<year>1994</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/AO.33.002768</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r9"><label>9</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Breslin</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Underwood</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>OSA Optics in Computing</source>, <publisher-loc>Lake Tahoe</publisher-loc>, <series>SLM Technical Digest</series> <fpage>105</fpage>-<lpage>107</lpage>, (<year>1997</year>)</mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></book-part></book-part-wrapper>
