<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0"
  xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <collection-meta collection-type="conf">
    <conference content-type="conf-name">
      <conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name>
      <conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym>
    </conference>
    <conference content-type="conf-other-meta">
      <conf-date content-type="start"> <day>17</day> <month>03</month> <year>1997</year></conf-date>
      <conf-date content-type="end"> <day>19</day> <month>03</month> <year>1997</year></conf-date>
      <conf-loc>Nevada, <country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc>
    </conference>
  </collection-meta>
  <collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
    <title-group>
      <title>SLM Applications</title>
      <alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/>
    </title-group>
  </collection-meta>
  <collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
    <title-group>
      <title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title>
    </title-group>
    <volume-in-collection>
      <volume-number>14</volume-number>
      <volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title>
    </volume-in-collection>
  </collection-meta>
  <book-meta>
    <book-title-group>
      <book-title>Spatial Light Modulators</book-title>
    </book-title-group>
    <contrib-group>
      <contrib contrib-type="editor">
        <name>
          <surname>Burdge</surname>
          <given-names>Geoffrey</given-names>
        </name>
      </contrib>
      <contrib contrib-type="editor">
        <name>
          <surname>Esener</surname>
          <given-names>Sadik C.</given-names>
        </name>
      </contrib>
    </contrib-group>
    <pub-date publication-format="electronic">
      <day>17</day>
      <month>03</month>
      <year>1997</year>
    </pub-date>
  </book-meta>
  <book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
    <book-part-meta>
      <title-group>
        <title>Applications of SLMs to phased array antennas and optical correlators</title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <name>
            <surname>Rajbenhach</surname>
            <given-names>Henri</given-names>
          </name>
          <xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <name>
            <surname>Dolfi</surname>
            <given-names>Daniel</given-names>
          </name>
          <xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <name>
            <surname>Huignard</surname>
            <given-names>Jean-Pierre</given-names>
          </name>
          <xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref>
        </contrib>
        <aff id="aff1"> <label>1</label>Thomson-CSF, Laboratoire Central de Recherches Domaine de
          Corbeville, F-91404 Orsay, <country country="FR">France</country></aff>
      </contrib-group>
      <elocation-id>170</elocation-id>
      <permissions>
        <copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
        <copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
        <copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
        <license license-type="open-access">
          <license-p>closed</license-p>
        </license>
      </permissions>
      <abstract>
        <p>We review two applications of liquid crystal SLMs: Optically controlled phased array
          antenna and optical correlators for biometric identification.</p>
      </abstract>
      <counts>
        <book-page-count count="27"/>
      </counts>
    </book-part-meta>
    <body>
      <p>Introduction We review two applications of liquid crystal SLMs: Optically controlled phased
        array antenna and optical correlators for biometric identification. Phased array antenna
        Wide instantaneous bandwidths will be required intlie future active phased array antennas.
        As multifunction antennas they will be used in a variety of operating modes such as radar,
        comlunications and countermeasures. &#x0005B;he far field patiern of a phased arrav antenna
        is controlled by the relative phase and the amplitude distribution of microwave sipnals
        emitteId by regnuarlv spaced radiatin Cleieints. Microwave phasese hIspOVidlehighly
        directiVe but ereatly requIe dependeit IIcy iiCrowIve bean steeriiIIg.or radars with a wide
        in.Ntantaneous bandwidth and couitermeasure systems, time delay neworks have to he
        introduced. In this case the antenna far-field pattern is not altered when the frequency is
        scanned or when a wide spectrum is radiated. Delays equivalent to the size of the antenna
        ire necessary to perfoiin a 450 deinonstration scan agle over a wide frequeicy bandwidth.
        Optoelectronic architectuires, with thein paalmIlel processine and low loss transmission
        capabilities are ;ttractive for tiie dcla heam forminie The operating principle of our 2D
        optical architectrc 3 is dItIiled ini. 1. A dual frequencV I;iser eam is the optical carrier
        of theicowvI'e sienal.This bean is expanded an travels throuh i set of SIMs with thesame
        number of pixels (pxp) as the numiber of raditig elements of (ithe atenna. M is a parallely
        aligned nematic liquid crystal SL.M. It coitrols the phase of the microwave signal by
        cliainging the relamive optical phase of the cross polari/ed componemts of ie ditl freqicncv
        beam. At the output ofNI. the hincrly oluized dual freqtcncv heam intercepts ;I set of
        spatial lieit modulators SLIM,. polarizing heam splitlers PBS 1and prisms P, They providc
        thei parllel control of the time delys assmicd to thei itcnna The heam polaizatio can he
        rotaited by 00( or 9 on each pixel. Accordine to the polairization, PBS, is trnsparent (and
        the light heam intercepts the iiext SI M,,,) or rellective (tnd the microwave sienal is
        delaved). The colhimited beam travels throliug all the (PBS,) and is focused by an ;rrav of
        lmicroleises (.) onto an ;ray of pxp fiber pitiiled photodiodes (Pl)A). For a given
        phoutxliodc, the phase of the microwave heatine sienal is determined by tlie applied vollage
        on the correspotnding pixel of 1 and by the choice of the PBS, on which &#x0005B;he
        Ielectios occur. Since the positions of prisms Pi provide delay values accordin to a
        geometric progression (t, 2T, 4T.), fie beating signal can be delayed ftom 0 to (2N-1)T with
        step t. The switching time of this architecture is mainly determined by the response time of
        the liquid crystal SLMs and can take advantage of their high resolution. To provide high
        speed switching, one can use ferroelectric liquid crystal SLMs. The response time of the
        analog control of the phase delays by Mo can be redned to 200 ps With chiral smectic liquid
        crystals. 4 Moreover, ina realistic radar application, even such lone switchine times can be
        handled. Resolution of liquid crystal SLIMs (up to 103 x 103) the number ofradiatin elements
        of die aantenna. It is then possible to replicate die image of the antenna M times on each
        SLMi (p x p x M pixels) and to use a high speed (10 ns) integrated optic lxM coupler placed
        just before BE (fig.1) to switch between the iinaes. We have recently completed the
        experimental optically controlled phased array antenna, operating between 2.5 and 3.5 GIIz.
        3 The 2D architecture is implemented widt 6 SLMs of 4 x 4 pixels. It provides 32 delay
        values (5 bits), an analog control oftlie phase &#x0005B;0.27t&#x0005D; and permits the
        control of a 16 element plased array antenna. Fig.2 displays an example of the microwave
        beam deflection using time delays. Furthermore, when far field patterns at differeit
        frequencies are superposed for a given scan direction (Fig.3). one cai notice the absence of
        any beai squiIIt. Based on this demonstrator (Fi,.4) it is realistic to extend these
        concepts to a much larger number of radiatine elnemts (tip to 103 - 104) with 26 to 211
        delay Ivles i iorder to piovide low sidelobe anays. A global comipaIct architecture forthe
        optoClectronic processing of both radar transnit and receive modes is furthermore under
        study. It could greatly benefit from recentt dvances ofoptical interconccts 5 and computer
        hologram -enerated technologies,6 taking advantage of a holographic backplane scheme 3 in
        orlde to solve the problems of coipaictness. reliability and scaling up to the millimeter
        wave frequelcies.</p>
      <p>Optical correlation for identification Biometrni recognition is of great interest in a wide
        range of validation, identificatio, and population conrol Ipplicatios. 7
        Fingerprintidentification is most piomising althomgh the two major issues are die speed of
        recogiition and tie image distortions diat oci in the lingerprilnt acquisition step, when a
        Spatial finger is placed in contact with a prism or paper. ImaeC correlation provide a
        global and fast approach, but can handle only a limited level of distortions. We present a
        non-contact fingerprint acquisition technique (Fig.5) that significantly improves the
        recognition performance of our correlator. 8-9 In a first approach, the finger is covered
        with a metallic powder, then presented, "nail-against-the-guideo a camera. The finger is
        illuminated by a rin white light soice through a polarizer. An analyser is placed in trot of
        the objective of the camera. A depolarization in the crests of the fingerprint occurs.
        Conversely, the ride lines, covered withi metal, preserve the polarization of the light and
        are thus clearlyvisible. The inerprint imae is veri vood: pores on the ridees can heseen
        (Fi. 5, B). For some applications covering a finger with a metallic powder is not
        acceptable. Inthuis case, the second alternative involves a digital processingater CCD
        idetection. parallel polariver/aiulyserorientation exploits the depolarization effects in
        the fingerprint crests. A digital filter provides contist enhancement and gtood image
        quality (Fig. 5, B). The main advantage of these techniques is that from acquisition to
        acquisition, there is no fingerprint image modification. Optical correlators provide the
        opportunity for processing fingerprint images at high speed.9 -11 The optical layout of our
        coelation demonstrator) is shown Fig. 6. It operates as follows: Reference R, originate from
        a fast access hard disk memory, while the unknown fingerprint is captured with the non-
        contact sensor. The two video signals are mixed to generate a single video image which
        represents the intensity distribution R, + S. This intensity distribution is relaved to a
        coherent optical beam with the use ofa SLM ( 428 x -44 pixels with pitch 31 x 46 pm). A
        mnini-YAG visible green laser is spatillv expanded and is modulated by the image on the SIM.
        A specially designed Fourier transform lens system generates the complex Fourier transform
        field. which is recorded in the photorefractive BSO material. The photoinduced phase
        hologram is read out under Bragg direction by a plane wave from a 3mW red laser diode. The
        diffracted field amplitude undergoes Fourier transform throughthe same optical lens and
        provides the correlation pcak atthe CCD sensor. The whole optical system is3(100 x 00 x 15
        m1m (Fi 7). Qualitative experimental results are shown in Fig.S. The distortions between two
        independaill acquisitions with a classical prisml senlsor arc clarly seen onl thle top
        pictures. Theresuling correlation peak is low. Independent acquisitionsmising our new
        non-contact fingerprint sensor ae shown in the middle pictures. Almost no distorsion cal he
        seen. ad (lthe associated correatioi peakislarge. Finally, the bottom picures Iepicts the
        results of correlation using our non- contact technique. \witlh o metal powderon Ihe Fig. 5:
        Non-contact tingerprint acquisition techniqu: The finger ispresented "nail-against-the-
        guide" to thecmera; P,Polaiei; A, Analyser. (A): with metal powder; (B): with digital
        contrast enhancement Fig. 6: Optical layout of the photorefractive joint transform conelatoi
        -0OIW3Ol55017001750 IW IO0,O IO -G.020 Fig.3 : Superposition of the far field patterns,
        obtained by time delay scanning, for frequencies ranging from 2.7 to 3.1 GHz and for a 80
        scan angle - no beam squint (amplitude in dB). Fig.4 Experimental set-up :4 x 4 channels, 32
        time delays (5 bits 17.5 , 35 , 70 , 140 , 280 mm), 7 bit phase control between 0 and 2T.
        Article 02: Untitled finger, but witha digital filter to enhance the image contrast. The
        correlation peak is still high. Preliminary quantitative experiments have so far involved
        the non-contact acquisition of 10 individuals. The recognition of a single person on this
        limited data base is always successful, with no false rejection. A statistical analysis
        using a larger data base will provide the False Acceptance Rate (FAR) and the False
        Rejection Rate. Our current measurements show a FAR smaller than 1&#x00025;. The authors
        thank the D.R.E.T. (Direction des Recherches, Eludes et Techniques) for partial support, the
        radar divisions of Thomson-CSF, S. Sanouilhan and J. Colin for their contributions. Fie.1 :
        Time and phase delays for phased array antenna : (BC) frequency shifter Bragg cell - (Aj):
        microwave amiplifiers - (E): radiating elements. Fi'.2 : Far field pttern of the opticaly
        controlled phiased array antenna :time I . (, delay scanning. between 0and 200 - a a
        ttfrequency3.1 Glzu(nplitude dB)</p>
    </body>
    <back>
      <ref-list>
        <ref id="r1">
          <label>1</label>
          <mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name>
            <surname>Mailloux</surname>
            <given-names>R. J</given-names>
            </name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<source>Phased array antenna handbook</source>&#x0201D;
            (<publisher-name>Artech</publisher-name>, (<year>1994</year>)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="r2">
          <label>2</label>
          <mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name>
            <surname>Zmnuda</surname>
            <given-names>H.</given-names>
            </name><name>
            <surname>Toughlian</surname>
            <given-names>E.N.</given-names>
            </name></person-group>, "<article-title>Photonic aspects of modem radar</article-title>"
            <source>Artech</source>, (<year>1995</year>)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="r3">
          <label>3</label>
          <mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name>
            <surname>Dolfi</surname>
            <given-names>D.</given-names>
            </name><etal/></person-group>, <source>Appl Opt</source>
            <volume>35</volume>(<issue>5293</issue>) <fpage>1996</fpage></mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="r4">
          <label>4</label>
          <mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name>
            <surname>Stockley</surname>
            <given-names>J.E.</given-names>
            </name><etal/></person-group>, <source>Opt Lett</source>, <volume>20</volume>
            <fpage>2441</fpage>, <year>1995</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi"
            >10.1364/OL.20.002441</pub-id></mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="r5">
          <label>5</label>
          <mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name>
            <surname>Song</surname>
            <given-names>S.H.</given-names>
            </name><etal/></person-group>, <source>Appl Opt</source> <volume>34</volume>
            <fpage>5913</fpage> <year>1995</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi"
            >10.1364/AO.34.005913</pub-id></mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="r6">
          <label>6</label>
          <mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name>
            <surname>Xu</surname>
            <given-names>F.</given-names>
            </name><etal/></person-group>, <source>Appl Opt</source>
            <volume>34</volume>(<issue>256</issue>) <fpage>1995</fpage></mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="r7">
          <label>7</label>
          <mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name>
            <surname>Newham</surname>
            <given-names>E.</given-names>
            </name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>The biometric
            report</article-title>&#x0201D;, <source>SJB Services Editor</source>,
            <publisher-loc>Somerton U.K</publisher-loc>., <fpage>1995</fpage></mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="r8">
          <label>8</label>
          <mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name>
            <surname>Samouilhan</surname>
            <given-names>S.</given-names>
            </name><etal/></person-group> <source>Proc. SEE &#x0201C;12&#x000E8;me journ&#x000E9;es
            d&#x02019;&#x000E9;tude du cercle d&#x02019;opto-informatique&#x0201D;</source>
            <publisher-loc>Paris</publisher-loc>, <year>1996</year></mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="r9">
          <label>9</label>
          <mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name>
            <surname>Rajbenbach</surname>
            <given-names>H.</given-names>
            </name><etal/></person-group>, <source>Proc SPIE</source> <volume>2752</volume>,
            <fpage>214</fpage>, <year>1996</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi"
            >10.1117/12.235653</pub-id></mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="r10">
          <label>10</label>
          <mixed-citation publication-type="patent"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name>
            <surname>Horner</surname>
            <given-names>J.L.</given-names>
            </name><etal/></person-group>, <source>US patent</source> <patent>5,485312</patent>,
            (<year>1996</year>)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="r11">
          <label>11</label>
          <mixed-citation publication-type="patent"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name>
            <surname>Tomko</surname>
            <given-names>G.</given-names>
            </name><etal/></person-group>, <source>US patent</source> <patent>WO 96/08093</patent>,
            <fpage>1996</fpage></mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    </back>
  </book-part>
</book-part-wrapper>
