<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
<collection-meta collection-type="conf">
<conference content-type="conf-name"><conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name><conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym></conference>
<conference content-type="conf-other-meta"><conf-date content-type="start">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-date content-type="end">
<day>19</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-loc>Nevada, 
<country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc></conference></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
<title-group>
<title>Integration and Packaging Techniques</title>
<alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/></title-group></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
<title-group>
<title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title></title-group>
<volume-in-collection>
<volume-number>14</volume-number>
<volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title></volume-in-collection></collection-meta>
<book-meta>
<book-title-group>
<book-title>Spatial Light Modulators</book-title></book-title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Burdge</surname><given-names>Geoffrey</given-names></name></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>Sadik C.</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group>
<pub-date publication-format="electronic">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></pub-date></book-meta>
<book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
<book-part-meta>
<title-group>
<title>DNA-Assisted Assembly of Photonic Devices and Crystals</title></title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>Sadik</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Hartmann</surname><given-names>Daniel</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>G&#x000FC;n&#x000E7;er</surname><given-names>Selim</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Fan</surname><given-names>Chi</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Heller</surname><given-names>Mike</given-names></name><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff"><sup>2</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Cable</surname><given-names>Jeff</given-names></name><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff"><sup>2</sup></xref></contrib>
<aff id="aff1">
<label>1</label>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, 0407 University of California at San Diego 9500 Gilman Drive La Jolla, CA 92093-0407</aff>
<aff id="aff2">
<label>2</label>Nanotronics Inc. 10398 Pacific Center Court, San Diego, CA 92122</aff></contrib-group>
<elocation-id>65</elocation-id>
<permissions>
<copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
<copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
<copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
<license license-type="open-access">
<license-p>closed</license-p></license></permissions>
<abstract>
<p>DNA self-recognition properties are investigated for the heterogenous integration of optoelectronic devices. Preliminary experimental results and their application to Smart Pixels and photonic crystals are reported</p></abstract>
<kwd-group kwd-group-type="OCIS">
<title>OCIS codes</title>
<kwd>DA-assisted self-assembly</kwd>
<kwd>Integrated optical devices</kwd>
<kwd>Photonic crystals</kwd>
<kwd>Optoelectronics</kwd></kwd-group>
<counts>
<book-page-count count="4"/></counts></book-part-meta>
<body>
<p>The progress made in Ill-V photonic devices and the practical necessity for their use with silicon chips make Heterogenous Integration (HI) techniques attractive for fast information handling hardware systems. This necessity has led to the adoption of the flip-chip bonding technique to build hybrid heterogenous chips such as CMOS-SEED Smart Pixels. However, in addition, to flip-chip bonding and various monolithic integration techniques based on heteroepitaxy, new hybrid integration methods that are potentially more cost effective, performant and flexible such as epitaxial lift-off, and wafer fusion bonding are emerging. These hybrid techniques are based on the transfer of thin film devices originally fabricated on mother substrates onto a silicon host substrate. With these hybrid techniques unless sophisticated pick and place systems capable of handling micron size devices can be developed e.g., by robotics precision assembly&#x0005B;l&#x0005D;, the layout of the host substrate remains severely restricted by the layout and dimensions of the mother substrate. To remove this important limitation, self-assembly techniques such as the fluidic self-assembly &#x0005B;2&#x0005D; based on geometrical similarity or DNA based self-assembly techniques &#x0005B;3,4&#x0005D; based on the self-recognition properties of DNA, become attractive. In this paper, we report a novel DNA assisted assembly process and discuss its application to the construction of Smart Pixels and photonic crystals. This technique promises to further enhance the capabilities of photonic devices, enlarging their application span and paving the way for a potential VLSI-Photonics revolution for information systems. Synthetic DNA polymers show good promise for assisting the assembly of photonic devices onto an electronic mother board. This is due to the fact that the two strands of a DNA molecule have complementary base pairs providing an inherent self-organization mechanism. An (A)danine base on one strand will hybridize only with a (T)hymine base on the other, while a (G)uanine base has a (C)ytosine complement. For example. strands of DNA having the base sequence ATTTGC can be attached to a substrate in places where we want optical devices to be attached. We shall call this DNA the &#x0201C;capture&#x0201D; DNA. The complementary sequence of TAAACG can be attached to the optical devices. When brought together, the capture and complementary DNA strands will naturally tend to hybridize, resulting in the self-assembly of the optical devices on the substrate at the locations where the capture strands were placed. Using this technique, it is possible to position optical components at very precise locations on a substrate. Experimentally, we have used artificially synthesized &#x0201C;capture&#x0201D; and &#x0201C;complementary&#x0201D; DNA strands with a desired sequence of bases. The sequence of bases was designed to minimize the possibility of intra-strand (self-) hybridization, while maximizing the strength of inter- strand hybridization. The DNA strands averaged 20 base- pairs (60 A) in length. Strands of this average length were long enough to be robust, while remaining short enough to be reproduced easily. To demonstrate the selective attachment of DNA to a substrate, the &#x0201C;capture&#x0201D; DNA strands were densely deposited n SiOcoateds ilicon wafer that had been functionalized with amine groups. The wafer was then patterned itheithereUV light having awavelength ofp255 amnoran electron-beamn. In either case, exposed capture DNA molecules lost the ability to hybridize with their complementary DNA strands. The complementary DNA strands were conjugated to fluorescent molecules in a sodium phosphate buffer and pipetted onto the substrate. Hy',bridization occurred between the fluorescently-tagged complementary DNA and the unexposed capture DNA on the substrate. Figure I shows the resulting patterned fluorescence. The minimum resolvable spot size in this picture is approximately 10 pm. One of the practical considerations that must be addressed is the size of the object (or photonic device) that can be positioned using the DNA self-assembly processes. Preliminary experiments to determine size constraints were performed using polystyrene beads. First, the capture DNA strands were attached to amine-coated non- fluorescent polystyrene beads, having diameters of 0.871 om and 3.1 pm. Both complementary and non- complementary DNA strands were conjugated to fluorofores in a sodium phosphate buffer. The fluorescently-labeled complementary DNA was mixed in one vial with the beads. The fluorescently-labeled non- complementary DNA was mixed with beads in a second vial, and served as a control. Both vials of bead-fluorofore solutions were centrifuged, and excess solution was pipetted off, leaving the beads in the vials. Fresh sodium phosphate buffer was added to the vials, and the beads were redistributed in the new solution. The centrifuging and diluting steps were repeated at least one more time. We then looked at the bead-fluorofore solutions under a UV (=350 nm) light. The bead solution that had been mixed with the complementary-DNA-conjugated fluorofores was brighter than the control solution (containing the non-complementary DNA) for both the 0.871 pm beads and the 3.1 pm beads. This indicates that capture DNA had successfully been conjugated to the heads, and was hybridizing with the fluorescently-tagged complementary DNA. The 0.871 pm beads exhibited a more pronounced difference between the control and complementary solutions than did the 3.1 pm beads. This suggests that the capture DNA conjugation was more effective with smaller beads--perhaps because the larger beads had a smaller number of surface amine groups. To illustrate the movement of beads on a substrate, tluorescent polystyrene beads that had been coated with negatively-charged surface functional groups, and having diameters of up to 10.4 pm, were placed in an aqueous solution on a 5x5 array of contact pads. Using a probe- card, one contact pad was biased positively, while the 1ig. 1. D\A ioh conjugated 11uorofores hybridized to a patterned Silicon substrate Minimum spot size is 10pm remaining 24 were given a negative bias. Under the influence of this potential difference, the charged beads selectively conglomerated around the positively-charged pad. When the positive bias was applied to a different pad the beads migrated to this new position on the wafer. A similar experiment was conducted using fluorescent beads up to 10.4 pmin diameter and just two active pads-one biased positively, the other negatively. Again, we observed the beads moving under the influence of the electric field. These experiments demonstrate the possibility of moving relatively large optical devices in an aqueous solution under the influence of an applied electric field. Theseresultssuggestthatsmall devices (micron size) can be positioned onto desired areas on a host substrate by the utilization of the self recognition property of DNA polymers. When fully developed, this approach will provide the distribution of various thin film devices (electronic, optical, fluidic and possibly micromechanical) onto processed silicon chips in an arbitrary fashion in one single step without any geometrical or layout restrictions imposed by the mother nor the host substrates. Thus for example a dense array of photonic devices fabricated on a modest dimension mother substrate can be distributed sparsely on a large host substrate. In addition because individual devices can be controlled selectively, the technique allows for the utilization of only &#x0201C;known-good- devices&#x0201D; with a potential to significantly improving system yields. This assumes that the testing of photonic devices can be accomplished at low cost prior to the removal from host substrates and the DNA assembly process. Furthermore, this approach can have an important impact in the low cost manufacturing of wavelength encoded Smart Pixels in that VCSELs and/or detectors of different wavelengths fabricated on different substrates can be brought together on a single substrate thereby allowing accurate control of the spatial as well as spectral behavior of the arrays. Other potential applications include various type of displays and heterogenous RF ICs. In the remainder of this paper, we would like to illustrate the revolutionary capabilities of this approach by describing its potential impact on the synthesis of photonic crstals. Photonic crystals are artificial lattices comprised of various materials with different dielectric constants. When the dielectric variation is on the order of the optical waxelength, an optical wave entering the medium is diffracted either constructively or destructively depending the phase condition. The diffraction of the electromagnetic \\ae can lead to a decrease in the electromagnetic density of states and result in a photon-forbidden bandgap in the optical spectrum. Our first target in constructing the photonic crxstal using the DNA self-assembly technique is to form a two-dimensional structure. A honeycomb confiizuration shown in Figure 2 is one of few two- dimensionalstructuresknownto exhibitafullphotonic andap for both TE and TM polarized light &#x0005B;5&#x0005D;. Fig.2: A cross-sectional view of a honeycomb structure with infinite rods We have calculated the optical field dispersion in a honeycomb periodic structure consisting of infinitely long dielectric rods in air. The dispersion for TE and TM waves was calculated along the irreducible wedge defined by the K. F. and Msymmetry points of the hexagonally shaped Brillouin zone of the honeycomb lattice. Maxwell's i.3: Diapersion relation of ato-dimensional honeycomb aroddihameter nith tospacing ratioonf0.5 Fi.4: 160 nm fluorescent beads hxbridized to patterned wafer equationforthemagneticfieldxwassolvedusingplane wvave expansion of the fields and the dielectric constant&#x0005B;6&#x0005D;. Figure3 showsabandgapforthetwotransverse electromagnetic fields centered at a frequency approximately equal to 0.6cav where c is the speed of light in vacuum, and a is the spacing between rods. The hexagon structure has a lattice period larger than the rod spacing by a factor of V . In the calculation, the ratio of the rod diameter to the structure spacing between rods is 0.5, which corresponds to approximately the optimum ratio for the largest photonic bandgap We have conducted experiments that demonstrate the feasibility of constructing two dimensional photonic crystals using the DNA self-assembly technique. Capture DNA was conjugated to a SiO,-covered silicon wafer that had been functionalized with amine groups. The wafer was then patterned using UV light. The complementary DNA strands were conjugated to amine-functionalized fluorescent beads of up to I pm in diameter. The beads were released in an aqueous solution on the substrate, and hybridized to the unexposed capture DNA. Figure 4 shows fluorescent beads 160 nm in diameter hybridized to the patterned substrate. A two dimensional photonic crystal might be realized in a similar fashion. by placing beads, on a honeycomb-patterned substrate. In summary, DNA assisted assembly relies on the self recognition propert\ of artificial DNA polymers as a selective glue&#x0201D; to bring together devices with incompatible layout and structures. In this paper, we have presented results on attachment of DNA onto metallic and semiconducting materials. In addition, deposited DNA strands have been lithographycally patterned using UV exposure. DNA strands being charged negatively have been used to control the movements of devices from 10nm to 10tm in size under the influence of an electric field. Finally, patterned DNA strands deposited to a host substrate hybridize with complementary DNA strands attached to individual devices, bonding them in a self aligned fashion to the desired location on the host substrate. We have argued that this technology can impact more than one area in photonics, including the synthesis of photonic crystals. Yet much research remains to be performed before this technique can be used in an performed ndustrialenvironment.Tonaeafewareth efiroretio tnie an bwareasu n ane fluidically self-assembled ter presently investigating we should cite further characterization of bonding strengths, and process yields, demonstration of selective bonding of multiple set of photonic devices (e.g., LED's with different wavelengths), and formation of ohmic contacts to the grafted devices. Acknowledgments The authors would like to thank Susan Wey for helpful discussions about photonic dicusonsabutph cs . beenfunddby5. J. D. Joannopoulos. R. D. Work at UCSDhasbeen fundedbyagrantfrom AFOSR. Work at Nanotronics was funded by a grant from ROME Laboratory, United States Air Force.</p></body>
<back>
<ref-list>
<ref id="r1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Smith</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Carson</surname><given-names>R.F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sullivan</surname><given-names>C.T.</given-names></name><name><surname>McClellan</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Monolithic integration of waveguide structure with surface-micromachined polysilicon actuators</article-title>.,&#x0201D; <source>Proceedings of SPIE</source> <volume>2722</volume>, <fpage>75</fpage>-<lpage>81</lpage>, (<year>1996</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1117/12.240431</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Talghader</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Tu</surname><given-names>J.K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Smith</surname><given-names>J. S.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Integration of fluidically self-assembled optoelectronic devices using a silicon-based process</article-title>&#x0201D; <source>IEEE Photonics Technology Lett</source> <volume>7</volume>, <fpage>1321</fpage>-<lpage>3</lpage>, (<year>1995</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1109/68.473485</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Mirkin</surname><given-names>C.A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Letsinger</surname><given-names>R.L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Mucic</surname><given-names>R.C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Storhoff</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>A DNA-based method for rationally assembling nanoparticles into macroscopic materials</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Nature</source> <volume>382</volume>, <fpage>607</fpage>, (<year>1996</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/382607a0</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Alivisatos</surname><given-names>A.P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Johnsson</surname><given-names>K.P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Peng</surname><given-names>X.G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wilson</surname><given-names>T.E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Loweth</surname><given-names>C.J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bruchez Jr</surname><given-names>M.P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Schultz</surname><given-names>P. G</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Organization of &#x02018;nanocrystal molecules&#x02019; using DNA</article-title>&#x0201D;, <source>Nature</source> <volume>382</volume>, <fpage>609</fpage>, (<year>1996</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/382609a0</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Joannopoulos</surname><given-names>J.D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Meade</surname><given-names>R.D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Winn</surname><given-names>J.N.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<source>Photonic Crystals: Molding the Flow of Light</source>&#x0201D; , <publisher-name>Princeton University Press</publisher-name>, (<year>1995</year>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Villeneuve</surname><given-names>P.R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Piche</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Photonic Bandgaps in Periodic Dielectric Structures</article-title>.&#x0201D; <source>Prog Quant Electr</source> <volume>18</volume>, <fpage>153</fpage>, (<year>1994</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/0079-6727(94)90007-8</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></book-part></book-part-wrapper>
