<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
<collection-meta collection-type="conf">
<conference content-type="conf-name"><conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name><conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym></conference>
<conference content-type="conf-other-meta"><conf-date content-type="start">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-date content-type="end">
<day>19</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-loc>Nevada, 
<country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc></conference></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
<title-group>
<title>SLM Materials and Sructures</title>
<alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/></title-group></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
<title-group>
<title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title></title-group>
<volume-in-collection>
<volume-number>14</volume-number>
<volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title></volume-in-collection></collection-meta>
<book-meta>
<book-title-group>
<book-title>Spatial Light Modulators</book-title></book-title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Burdge</surname><given-names>Geoffrey</given-names></name></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>Sadik C.</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group>
<pub-date publication-format="electronic">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></pub-date></book-meta>
<book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
<book-part-meta>
<title-group>
<title>Spatial Light Modulators with Polymeric Thin Film Fabry-P&#x000E9;rot Etalons</title></title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Harada</surname><given-names>Kenji</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Munakata</surname><given-names>Katsuhiro</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Itoh</surname><given-names>Masahide</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Yoshikawa</surname><given-names>Nobukazu</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Yatagai</surname><given-names>Toyohiko</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Yonezu</surname><given-names>Hiroo</given-names></name><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff"><sup>2</sup></xref></contrib>
<aff id="aff1">
<label>1</label>Institute of Applied Physics, University of Tsukuba and Tsukuba Advanced Research Alliance Tennohdai 1-1-1, Tsukuba, Ibaraki 305, 
<country country="JP">Japan</country></aff>
<aff id="aff2">
<label>2</label>Department of Electrical and Electronic Engineering, Toyohashi University of Technology Toyohashi Aichi 441, 
<country country="JP">Japan</country></aff></contrib-group>
<elocation-id>127</elocation-id>
<permissions>
<copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
<copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
<copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
<license license-type="open-access">
<license-p>closed</license-p></license></permissions>
<abstract>
<p>An electrically addressable spatial light modulator with a spin-coated azo-dye/polymer thin film sandwiched with Fabry-Perot etalon is designed for optical information processing and display. Transmissivity of the device was electrically modulated. The contrast ratio of 70:1 was obtained at 1kHz with 15V ac applied voltage.</p></abstract>
<kwd-group kwd-group-type="OCIS">
<title>OCIS codes</title>
<kwd>Spatial light modulator</kwd>
<kwd>Fabry-Perot etalon</kwd>
<kwd>Polymeric material</kwd>
<kwd>Electrooptic effect</kwd></kwd-group>
<counts>
<book-page-count count="5"/></counts></book-part-meta>
<body>
<p>Introduction Spatial light modulators (SLMs) play very important roles for optical computing. including optical neural network and optical image processing. Advances in SLM technologies therefore have a direct impact on these critical application. Liquid crystal SLMs generally used in optical computing have a very slow modulation speed and a low contrast ratio. Development of sophisticated SLMs with both very fast modulation speed and high contrast ratio is essential. One of the candidates for SLM material is nonlinear organic materials which have large optical nonlinearity. Some organic materials offer a lot of advantages such as large variety of molecular structures with large nonlinearities and quick electro-optical responses. Polymeric materials is one of the most promising organic materials for nonlinear applications. Their fabrication is easy compared with growing single crystals of organic and inorganic materials- moreover, the dielectric constants of polymeric materials are generally 1/10 that of LiNbO3. This makes it possible to operate polymer devices at very high frequency. Operation at 40 GHz was demonstrated with poled polymer optical modulator. In recent years. considerable progress has been made in the development of nonlinear organic materials having large nonlinearities and thermal stability. Some poled polymers have large electrooptic coefficient r comparable to that of LiNbO3. Very advanced materials using DRI9 of ris=40- 60pm/V was reported. It is enough electrooptic coefficient for awaveguide light modulator to control the light. but not enough for a spatial light modulator because the effective optical pass length is much shorter than that of a waveguide light modulator. It can be solved by using the Fabry-Perot etalon structure because it increases the effective optacal pass length acting across the spacer region and minimizes the drive voltages. We will discuss here the advantages of these materials and the development of SLMs using them. We have simulated and demonstrated the clectrically induced changes in light intensity using polymeric thin film in a Fabry-Perot structure.</p>
<p>Polymeric Spatial Light Modulators with a Fabry-Perot Structure A limited number of research has been done on SLMs with polymeric film. An electronicallv addressable SLM is designed here for optical information processing and display (Fig. 1). Figure 1. Electrically addressable SLM with polymeric materials. It is composed of a dielectric mirror, a polymeric thin film. transparent electrodes. a planarization layer and a VLSI processor. The polymeric films which have a large electrooptic coefficient make it possible to achieve a high modulation speed and high contrast ratio. The use of a Fabry-Perot etalon is proposed to minimize the driving voltages(Fig. 2) Each mirror is composed of Si02(n=1.46) and TiO2(n=2.35) of 17 layers. The reflectivity of the dielectric mirror is 99.4&#x00025; at the wavelength of 633nm. The device shows a sharp shr spectrum in i specific seii wavelength aelnt determined by the polymer film thickness and refractive index. We can control the intensity of Figure 2. Resonator structure for polymeric materials.</p>
<p>Simulations We simulated the light modulation of the polymeric thin film Fabry-Perot device. We have previously shown that Fabry-Perot devices are useful as electrooptic devices. A film poled in the direction of the surface normal has the electrooptic tensor can be expressed as where r33=3r13. For an electric field in the direction of the surface normal(z-direction), the equation for the refractive index ellipsoid is wherm Nire X, Y. and Z refer to the laboratory axes parallel to the principal dielectric axes parallel to the principal dielectric axes of the film, and no and ne are the ordinary and extraordinary refractive indices respectively. On application of an electric field in the direction of surface normal, the change in refractive index experienced by ordinary ray is thus. 13 An- =-n r3 Ez (2) 02/ 2 2 and for the extraordinary rays. An, = nfrlEz (3) 2 Changes in the indices of refraction experienced by the ordinary ray can be related to the modulation voltage ' by the expressions, using (3) as 13 V An, = n r (4) 2 01 where I is the separation of the two ITO electrodes. This induced A, changes the device transfer characteristics by a phase change in the polymeric laver. Figure 3 shows the simulation of the change in transmissivity by applying dc voltage when film thickness was 3 n. film refractive index was 1.6. dielectric mirrors had 17 layers, and electrooptic coefficient was 2pm/V. In this simulation, there is no optical loss of the sample, and there is no change of the reflectivity of the dielectric mirrors when applied voltage. We can control the intensity of monochromatic light by applying electric field. Figure 4 shows the calculation of the monochromatic light modulation. The contrast ratio in this case is estimated about 20:1 when the applied voltage is 10V/m.</p>
<p>Experiment We used a system consisting of disperse red 1 (DRI) doped poly-methyl-methacrylate(PMMA). Figure 3. Simulation of changes in trans- missivity by applying electric field when film thickness=3 t m, electrooptic coefficient=2pm/V. and dielectric mirror= 17layers. Figure 4. Simulation of changes in trans- missivityat633nmwhenfilmthickness=3 electrooptic coefficient=2pm/V. and dielectric mirror=17layers. Theazodyedispersered I(4-&#x0005B;N-tl--(2- do. is the nonlinear optic dopant molecule. PMMA is the polymermatrixmaterial.Themeasuredelectro- optic coefficientr3 ofDR(3wt&#x00025;)/PMMAwas p a v of632.8nMnAwam thickness film of DR1(1Owt&#x00025;) doped PMMA is prepared by spin coating on a ITO glass plate with dielectric mirrors. After baking at 90C for 30 min to remove the solvent, corona depositing poling was performed to align the chromophore orientation. Then the sample was sandwichedbetweendielectricmirrors(Fig.2). Using experimental setup shown in figure 5. changes in transmissivity were observed by applying an ac voltage across the device and monitoring the transmitted light using a photo detector. Figure 6 shows the results of measurements of the changes in transmissivity of an unpoled DR1/PMMA film. Unpoled DR1/PMMA film has the center of inversion and has no electrooptic effect, these modulation are not by the electro-optic effect but by the mechanically induced changes in thickness due to compressive stress generated by attraction of the charged cavity mirrors. To separate any mechanical effects from the electro-optic effect. we measured the higher harmonics of the modulation frequency. Any mechanical effects will be observed at the second harmonic frequency. since the attractive force between the plates of a charged capacitor is proportional to the square of the modulation voltage. Figure 7 shows the results of modulation of poled DR1/PMMA at 1kHz. In this experiment. no mechanical effect was observed. Figure 8 shows the frequency response of the developed sample. The roll off occurred at 30kHz because of the electrical characteristics of the Fabry-Perot etalon. The contrast at IkHz was 70:1 when the applied voltage was 15V. Figure 5. Experimental setup. Figure 6. Light modulation of unpoled DR1/PMMA at 10kHz. 15V. (Upper: output signal) Figure 7. Light modulation of poled DRI/PMMA at 1kHz. 15V. (Upper: output signal)</p>
<p>Conclusions In conclusion. an electrically addressable high speed SLM is designed using polymeric thin film with Fabry-Perot etalons for optical information processing and display. The contrast ratio of 70:1 was obtained by applying ac voltage of i l5V. This contrast ratio is, to our knowledge. the largest modulation of the light intensity by electrooptic effect (may include some converse piezoelectric effect )13 Fabry-Perot etalons have response limitations as a function of cavity finesse and cavity length. 1) Very high modulation speed cannot be expected using a resonator structure with large cavity finesse, but the modulation of devices with polymeric materials in our experiment was much faster than that of liquid crystal SLMs. These SLMs with nonlinear organic materials could be used for many applications in optical computing field.</p>
<p>Acknowledgements We wish to thank Nihon Kagaku Engineering Co.Ltd. for making dielectric mirrors. This research was partly supported by a Grant-in-Aid for Scientific Research from the Ministry of Education. Science, Sports and Culture of Japan and by the Yatagai Project. Tsukuba Advanced Research Alliance. University of Tsukuba.</p></body>
<back>
<ref-list>
<ref id="r1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>S.C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Horner</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>K.M.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Spatial light modulators and their applications: introduction by the guest editors</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Appl Opt</source> <volume>31</volume>, <fpage>3879</fpage>, (<year>1992</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/AO.31.003879</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Levine</surname><given-names>B.F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bethea</surname><given-names>C.G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Thurmond</surname><given-names>C.D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lynch</surname><given-names>R.T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bernstein</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>An organic crystal with an exceptionally large optical second-harmonic coefficient: 2-methvl-4-nitroaniline</article-title>.,&#x0201D; <source>J Appl Phys</source>, <volume>50</volume>, <fpage>2523</fpage>-<lpage>2527</lpage>, (<year>1979</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.326248</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Singer</surname><given-names>K.D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sohn</surname><given-names>J.E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lalama</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Second harmonic generation in poled polymer films</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Appl Phys Lett</source>, <volume>49</volume>, <fpage>248</fpage>-<lpage>250</lpage>, (<year>1986</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.97184</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Burland</surname><given-names>D.M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Miller</surname><given-names>R.D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Walsh</surname><given-names>C.A.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Second-order nonlinearlity in poled polymer systems</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Chemn Rev</source> <volume>94</volume>, <fpage>31</fpage>-<lpage>75</lpage>, (<year>1994</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/cr00025a002</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Teng</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Traveling-wave polymeric optical intensity modulator with more than 40 GHz of 3-dB electrical bandwidth</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Appl Phys Lett</source>, <volume>60</volume>, <fpage>1538</fpage>-<lpage>1540</lpage>, (<year>1992</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.107482</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Jungbauer</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Reck</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Twieg</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>D.Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wilson</surname><given-names>C.G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Swalen</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Highly efficient and stable nonlinear optical polymers via chemical cross-linking under electric field</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Appl Phys Lett</source>, <volume>56</volume>, <fpage>2610</fpage>-<lpage>2612</lpage>, (<year>1990</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.102853</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r7"><label>7</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Becker</surname><given-names>M.W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Dalton</surname><given-names>L.R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ranon</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Shi</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Steier</surname><given-names>W.H.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>New random main-chain, second-order nonlinear optical polymers</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Macromolecules</source> <volume>25</volume>, <fpage>6716</fpage>-<lpage>6718</lpage>, (<year>1992</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/ma00050a052</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r8"><label>8</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Aramaki</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Okamoto</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Murayama</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Cross-linked poled polymer: poling and thermal stability</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Jpn J Appl Phys</source>, <volume>33</volume>, <fpage>5759</fpage>-<lpage>5765</lpage>, (<year>1994</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1143/JJAP.33.5759</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r9"><label>9</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Harada</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Itoh</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yatagai</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Development of spatial light modulators with nonlinear organic materials</article-title>.,&#x0201D; <source>Opt Rev</source> <volume>3</volume>, <fpage>440</fpage>-<lpage>442</lpage>, (<year>1996</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF02935954</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r10"><label>10</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Williams</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></name></person-group>, in <source>Nonlinear Optical Properties of Organic Molecules and Crystals 1</source>, <person-group person-group-type="editor"><name><surname>Chemla</surname><given-names>D.S.</given-names></name> and <name><surname>Zyss</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name></person-group> (<publisher-name>San Diego Academic Press</publisher-name>, (<year>1987</year>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r11"><label>11</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Singer</surname><given-names>K.D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kuzyk</surname><given-names>M.G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sohn</surname><given-names>J.E.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Second-order nonlinear-optical processes in orientationally ordered materials; relationship between molecular and macroscopic properties</article-title>.,&#x0201D; <source>J Opt Soc Am B</source>, <volume>4</volume>, <fpage>968</fpage>-<lpage>976</lpage>, (<year>1987</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/JOSAB.4.000968</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r12"><label>12</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Eich</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sen</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Looser</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bjorklund</surname><given-names>G.C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Swelen</surname><given-names>J.D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Twieg</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>D.Y.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Corona poling and real-time second-harmonic generation study of a novel covalently functionalized amorphous nonlinear optical polymer</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>J Appl Phys</source>, <volume>66</volume>, <fpage>2559</fpage>-<lpage>2567</lpage>, (<year>1989</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.344220</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r13"><label>13</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Eldering</surname><given-names>C.A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Knoesen</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kowel</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Use of Fabry-P&#x000E9;rot devices for the characterization of polymeric electro-optic films</article-title>.,&#x0201D; <source>J Appl Phys</source>, <volume>69</volume>, <fpage>3676</fpage>-<lpage>3686</lpage>, (<year>1991</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.348960</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r14"><label>14</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Eldering</surname><given-names>C.A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Dienes</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kowel</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Etalon time response limitations as calculated from frequency analysis</article-title>.,&#x0201D; <source>Opt Eng</source>, <volume>32</volume>, <fpage>464</fpage>-<lpage>468</lpage>, (<year>1993</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1117/12.61057</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></book-part></book-part-wrapper>
