<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
<collection-meta collection-type="conf">
<conference content-type="conf-name"><conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name><conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym></conference>
<conference content-type="conf-other-meta"><conf-date content-type="start">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-date content-type="end">
<day>19</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-loc>Nevada, 
<country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc></conference></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
<title-group>
<title>SLM Materials and Sructures</title>
<alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/></title-group></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
<title-group>
<title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title></title-group>
<volume-in-collection>
<volume-number>14</volume-number>
<volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title></volume-in-collection></collection-meta>
<book-meta>
<book-title-group>
<book-title>Spatial Light Modulators</book-title></book-title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Burdge</surname><given-names>Geoffrey</given-names></name></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>Sadik C.</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group>
<pub-date publication-format="electronic">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></pub-date></book-meta>
<book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
<book-part-meta>
<title-group>
<title>Field-Dependent Birefringence of an Electroclinic Organosiloxane Liquid Crystal</title></title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Lindle</surname><given-names>J. R.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Bartoli</surname><given-names>F. J.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Flom</surname><given-names>S. R.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Ratna</surname><given-names>B. R.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Shashidhar</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<aff id="aff1">
<label>1</label>Naval Research Lab, Washington, DC 20375</aff></contrib-group>
<elocation-id>107</elocation-id>
<permissions>
<copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
<copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
<copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
<license license-type="open-access">
<license-p>closed</license-p></license></permissions>
<abstract>
<p>The field-dependent birefringence is measured for an electroclinic organosiloxane liquid crystal, designated as DSiKN65. The measured field-induced change in the birefringence is large and can produce a modulation of the transmission comparable to that produced by the electroclinic effect. The induced change is attributed to a field induced optical biaxiality and is shown to be strongly correlated to the tilt angle. Optical biaxiality is shown to augment the electroclinic effect and enhance the achievable contrast ratio.</p></abstract>
<kwd-group kwd-group-type="OCIS">
<title>OCIS codes</title>
<kwd>Liquid crystals</kwd>
<kwd>Liquid crystal devices</kwd>
<kwd>Spatial light modulators</kwd></kwd-group>
<counts>
<book-page-count count="4"/></counts></book-part-meta>
<body>
<p>Introduction The growing desire for spatial light modulators with grey-scale capability and a fast response has stimulated interest in the development of new electroclinic liquid crystals with large tilt angles. The achievable contrast ratio in these devices is limited by the magnitude of the tilt angle as well as by a field-induced deformation of the smectic layers which degrades the extinction. Recently, it was shown that field-induced changes in the birefringence can also contribute significantly to the electro-optic response &#x0005B;1&#x0005D;. In this paper, optical phase retardation measurements are performed to investigate the field dependence of the birefringence and the contrast ratio for a new electroclinic liquid crystal, designated a DSiKN65, which has recently been synthesized and which exhibits both a large electroclinic tilt angle (&gt;22.50 ) and a fast response (&lt;100s) &#x0005B;2&#x0005D;. The first observation of a large field- dependent optical biaxiality in this material is reported. The implications on these results on device performance will be discussed.</p>
<p>Experimental Sample Preparation and Characterization The molecular structure of DSiKN65 is shown in Fig. 1; its synthesis is reported elsewhere &#x0005B;2&#x0005D;. The phase transition sequence of DSiKN65 is: SmC*-- 40.5C--SmA*--55C--I. This material was loaded in temperature-controlled commercial glass cells whose interior surfaces were coated with ITO electrodes and with a rubbed polyimide alignment layer. The cell thickness was measured interferometrically prior to filling. The sample was aligned using a bipolar electric field (5V/pm) applied as the sample was slowly cooled from the O CH3 CH3 CH 3 C- S 0-c /- O -CH-CH, CH3 CH3 NO, Figure 1. Molecular structure of DSiKN65. isotropic to the Sm A* phase. Spectra of DSiKN65 show that it is transparent in the visible and near-IR spectral regions.</p>
<p>Dispersion of the Birefringence The birefringence and its dispersion were determined by measuring the transmission of the sample as a function of wavelength using a Perkin Elmer spectrometer which was modified to position the sample between polarizers. This technique allows one to determine uniquely the birefringence of the liquid crystal and its dispersion. The results are presented in Fig. 2. The curve through the data is a best fit calculated using the following expression for the transmitted intensity &#x0005B;3&#x0005D; I = Io&#x0005B;cos2(X)-sin(20)sin(20 -2X)sin 2(6 /2)&#x0005D; (1) where 10 is the incident intensity, X is the angle between the polarizer and analyzer, 4 is the angle of the long molecular axis relative to the orientation of the polarizer, 6 is the phase angle introduced by Figure 2. Transmission of 10.4 tm thick DSiKN65 sample interposed between parallel polarizers as a function of wavelength. The sample temperature is maintained at 420 C in the SmA phase. the sample birefringence, An. (=27tAn d/,where d is the samplethickness and is the wavelength of light.) Anisassumedtobeoftheform&#x0005B;41 (2) where A0 is the mean resonance wavelength of the liquid crystal and G is a temperature-dependent parameter which depends on the anisotropy in the oscillator strength, the order parameter of the liquid crystal, and the density of active electrons. The dispersion of the birefringence is determined from computer simulations using G and A0 as fitting parameters. The results, presented in Fig. 3, reveal that the birefringence depends significantly on the wavelength in the visible spectral region. The best fit was obtained for G(T) 1.327 Pm-2 and A0=0.2175 pim. Figure 3. Dispersion of the birefringence of DSiKN65 at 420 C determined by fitting the data in Fig. 2.</p>
<p>Electro-optic Properties of DSiKN65 The electro-optic properties were determined by measuring the sample transmission placed between polarizers using a fixed wavelength. Measurements were performed using a chopped CW HeNe laser operating at 594 nm. This wavelength was chosen to provide a large change in transmission with field (see Fig. 2) subject to laser availability constraints. The laser output was mechanically chopped at 12.5 Hz with a 5&#x00025; duty cycle and field dependent measurements were made by synchronizing bipolar square electrical pulses with the optical pulses. The optical pulses sampled the same polarity throughout these studies. In these studies, the polarization of the laser was rotated while the sample remained stationary. This was accomplished by mounting a Babinet-Soleil adjusted for half-wave retardation at the laser wavelength, in a computer controlled rotation stage. The analyzer was also mounted in an automated rotation stage which could be rotated in tandem while maintaining either a parallel or crossed polarization configuration. With the sample removed, the extinction ratio was approximately 10 through a 3600 rotation.</p>
<p>Results and Discussion  The measured crossed-polarized transmission as a function of polarization angle for several values of the applied field is presented in Fig. 4 for a 10.4 pm thick DSiKN65 sample maintained at 45 0C. The field dependence of the electroclinic tilt angle, the birefringence and its field-induced change, and the contrast ratio are determined from the data in Fig.4. Figure 4. Crossed-polarized transmission as a function of polarization angle for a 10.4 um thick DSiKN65 sample subjected to electric fields of OV/'m (lowest data set), 1.OV/um, 1.9V/pm, 2.9V/LIm, 4.8V/pm, and 7.3V/pm (highest data set). The sample temperature was 450C and the laser wavelength was 594 nm.</p>
<p>Electroclinic Tilt Angle  In Fig. 4, the angular shift in the position of the maxima and minima with applied field is due to the electroclinic tilt angle. The electroclinic tilt angle determined from Fig. 4 is plotted in Fig. 5. It increases monotonically with field (approximately linearly up to 7.3V/pm) in agreement with the published results of Naciri, et al &#x0005B;2&#x0005D;. At 9.7V/ptm, the tilt angle exceeds 22.5 degrees, the angle necessary for maximum contrast ratio. Figure 5. Field dependence of the electroclinic tilt angle.</p>
<p>Field-induced Change in the Birefringence The field dependence of the birefringence is determined from simultaneously fitting the crossed- polarized data (Fig. 4) and the corresponding parallel-polarized data (not shown) using Eqn. (1). The change in the amplitude of the transmission maxima with field in Fig. 4 is a manifestation of a field-dependent birefringence. The measured birefringence at 594 nm with no applied fieldis 0.071 and its change with field, 8An, isplotted in Fig. 6. Experimentally, 8An was found to vary with the applied field, in agreement with theoretical predictions for field-induced biaxiality. The curve through the data illustrates this quadratic field dependence. The field-induced increase in An is quite large for DSiKN65 (-30&#x00025;) Figure 6. The field dependence of the change in the birefringence, .An, detennined by itting the curves in Fig. 4 using Eqn. (1) The line through the data is a quadratic fit. when compared to KN125 (&lt;5&#x00025;) &#x0005B;1&#x0005D; and produces a phase retardation greater than quarter wave. The change in the birefringence is attributed to a field-induced optical biaxiality. Although the molecules are biaxial, the random orientation produced by the free rotation about the long axis of the molecule makes these materials macroscopically uniaxial. When a field is applied, the free rotation is hindered due to the preferential alignment of the transverse dipole moment with the field, producing an increase in the birefringence and making the sample optically biaxial. Fig. 7 illustrates that the induced biaxiality is strongly correlated and varies quadratically with the electroclinic tilt angle. A similar coupling of the optical biaxiality and electroclinic effect has been previously observed in KN125 &#x0005B;1&#x0005D;. This coupling has significant implications for device applications. Figure 7. Dependence of optical biaxiality on the electroclinic tilt angle.</p>
<p>Contrast Ratio The contrast ratio, defined as the ratio of the transmission with an applied field to that with no applied field, can be calculated using the data in Fig. 4. Although not fully optimized, a contrast ratio greater than 100 was observed for DSiKN65. Fig. 4. illustrates that the modulation of the transmission due to the induced optical biaxiality may be comparable to that produced by the electroclinic effect. Thus, both induced biaxiality and electroclinic tilt can be exploited to optimize the contrast in devices fabricated from this material. This may be particularly important in device design since low voltage operation is usually preferred.</p>
<p>Conclusion In conclusion, the electroclinic tilt angle, birefringence, and contrast ratio of a new electroclinic liquid crystal, DSiKN65, have been measured. This material possesses a large electroclinic tilt angle (&gt;250 at 10 V/pm) and exhibits a large induced optical biaxiality associated with the hindrance of the free rotation about the long molecular axis. The induced biaxiality is strongly correlated with the tilt angle indicating that a common mechanism is responsible for both. It augments the electroclinic effect and can be exploited to optimize the contrast in devices fabricated from this material. Contrast ratios greater than 100 have been measured.</p>
<p>Acknowledgments The authors wish to thank the Office of Naval Research for support of this research and J. Naciri for synthesizing the liquid crystals studied here.</p></body>
<back>
<ref-list>
<ref id="r1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Bartoli</surname><given-names>F.J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lindle</surname><given-names>J.R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Flom</surname><given-names>S.R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Selinger</surname><given-names>J.V.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ratna</surname><given-names>B.R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Shashidhar</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Field-induced optical biaxiality in chiral, smectic-A liquid crystals</article-title>.&#x0201D; <source>Phys Rev E</source> <volume>55</volume>, <fpage>R1271</fpage>, (<year>1997</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevE.55.R1271</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Naciri</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ruth</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Crawford</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Shashidhar</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ratna</surname><given-names>B.R.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Novel ferroelectric and electroclinic organosiloxane liquid crystals</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Chem Mater</source> <volume>7</volume>, <fpage>1397</fpage>, (<year>1995</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/cm00055a019</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Born</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wolf</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>Principles of Optics</source>, <edition>5</edition><sup>nd</sup> Ed (<publisher-name>Pergamon Press</publisher-name>, <publisher-loc>New York</publisher-loc>, (<year>1975</year>)<fpage>695</fpage></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Birefringence dispersion of liquid crystals</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Phys. Rev</source>. <volume>A33</volume>, <fpage>1270</fpage>, (<year>1986</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevA.33.1270</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></book-part></book-part-wrapper>
