<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
<collection-meta collection-type="conf">
<conference content-type="conf-name"><conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name><conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym></conference>
<conference content-type="conf-other-meta"><conf-date content-type="start">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-date content-type="end">
<day>19</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-loc>Nevada, 
<country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc></conference></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
<title-group>
<title>SLM Materials and Sructures</title>
<alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/></title-group></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
<title-group>
<title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title></title-group>
<volume-in-collection>
<volume-number>14</volume-number>
<volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title></volume-in-collection></collection-meta>
<book-meta>
<book-title-group>
<book-title>Spatial Light Modulators</book-title></book-title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Burdge</surname><given-names>Geoffrey</given-names></name></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>Sadik C.</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group>
<pub-date publication-format="electronic">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></pub-date></book-meta>
<book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
<book-part-meta>
<title-group>
<title>Modeling Electric Field Induced Effects in PLZT EO Devices</title></title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Shames</surname><given-names>Paul E.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>Pang-Chen</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Fainman</surname><given-names>Yeshayahu</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<aff id="aff1">
<label>1</label>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering University of California, San Diego 9500 Gilman Drive, La Jolla, CA 92093-0407</aff></contrib-group>
<elocation-id>121</elocation-id>
<permissions>
<copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
<copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
<copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
<license license-type="open-access">
<license-p>closed</license-p></license></permissions>
<abstract>
<p>PLZT 8.8-9.5/65/35 electrooptic (EO) devices subject to electric fields on the order of 1 <sup>v</sup>/<sub>&#x003BC;m</sub> can become highly scattering and depolarizing as well as exhibit high-order EO effects. We describe a method of modeling EO modulators that encounters for these effects. Utilizing these characteristics in simulating Surface electrode devices we compare our model to measurements of a fabricated device and find excellent correlation.</p></abstract>
<kwd-group kwd-group-type="OCIS">
<title>OCIS codes</title>
<kwd>PLZT modeling</kwd>
<kwd>Scattering and Depolarization</kwd>
<kwd>Optical Characterization</kwd>
<kwd>Mueller Matrices</kwd></kwd-group>
<counts>
<book-page-count count="3"/></counts></book-part-meta>
<body>
<p>Introduction Applying the advances in electronic and optical computer aided design (CAD) to optoelectronic systems requires precision simulation of electrooptic (E)devices.Inthispaperwe presentasimplebut accurate method of modeling EO devices using, as an example, lanthanum-modified lead titanate zirconate (PLZ) wth ompsitons .X/5/3. Tese are ferroelectric fereeticraisaetogEefcsnae ceramics have strong EO effects and cost effective and are therefore excellent candidates for use in optoelectronic systems. In the absence of field the ceramic is optically isotropic whereas an applied field induces anisotropy and optical birefringence. This electrooptic response has been modeled as a classic Kerr quadratic effect &#x0005B;1&#x0005D; as well asacombinationoflinearandquadraticeffects&#x0005B;2&#x0005D;. However,thesetechniquesfallshortofaccurately modeling fabricated devices, which will be required foelecatvi s. frotecrnIcCAtol. have developed a simple method of charaerizingasa mplet et.PLZT a sample of EO material (e.g. PLZT) using a set of equations that relate scattering, depolarization and electrooptic effect to applied electric field. By integrating these responses with the of the field, for given device geometries anddrivingvoltages,wehaveachievedexcellent correlation to experimental data. In this paper we describe our EO characterization and device modeling, with an emphasis on comparisons of computer simulation to fabricated devices.</p>
<p>TransmittanceModelandCharacterization Previous work &#x0005B;3&#x0005D; and experimental evidence shows experiences depolarization due to multiple scattering Therefore, we use the coherency matrix efecs formalism, Thrfr,. which describes s echrnymti partially polarized light bytakingi ntochcntpariandupolarized by taking into account polarized and uinpolarized intensity of a monochromatic plane wave transmitted through our apparatus. For example, for linearly polarized light passing through crossed polarizers set at 45' the equation relating transmitted intensity to change in relative phase is given by I = + B +2C+&#x000B1;2 coB (1) 4 whereAandBrepresentthepolarizedlightintensity measured along the two orthogonal basis and C is the unpolarized component, 4 is the change in relative phase between the two orthogonal components. Choosing four pairs of angles, for the incident polarizer and analyzer, gives four equations which are used to solve for the relative change in By sandwiching our PLZT sample between two large, parallel, gold-plated copper plates we generate a constant field inside and outside the ceramic. The distance between plates and the thickness of the PLZT give us the electric field strength and interaction length, respectively. We experimentally measure the normalized optical intensity for various orientations of the polarizer/analyzer pairs (see Figure 1). For incident light polarized at 45' with a parallel analyzer we see a sinusoidal variation of the intensity as the relative phase is changed with applied voltage, as predicted in Eq. 1. In the measurement of the vertical (00) and horizontal (90') components we see the effects of scattering and depolarization as the field is increased. Figure 1. The sinusoidal curve is the transmission through parallel polarizers oriented at 450 to the direction of the electric field. The mismatch between this curve and the 'envelope' is due to a wedge shaped PLZT sample that results in slightly varying path length within the sampled region. UsingthetransmissiondatafromFigure1,we solve for the change in relative phase 4as a function of electric field (see Figure 2). To accurately curve fit the EO data we need to use at least a fifth order polynomial, indicating that the EO behavior of these PLZTceramics cannot be fully described bythe Figure 2. The change in relative phase is shown for the PLZT 8.9/65/35 composition.</p>
<p>Device Modeling For a plane wave propagating through a PLZT device we can use a standard index ellipsoid approximation &#x0005B;4&#x0005D; to find the index change for any two orthogonal polarization components of the light. We use a commercial finite element analysis (FEA) tool to calculate the electric field distribution for arbitrary device geometries. By integrating the change in index of refraction, scattering and depolarization data with the calculated electric field components we can determine the change in index as a function of position for any given device geometry. incident beam linearly polarized at 450 with respect to the electrodes and using an analyzer placed surface electrode device. For this comparison, we used Imm CrAu electrodes spaced 500 pm apart and a gedthetransmitte intesityfromhecen averaged C the transmitted intensity from the center 100 jutm of the gap. As can be seen in Figure 3, we get an excellent match of device behavior, including the 'flat' response at low voltage, the reduction of maximum intensity due to scattering and the decrease in contrast due to an unpolarized bias component. Figure 3. Comparison of measured performance of fabricated surface electrode PLZT device (dots) and computer simulation using new modeling method (line). Device has 2mm wide CrAu electrodes separated by a 500 m gap and evaporated onto a 380 vm thick wafer.</p>
<p>Conclusion By using four polarizer/analyzer orientations and takig measurements of optical response versus applied voltage we generate sufficient information to calculate the relative change in index of refraction for PLZT. From these measurements we extract information on the scattering, depolarization and change in relative phase. By incorporating that same information into simulating device behavior we then accurately model arbitrary geometries for polarization rotation devices. We are currently using this technique to optimize device design for a variety of performance characteristics including maximum contrast, efficiency and minimized cross talk. This empirically-based modeling of electrooptic devices is essential for developing accurate and reliable CAD tools necessary for design of future optoelectronic systems</p>
<p>Acknowledgments  We wish to thank Eddie Rezler of Marc Analysis for his assistance with computer simulations. This research is funded in part by AFOSR, NSF and Rome Lab.</p></body>
<back>
<ref-list>
<ref id="r1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Haertling</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Land</surname><given-names>C.E.</given-names></name></person-group> &#x02018;<article-title>Hot-Pressed (Pb, La)(Zr, Ti)O<sub>3</sub> Ferroelectric Ceramics for Electrooptic Applications</article-title>&#x02019;, <source>J Am Ceram Soc</source>, <volume>54</volume>(<issue>1</issue>) <fpage>1</fpage>-<lpage>10</lpage>, (<year>1971</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1151-2916.1970.tb12105.x-i1</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="thesis"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Mansoorian</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>Design and Characterization of Flip-Chip Bonded Si/PLZT Smart Pixels</article-title> (<source>PhD Thesis</source>), Ch 2, <publisher-name>University of California</publisher-name>, <publisher-loc>San Diego</publisher-loc>, (<year>1994</year>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ivey</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x02018;<article-title>Birefringent Light Scattering in PLZT Ceramics</article-title>&#x02019;, <source>IEEE Transactions on Ultrasonics, Ferroelectrics, and Frequency Control</source>, <volume>38</volume>(<issue>6</issue>) <fpage>579</fpage>-<lpage>84</lpage> <publisher-name>IEEE</publisher-name>, <publisher-loc>New York</publisher-loc>, <year>1991</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1109/58.108855</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Title</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x02018;<article-title>Modeling and characterization of embedded electrode performance in transverse electrooptic modulators</article-title>&#x02019;, <source>Appl Opt</source> <volume>29</volume>(<issue>1</issue>) <fpage>85</fpage>-<lpage>98</lpage> <month>January</month> (<year>1990</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/AO.29.000085</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Haertling</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name></person-group> &#x02018;<article-title>Electro-optic ceramics and devices</article-title>&#x02019;, <source>Electronic Ceramics</source>, Ed. <person-group person-group-type="editor"><name><surname>Levinson</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name></person-group>, <fpage>371</fpage>-<lpage>492</lpage> <publisher-name>Cot&#x000E9; and Bouchard</publisher-name>, <year>1988</year></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></book-part></book-part-wrapper>
