<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
<collection-meta collection-type="conf">
<conference content-type="conf-name"><conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name><conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym></conference>
<conference content-type="conf-other-meta"><conf-date content-type="start">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-date content-type="end">
<day>19</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-loc>Nevada, 
<country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc></conference></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
<title-group>
<title>SLM Materials and Sructures</title>
<alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/></title-group></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
<title-group>
<title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title></title-group>
<volume-in-collection>
<volume-number>14</volume-number>
<volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title></volume-in-collection></collection-meta>
<book-meta>
<book-title-group>
<book-title>Spatial Light Modulators</book-title></book-title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Burdge</surname><given-names>Geoffrey</given-names></name></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>Sadik C.</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group>
<pub-date publication-format="electronic">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></pub-date></book-meta>
<book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
<book-part-meta>
<title-group>
<title>Novel Static RAM Pixel Circuits for Liquid Crystal over Silicon Spatial Light Modulators</title></title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Breslin</surname><given-names>John A.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref><xref rid="cor1" ref-type="corresp"><sup>*</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Underwood</surname><given-names>Ian</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<aff id="aff1">
<label>1</label>Department of Electrical Engineering, The University of Edinburgh, Mayfield Road, Edinburgh, EH9 3JL, 
<country country="GB">SCOTLAND</country></aff></contrib-group>
<author-notes>
<corresp id="cor1">
<label>*</label>+44 (0)131 650 5565, <email>John.Breslin@ee.ed.ac.uk</email> (March 27th, 1997)</corresp></author-notes>
<elocation-id>160</elocation-id>
<permissions>
<copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
<copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
<copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
<license license-type="open-access">
<license-p>closed</license-p></license></permissions>
<abstract>
<p>In this paper, we present two novel Static RAM pixel designs for use in Liquid-Crystal-over-Silicon Spatial Light Modulators. Compared with existing designs, these new pixels have advantages in terms of circuit simplicity, circuit size, circuit connectivity, and power consumption. We discuss what considerations are required in the design of these pixels, why such considerations are important, and outline two schemes to drive the devices.</p></abstract>
<kwd-group kwd-group-type="OCIS">
<title>OCIS codes</title>
<kwd>liquid crystal devices</kwd>
<kwd>spatial light modulators</kwd></kwd-group>
<counts>
<book-page-count count="5"/></counts></book-part-meta>
<body>
<p>Introduction Spatial Light Modulators (SLMs), consist of an array of pixels which, in binary devices, can be on or off (see Fig. 1). Liquid Crystal (LC) devices use an LC material to modulate the amplitude and/or the phase of an incident light ray. There are several types of LC materials such as nematics and ferroelectrics &#x0005B;2&#x0005D;. For the purposes of this publication, ferroelectric liquid crystal will be discussed. The devices are constructed by gluing the edges of a cover glass over a silicon die, on which an array of pixels is present. The inside of the cover glass is coated with a transparent electrode, and a gap is left between the electrode/glass and the surface of the die. This gap is filled with LC material. One method of effecting amplitude modulation is as follows: Polarised light is presented to the pixel array. A voltage applied across the liquid crystal rotates the polarization of the light as it passes through the material. The "altered" light can be viewed through Polarizer B, the unaltered light cannot, and so the pixel appears dark (see Fig. 2). LIGHT RAY Figure 1. Spatial Light Modulator Pixel Array. These devices have applications in displays, holo- graphy and optical computing systems &#x0005B;1&#x0005D;. Figure 2. Amplitude Modulation using a LC SLM. A requirement of liquid crystal materials is that they must be charge-balanced. This means that a voltage of +V volts, applied for I seconds, must be followed by a voltage of -V volts, for t seconds. That is, the net d.c. (i.e. time averaged), voltage across the material must be zero &#x0005B;3&#x0005D;, otherwise the liquid crystal breaks down by electrochemical decomposition. Each pixel in the array can be on or off, and thus has to store a logic 1' or 'O' (for binary devices). . .This storage can be implemented using SRAM or DRAM cells.</p>
<p>DRAM and SRAM Pixels DRAM cells are small and simple. However, they must be refreshed, suffer from photo-induced charge leakage, and may supply only a limited amount of charge to the mirror. To charge balance these devices may require a complex addressing scheme. This involves loading an image and then its inverse, possibly interspersed with blanking frames to turn the whole array on or off &#x0005B;4&#x0005D;. This lowers the frame rate of the device and means that the array has to be viewed under a pulsed light source. SRAM1 cells are larger than DRAM. They require no refresh, are more robust, and provide better driv ing voltages for the pixel with an unlimited supply of charge (i.e. Vdd and Vss), via the SRAM cell - unlike the DRAM pixel which has a limited amount of charge stored in the DRAM capacitor. Also, SRAM cells can be viewed under a continuous light source. This is because specialised charge balancing circuitry can be incorporated directly onto the SRAM cell, and a complex addressing and driving scheme is not required (i.e. no inverse frame(s) require to be loaded). This in turn means that the device can have a higher frame rate.</p>
<p>Current SRAM Technology  Current charge-balancing SRAM pixels normally consist of a 10 transistor cell: Two pass transistors to allow data loading; two cross-coupled inverters to implement storage; and an XOR (or XNOR), gate to implement the charge balancing circuitry &#x0005B;5, p.64&#x0005D; &#x0005B;6&#x0005D; (see Fig. 3). However, the internal XOR connectivity can be complex and the XOR circuitry may be large. This is be- cause the transistors are lengthened in order to reduce current spikes when switching. The mirror is either driven by the CLOCK line through the transmission gate, or by a buffered (inverted) CLOCK. This means that the drive scheme is unequal as CLOCK is a global busline. Charge balancing is effected by XORing Charge the CLOCK signal - which is common to all pixels- with the. stratavalue(LATs c H)monto. ThiCl signal ition. if the stored data value (LATCH). This CLOCK signal is also present on the global Indium Tin Oxide (ITO), elec- trode. If the pixel is storing a '1', the mirror experiences a +VDD, -VDD, transition over one clock period. This will turn the pixel ON, and then implement the charge balance (the mirror having a 50&#x00025; duty cycle). If the p oth pixel is storing a '', the XOR output is in phase with CLOCK, so the mirror will have a zero -voltagre drop and remain off. In each case, the net d.c. voltage across the mirror is zero (see Fig. 4) &#x0005B;5, pp.66-69&#x0005D;. Since the CLOCK line iscommon to all pixels. the charge bal ance occurs simultaneously across the whole array. CLOCK Figure 3. Conventional XOR SRAM Pixcl. Th.~aeseeyeurdomlmnaO transition if the pixel is to be ON, and a HI-LO trans- is to be OFF (or vice versa). Our new .iel us sipe ehiust oti. pixelsusesimplertechniquestodothis NewDevices Thenewdevicesmakeuseoftransmissiongatesorpass transistors to switch the output of the SRAM cell LO- HI orHI-LO(orviceversa),asrequired. Twodevices 10 Transistor SRAM Pixel CLOCK Figure 5. 10 Transistor SRAM Pixel. This pixel contains 10 transistors. It consists of: * A 6 transistor SRAM cell. * 2 transmission gates switched by CLOCK and CLOCKBAR to toggle the SRAM outputs. * When CLOCK is HI, OUTPUT is LATCH- BAR. * When CLOCK is LO, OUTPUT is LATCH. Advantages The transmission gate transistors can be minimum sized and the connectivity of the pixel is sim- fer pier - this leads to a saving in pixel area. Also, the mirror is driven directlv by the SRA a outputs (via the of transmissiongates),sothedriveschemeisbalanced. mrnsissionigates),isoethet t chemeisated 8 Transistor Pixel CLOCK Figure 6. 8 Transistor SRAM Pixel. This pixel contains 8 transistors. It consists of: * A 6 transistor SRAM cell. * 2 pass transistors switched by CLOCK*. * When CLOCK* is HI, OUTPUT is LATCH- BAR. * When CLOCK* is LO, OUTPUT is LATCH. * The CLOCK* signal is switched between (Vss - Vh) and (VDD +Vth) to ensure good logic levels at OUTPUT (this will be discussed later). CLOCK switches between Vss and VDD as nor- mal. Advantages This pixel exhibits similar advantages to the 10 transistor design. In addition, it uses only 8 transistors, has an even simpler connectivity, and one less busline. Comparisons Cmagg A comparison of pixel attributes, taken from the AMS 1.2pi, CCMOS process, run at 5V, can be seen in Table Table 1. Pixel Attributes. 1. This pixel was used in a 256x256 SRAM LC-SL.M designed at the University of Edinburgh. 2. This pixel is a redesign of the above. 3. Using an overdriven CLOCK* . With savings in pixel area and the continuing re duction in process geometries (IMEC &#x0005B;Belgium&#x0005D; offer 0.5pm CMOS and will soon offer 0.3pm &#x0005B;7&#x0005D;: IBM of- CMOS &#x0005B;8&#x0005D;), it is now feasible to produce Ultra-scale SRAM SLM devices, i.e. having resolutions to 2000x2000 pixels and above. The new pixel designs can be further modified to reduce the number of transistors and buslines and/or change the transistor type(s) and configurations &#x0005B;9&#x0005D;. Design Considerations Care must be taken in the design of the new pixel cir- cults shown in Figs. 5 and 6. Several important features must he considered. Charge Sharing and Current Spikes If, as in this case, one-phase, complementary clock sig nals are being used, there will be a point when the clock signal switches where both LATCH and LATCH-BAR are short-circuited. It is important to ensure that current spikes are acceptable under these conditions. PixelMirrorCapacitance If the mirror capacitance is very large, and the capacitance at nodes A and B is small, then when the SRAM cell tries to drive the mirror to a different state, charge could leak back from the mirror into the SRAM cell. This would cause the SRAM cell to change state. That is, the mirror would drive the SRAM cell, rather than the SRAM cell driving the mirror. Care must be taken to ensure that the capacitance values associated with these nodes are ratioed properly, and that the inverters have sufficient drive capability. Simulations show that with a 30x30pm mirror, the capacitance of the mirror node would have to be over an order of magnitude above typical calculated values in or- der to effect this. That is, the mirror capacitance would have to be at least 1970fF, when the typical value is ac- tually 134.1fF (with a node A capacitance of 13.29fF). Driving Schemes The 8 transistor cell drives the mirror through a pm0os or nmos transistor. In isolation, these devices are not ideal switches. A pmos transistor is able to switch a III logic signal, but will attenuate a LO logic signal; when the gate voltage is LO. A nmos transistor will switch a LO signal, and attenuate a III; when the gate voltage is III &#x0005B;10, p.56&#x0005D;. The attenuation, for annmos transistor, is as follows (see Fig. 7). T.e t I , is not constant. It varies The threshold voltage ~creased with the body effect &#x0005B;10, p.41&#x0005D;: 1 h klto) +&#x0005B; 1 + 2 0F- _ (2) Where, V.b is the substrate voltage, 6F is a constant, 1(() is the threshold voltage when .b= 0, and - is a constant that describes the substrate bias effect. Therefore in order to allow good switching of logic levels in the 8 transistor pixel, the pass transistors must be driven by a CLOCK* signal that switches between at least (Vs- th), and (DD +th)-</p>
<p>Implementation Circuitry based on the above designs has been included contains: .testchip(Xavierl, * an 8x7 array of 10 transistor SRAM cells. * a 2x2 array of 8 transistor SRAM cells with drive scheme 1 (detailed below). * a 2x2 array of 8 transistor SRAM cells with drive scheme 2 (detailed below). The chip is being fabricated through MOSIS on the Orbit 2pm, 5V, analogue, CMOS, n-well process. Simulations show, that to drive the 8 transistor devices properly reqires voltages of -3V and +7V. The latter can be generated using on-chip circuitry by shielding a n-well and strapping it to +7 volts. As it is not possible in an n-well process to create individual p-wells, a similar technique cannot be used to generate the required -3 volts. Drive Scheme 1 The first approach is to drive the transistors directly with -31 and +7V. The CLOCK signal does not, pass through any transistor circuitry on the chip. However, this means that the standard pads with Electrostatic Discharge (ESD), Protection circuitry cannot be used. Therefore there is a danger of damaging the circuitry when handling the chip. The actual voltage that could be generated at the transistor gate is given in Eq.3 &#x0005B;10, p.227&#x0005D;: JI The Voltage produced cai be extreily high relative to the small current that may flow onto the chip from external sources if handled incorrectly. For example, if I=10pA, and C,=0.03pF, and A1=1ps: then V-330 volts. In order to reduce this voltage, the capacitance of athe node is increased, and the line resistance is also in- craetrdcteoetacretsei.8) to reduce the potential current (see Fig. 8). .0 This approach limits the operational speed of the pixels, but will allow some testing and characterisation to be carried out. UNBUFFERED INPUT LargePolyReItmr LrgePolyReitor -/------ smLiUgatecapacifanco LargeMI verPoly Capacitor Figure 8. Simple ESD Protectioi Circuitry. Drive Scheme2 The second approach is to build a buffer on the chip itself. The buffer takes a 0 51' input, and has a +71', -31' output. This means that the CLOCK signal can be buffered via a standard input, pad that contains ESD protection circuitry. However, the buffer requires a+71' n-well and a -31 p-well in order to operate (see Fig. It is not possible to fabricate a p-well directly with the available process. However, one cal be synthesized by creating an n-well ring around a small area of the p-substrate. This small area is tied to the required -3 voltsandheavilyshielded(seeFig. 10). Figure 9. BufferSchematic. suhstrateresistance Figure 10. Synthesized p-well Inverter. The guard ring shielding and the n-well ring (around the -3 volt area), with another Ground guard ring, should help to limit the substrate current. Note that these drive schemes would not be required in a twin-well process. They are only required for single- well wafers.</p>
<p>Conclusions It is desirable to use SRAM pixels in binary Liquid-Crystal-over-Silicon Spatial Light Modulators. On-pixel charge balancing circuitry allows devices to have a high frame rate. We have presented two novel SRAM pixel circuits for use in LC SLMs. These devices exhibit several advantages over current designs. Any saving in pixel area and current/power requirements can have a significant effect on the device resolution/size/performance/yield trade-off, especially in the design of very high resolution SLMs.</p>
<p>Acknowledgements This work is being jointly funded by the Engineering and Physical Sciences Research Council (EPSRC); and Thorn CRL, Hayes, Middlesex, England. I would like to thank Torsten Lehmann for his views and suggestions relating to this work.</p></body>
<back>
<ref-list>
<ref id="r1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="editor"><name><surname>Efron</surname><given-names>Uzi</given-names></name></person-group> (Editor), <source>Spatial Light Modulator Technology, Materials, Devices, Applications</source>, <publisher-name>Marcel Dekker Inc</publisher-name>, (<year>1996</year>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="editor"><name><surname>Karim</surname><given-names>Mohammad A.</given-names></name></person-group> (Editor), <source>Electro-optical Displays</source>, <publisher-name>Marcel Dekker Inc</publisher-name>, (<year>1992</year>)</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Drabik</surname><given-names>Timothy J.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>, <article-title>2D silicon/ferrolectric liquid crystal spatial light modulators</article-title>. <source>IEEE Micro</source> <volume>15</volume>(<issue>4</issue>) <fpage>70</fpage> <month>August</month> <year>1995</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1109/40.400643</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Underwood</surname><given-names>Ian</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>, <article-title>A high performance spatial light modulator</article-title>. <source>Proceedings of the SPIE</source>, <volume>1562</volume>, <fpage>107</fpage>-<lpage>115</lpage>, (<year>1991</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1117/12.50776</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="thesis"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Burns</surname><given-names>Dwayne C.</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>Design and Characterisation of a Ferroelectric Liquid Crystal over Silicon Spatial Light Modulator</article-title>. <source>PhD thesis</source>, <publisher-name>The University of Edinburgh</publisher-name>, <year>1994</year></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Burns</surname><given-names>Dwayne C.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>, <article-title>A 256 &#x000D7; 256 sram-xor pixel ferroelectric liquid crystal over silicon spatial light modulator</article-title>. <source>Optics Comms</source>, <volume>119</volume>, <fpage>623</fpage>-<lpage>632</lpage>, (<year>1995</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/0030-4018(95)00414-4</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r7"><label>7</label><mixed-citation publication-type="web"><person-group person-group-type="author"><collab>CAST</collab></person-group> <source>IMEC custom application specific technologies</source> <year>1997</year>, <ext-link xlink:href="http://www.imec.be/aspinfo/cast/CASTall.html" ext-link-type="uri">http://www.imec.be/aspinfo/cast/CASTall.html</ext-link>.</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r8"><label>8</label><mixed-citation publication-type="web"><person-group person-group-type="author"><collab>IBM Corporation</collab></person-group> <article-title>IBM introduces industry&#x02019;s first</article-title>. <source>18 micron asic product</source>, <month>May</month> <year>1996</year> <ext-link xlink:href="http://fnctsrv0.chips.ibm.com/news/sal2.annc.html" ext-link-type="uri">http://fnctsrv0.chips.ibm.com/news/sal2.annc.html</ext-link>.</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r9"><label>9</label><mixed-citation publication-type="patent"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Breslin</surname><given-names>John A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Underwood</surname><given-names>Ian</given-names></name></person-group>, <article-title>Novel Circuit Designs for Liquid Crystal over Silicon Spatial Light Modulator Pixels</article-title>. <year>1996</year>. <source>UK Patent Ref</source>. <patent>9602766</patent> <fpage>9</fpage></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r10"><label>10</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Weste</surname><given-names>Neil</given-names></name><name><surname>Eshraghian</surname><given-names>Kamran</given-names></name></person-group>, <source>Principles of CMOS VLSI Design</source>, <publisher-name>Addison-Wesley</publisher-name>, (<year>1985</year>)</mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></book-part></book-part-wrapper>
