<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0"
    xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
    <collection-meta collection-type="conf">
        <conference content-type="conf-name">
            <conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name>
            <conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym>
        </conference>
        <conference content-type="conf-other-meta">
            <conf-date content-type="start">
                <day>17</day>
                <month>03</month>
                <year>1997</year>
            </conf-date>
            <conf-date content-type="end">
                <day>19</day>
                <month>03</month>
                <year>1997</year>
            </conf-date>
            <conf-loc>Nevada, <country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc>
        </conference>
    </collection-meta>
    <collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
        <title-group>
            <title>SLM Materials and Sructures</title>
            <alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/>
        </title-group>
    </collection-meta>
    <collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
        <title-group>
            <title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title>
        </title-group>
        <volume-in-collection>
            <volume-number>14</volume-number>
            <volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title>
        </volume-in-collection>
    </collection-meta>
    <book-meta>
        <book-title-group>
            <book-title>Spatial Light Modulators</book-title>
        </book-title-group>
        <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="editor">
                <name>
                    <surname>Burdge</surname>
                    <given-names>Geoffrey</given-names>
                </name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="editor">
                <name>
                    <surname>Esener</surname>
                    <given-names>Sadik C.</given-names>
                </name>
            </contrib>
        </contrib-group>
        <pub-date publication-format="electronic">
            <day>17</day>
            <month>03</month>
            <year>1997</year>
        </pub-date>
    </book-meta>
    <book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
        <book-part-meta>
            <title-group>
                <title>The Fast Bit Plane SLM: A New Ferro-Electric Liquid crystal on Silicon
                    Spatial Light Modulator Designed for High Yield and Low Cost
                    Manufacturability</title>
            </title-group>
            <contrib-group>
                <contrib contrib-type="author">
                    <name>
                        <surname>Crossland</surname>
                        <given-names>W.A.</given-names>
                    </name>
                    <xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">
                        <sup>1</sup>
                    </xref>
                </contrib>
                <contrib contrib-type="author">
                    <name>
                        <surname>Wilkinson</surname>
                        <given-names>T.D.</given-names>
                    </name>
                    <xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">
                        <sup>1</sup>
                    </xref>
                </contrib>
                <contrib contrib-type="author">
                    <name>
                        <surname>Coker</surname>
                        <given-names>T.M.</given-names>
                    </name>
                    <xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">
                        <sup>1</sup>
                    </xref>
                </contrib>
                <contrib contrib-type="author">
                    <name>
                        <surname>Yu</surname>
                        <given-names>TCBY</given-names>
                    </name>
                    <xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff">
                        <sup>2</sup>
                    </xref>
                </contrib>
                <contrib contrib-type="author">
                    <name>
                        <surname>Stanley</surname>
                        <given-names>M.</given-names>
                    </name>
                    <xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff">
                        <sup>3</sup>
                    </xref>
                </contrib>
                <aff id="aff1">
                    <label>1</label>Cambridge University Engineering Department, Trumpington Street,
                    CAMBRIDGE, CB2 IPZ</aff>
                <aff id="aff2">
                    <label>2</label>Department of Cybernetics, Reading University, White Knights,
                    READING, Surrey</aff>
                <aff id="aff3">
                    <label>3</label>DRA Malvern, St Andrews Road, MALVERN, Worcs</aff>
            </contrib-group>
            <elocation-id>102</elocation-id>
            <permissions>
                <copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
                <copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
                <copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
                <license license-type="open-access">
                    <license-p>closed</license-p>
                </license>
            </permissions>
            <abstract>
                <p>We announce a new VLSI silicon backplane Spatial Light Modulator known as the DRA
                    Fast Bit Plane SLM. The size of the pixel array is 320x240 with a fill factor of
                    65&#x00025;; the pixel type is single transistor DRAM. With DRA2 liquid crystal
                    &#x0005B;2&#x0005D; the maximum possible frame rate is 22.7kHz. Initial devices
                    have been set up for binary phase modulation using a crystal with a cone angle
                    wider than is optimal for intensity modulation. Even so a contrast ratio of
                    12:1, averaged over a small array of pixels, has been measured and results from
                    imaging applications are presented. An image has been projected from the
                    un-planarised device and displayed images are plainly visible under ambient
                    illumination; full colour images are possible in a helmet-mounted configuration.
                    In its planarised form the device is considered to be a low cost alternative to
                    the TI DMD for many applications.</p>
            </abstract>
            <kwd-group kwd-group-type="OCIS">
                <title>OCIS codes</title>
                <kwd>Optical Devices - Theory and Technology - Spatial light modulators</kwd>
                <kwd>liquid crystal devices</kwd>
                <kwd>silicon backplane devices</kwd>
            </kwd-group>
            <counts>
                <book-page-count count="5"/>
            </counts>
        </book-part-meta>
        <body>
            <p>GENERAL DESCRIPTION The Fast Bit Plane SLM is a VLSI silicon backplane EASLM of a
                generic type first reported by Collings et al &#x0005B;31. The pixels are of the
                sinle transistor DRAM type laid out in a 320x240 array. The data bus is 64 bits wide
                with 5:1 de-multiplexing whilst the rows are controlled by a token and shift
                register scheme rather than by line address decoding. The pixel pitch is 34 microns
                and the overall die size is 4x14mnm. The device has been manufactured by a
                commercial VLSI process from Austria Mikro Systeme International (AMS). This device
                is similar in some aspects to the devices reported by Handschy et al
                &#x0005B;4&#x0005D;.</p>
            <p>DESIGN CRITERIA The principle design criteria were threefold: * High yield and ease
                of manufacture. * High fill factor and mirror flatness. * Maximum possible
                addressing speed. The second criterion arose from the requirement that the device
                should be usable even if un-planarised. This lead almost directly to the use of a
                DRAM rather than SRAM type pixel but also meant that there could be no circuitry
                underneath the pixel mirror. At an early point in the design sequence it was also
                decided that a high voltage 2 micron VLSI process would be used in order to switch
                the Liquid Crystal as quickly as possible. As a consequence of these two factors the
                best fill factor that could be achieved was 65&#x00025; - note the Handschy devices
                achieve a much higher fill factor but this is done by placing the mirror over
                underlying circuitry. The pixel layout is shown in Fig 1. Given that a 2 micron
                process was used, this would perhaps limit the speed of the device somewhat. Even so
                the device is rated at 50MHz, with a 100ns line address time. Coupled with the DRA2
                liquid crystal mixture the maximum possible frame rate is 22.7kHz, although this is
                dependent on the liquid crystal drive scheme. Assembly and Yield. Previous problems
                encountered in the high yield fabrication of these devices, particularly that of
                'front to back' shorts, have been tackled and new, yield enhancing methods for
                device assembly and glue lane deposition have been employed. Liquid Crystal Drive
                Schemes. In addition to the criteria mentioned above, the device has also been
                designed with a novel Liquid Crystal drive scheme in mind. In the past inverse frame
                is written to the SLM for every image frame and the illumination is modulated
                appropriately &#x0005B;5&#x0005D;. The scheme the device was designed for is
                inherently DC balanced and in practice this has meant that extra functionality has
                been included in the electrical addressing scheme of the SLM. The significance of
                this scheme is that the SLM is now continuously viewable, unlike the previous 2
                schemes. Previously only SRAM type SLMs have had this feature and they have relied
                on a much more complex pixel circuit and addressing scheme, often accompanied with a
                reduction in light throughput &#x0005B;6&#x0005D;.</p>
            <p>TESTFEATURES In order to accurately assess devices and to monitor them in actual
                operation a number of test features have been included in the design. At the end of
                each row and column line there are 2 MOSFETs (an n channel and ap channel). These
                are connected together such that, in combination with an external pull-up or
                pull-down resistor, they form both a wired NOR and a wired NAND gate monitoring the
                row and column lines. Using this feature, the switching of both row and column lines
                can be verified. The most useful test feature is the pixel followers Figure 2 - Test
                outputs. SLMs of this type (ie DRAM) have been driven by holding the potential of
                the front electrode at a point half way between ground and the maximum potential
                that the pixel can reach, in this way opposite polarity fields can be applied to the
                appropriate pixels. In order to maintain DC balance the data is either periodically
                reversed &#x0005B;41 or an that have been connected to one pixel from each of the 2
                bottom rows of the array. Using the outputs from these, the switching of the 2
                pixels can be directly observed; this enables such experiments as observing the
                dipole switching current of the FELC and the effects of high intensity illumination
                on pixels (before, during and after they switch) to be carried out. Other features
                include the token buffers at the bottom of each shift register which verify that the
                complete shift register is operating and a temperature sensor that, in addition to a
                peltier heater, could be used to accurately control the temperature of the device. A
                sample of the outputs from these test feature is shown in Figure 2; in this figure
                the top trace is the output from a token buffer, the next the pixel follower
                (incidentally this indicates a pixel droop under lab light illumination of around
                10ins), trace 4 is one of the clocks and trace 3 is the output from the wired NOR
                gate connected to one set of row lines, indicating the switching of the rows.</p>
            <p>ASSEMBLY AND YIELD RESULTS Unsurprisingly there are many steps in the total assembly
                procedure but the 2 principal ones are the coming together of the silicon and glass
                and wire bonding and packaging. The former process has been carried out in the Class
                100 clean room facility at Cambridge University Engineering Department (Photonics
                and Sensors Group) using a semi- automated system that enables 4 devices to be
                assembled at once. The packaging and wire bonding has been carried out at DRA
                Malvern. Table I shows the overall yield and its constituent values. Note that,
                normally, dice would be probed once, whilst they were on the wafer, and for a second
                time after the front glass was glued in place. For simplicity and to increase
                overall yield (as the second probing will itself lead to some devices failing) the
                first probing is omitted. Consequently the figure for manufacture and assembly
                includes both the yield on the wafer and the yield of the assembly process. A
                separate wafer was probe tested initially, the yield on this was 88.5&#x00025;
                although this is a little misleading as, of a necessity, this test is unable to
                reveal all faults that may exist on a device. Table I - Manufacturing Yield</p>
            <p>LIQUID CRYSTALS The devices assembled so far have been filled with a high tilt angle
                material known as MPP3 &#x0005B;2&#x0005D;. In this case it has been aligned by a
                conventional rubbed nylon layer; both the cover glass and the silicon have been
                rubbed - unlike the Handschy devices &#x0005B;2&#x0005D; - although the silicon was
                rubbed more gently! Previously it was thought that rubbing the silicon in this way
                would damage the circuitry, mainly the pixel transistor gates. However this does not
                seem to be the case and the devices prepared in this way align extremely well. In
                theory the liquid crystal can align into I of 2 domains, the difference being the
                inclination of the smectic layers to the rubbing direction. In practice only single
                domain structures have been observed both in these devices and simple glass test
                cells.</p>
            <p>APPLICATIONS RESULTS With MPP3 the maximum observed contrast ratio, averaged over 100
                or so pixels, is 12:1; the switching speed is of the order of 100us. However one
                must remember that MPP3 has a high tilt angle (60 degrees) which is greater than
                that required for maximum contrast in a display application; the high tilt angle
                also explains to a certain extent the relatively slow switching speed of this
                material. A full interface/framestore is nearing completion but was not available to
                drive the chip for the system described below, consequently the images shown are
                very simple. The full interface has the capability to drive the chip at its rated
                speed of 50MHz - a burst data rate of 3.2 Gbit/s - and can store sufficient image
                data for at least a 4 second full motion video clip &#x0005B;7&#x0005D;. Figure 3
                shows an image written to the SLM and viewed under ambient illumination through a
                single polariser. Figure 4 shows the same image written to the SLM but projected
                onto a normal slide projector screen. The projected image is plainly visible in this
                way (albeit in a dimly lit room) although the actual image size is limited to about
                40x30 cm (representing an image magnification of about 35 times). A very simple off
                axis reflection scheme - see Figure 5 - was used to project this image. The optical
                power incident onto the SLM for this experiment was around 10mW/cm 2 . This is
                comparable to the figure quoted by Handschy for their Generation I devices. The
                Generation II devices would appear to be highly resistant to incident radiation,
                however one would expect this given design (specifically that mirrors are placed
                over circuitry which acts to protect the circuitry from incident radiation as well
                as to increase fill factor). A detailed model of how the Fast Bit Plane SLM responds
                to the incident optical power will be the subject of a later paper. Given that the
                device is currently unplanarised the performance of the projection display is very
                good. Figure 3 -Image viewed under ambient illumination through a single polariser.
                Figure 4 -Projected image. Furthermore the planarised device is expected to be as
                resistant to high intensity illumination as the Generation II Handschy devices. With
                this in mind this device must be considered as a viable alternative to the Texas
                Instruments DMD, but at a fraction of what is assumed to be the cost of ni, Figure 5
                - Off axis projection system these devices. A simple variant of the projection
                display is the helmet-mounted type, replacing the high intensity white light with
                simple LEDs and viewing the image througha beam splitter. This configuration also
                lends itself to a full colour imaging system 18&#x0005D;. The images shown here are
                simple black and white ones, however grey scale is easily achievable, even under
                fairly intense illumination, by using a temporal averaging or bit plane scheme. This
                has been demonstrated with simple images in the laboratory, both in projection and
                viewed directly.</p>
            <p>CONCLUSION The DRA Fast Bit Plane SLM is a silicon VLSI backplane electrically
                addressed SLM. It has been designed for speed, flexibility, high yield and ease of
                manufacture. Initial work hasshownthatdevicescanbemadeinquantity,although the
                overall yield is moderate at the moment. The first devices have been set up for
                binary phase modulation but even so good intensity contrast has been achieved. With
                a simple interface and optics a projection display has been constructed, whilst
                images, both grey scale and black and white. are directly viewable under ambient
                illumination. The resistance of the device to high intensity illumination in its
                unplanarised state is very good and consequently it is considered that the
                planarised device will be a viable, but much lower cost, alternative to the Texas
                Instruments DMD device. Further work will include trials of the device as a phase
                hologram source, and the extension of the imaging application to full colour full
                motion video.</p>
            <p>ACKNOWLEDGEMENTS This SLM was developed for DERA Malvern under contract MAL 1b/2256.
                Our thanks are due to Drs Meirion Lewis and Brian Lowans of DERA Malvern, Mick Stone
                of the Engineering Department, Dr Martin Birch of CRL and Dr Ian Underwood of
                Edinburgh University. TM Coker is an EPSRC student and also has a CASE award from
                DERA Malvern.</p>
        </body>
        <back>
            <ref-list>
                <ref id="r1">
                    <label>1</label>
                    <mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>TCBY Yu designed and
                            laid out the device whilst at Cambridge under a Croucher Foundation
                            Research Fellowship</article-title>.</mixed-citation>
                </ref>
                <ref id="r2">
                    <label>2</label>
                    <mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>The DRA2 mixture was
                            supplied by DRA Malvern and the MPP3 material by the University of Hull
                            under the LINK DTI programme 'Fast Optical and Electro-Optical Effects
                            in Chiral Liquid Crystals'</article-title>.</mixed-citation>
                </ref>
                <ref id="r3">
                    <label>3</label>
                    <mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group
                            person-group-type="author"
                                    ><name><surname>Collings</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name><name><surname>Crossland</surname><given-names>W.A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ayliffe</surname><given-names>P.J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Vass</surname><given-names>D.G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Underwood</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></name></person-group>,
                            "<article-title>Evolutionary development of advanced liquid crystal
                            spatial light modulators</article-title>", <source>Applied
                            Optics</source>
                        <volume>28</volume>(<issue>22</issue> (<day>15</day>
                        <month>Nov</month>
                        <year>1989</year>).<pub-id pub-id-type="doi"
                        >10.1364/AO.28.004740</pub-id></mixed-citation>
                </ref>
                <ref id="r4">
                    <label>4</label>
                    <mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group
                            person-group-type="author"
                                    ><name><surname>Handschy</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chase</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Cotter</surname><given-names>L.K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Cunninham</surname><given-names>J.D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Pattee</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Drabik</surname><given-names>T.J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Gaalema</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></name></person-group>,
                            "<article-title>One transistor DRAM ferro-electric liquid crystal
                            spatial light modulator</article-title>," <source>Proceedings of SPIE
                            237 - Optical Pattern Recognition V</source>, (<year>1994</year>)<pub-id
                            pub-id-type="doi">10.1117/12.169449</pub-id></mixed-citation>
                </ref>
                <ref id="r5">
                    <label>5</label>
                    <mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group
                            person-group-type="author"
                                    ><name><surname>Radcliffe</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Griffith</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Laycock</surname><given-names>L.C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Worboys</surname><given-names>M.R.</given-names></name></person-group>,
                            "<article-title>Miniature silicon backplane ferro-electric liquid
                            crystal displays for head mounted display applications</article-title>."
                            <source>Ferroelectrics</source>
                        <volume>179</volume>(<issue>2</issue>), (<year>1996</year>)<pub-id
                            pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/00150199608007878</pub-id></mixed-citation>
                </ref>
                <ref id="r6">
                    <label>6</label>
                    <mixed-citation publication-type="thesis"><person-group
                            person-group-type="author"
                                    ><name><surname>Burns</surname><given-names>D.C.</given-names></name></person-group>
                            "<article-title>Design and characterisation of a ferroelectric liquid
                            crystal over silicon spatial light modulator</article-title>,"
                            <publisher-name>University of Edinburgh</publisher-name>
                        <source>PhD thesis</source>
                        <year>1994</year></mixed-citation>
                </ref>
                <ref id="r7">
                    <label>7</label>
                    <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
                        <article-title>The frainestore is being designed and constructed by
                            Cambridge University, Computer Laboratory</article-title>
                    </mixed-citation>
                </ref>
                <ref id="r8">
                    <label>8</label>
                    <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">See, for example &#x0005B;5&#x0005D;
                        or <person-group person-group-type="author"
                                    ><name><surname>Rankin</surname><given-names>I.D.</given-names></name><name><surname>O&#x02019;Hara</surname><given-names>I
                                    Underwood.
                                    A</given-names></name><name><surname>Vass</surname><given-names>D.G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Worboys</surname><given-names>M.R.</given-names></name></person-group>,
                            "<article-title>Full colour images on a binary spatial light
                            modulator</article-title>." <source>Ferroelectrics</source>
                        <volume>179</volume>(<issue>2</issue>), (<year>1996</year>)</mixed-citation>
                </ref>
            </ref-list>
        </back>
    </book-part>
</book-part-wrapper>
