<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book-part-wrapper PUBLIC "-//OSA//DTD OSA BITS Conference DTD v1.0 20170715//EN" "OSA-BITS-conference.dtd">
<book-part-wrapper content-type="conf-paper-wrap" dtd-version="2.0" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
<collection-meta collection-type="conf">
<conference content-type="conf-name"><conf-name>Spatial Light Modulators</conf-name><conf-acronym>SLMO</conf-acronym></conference>
<conference content-type="conf-other-meta"><conf-date content-type="start">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-date content-type="end">
<day>19</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></conf-date><conf-loc>Nevada, 
<country country="US">United States</country></conf-loc></conference></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-session">
<title-group>
<title>SLM Materials and Sructures</title>
<alt-title alt-title-type="conf-session-acronym"/></title-group></collection-meta>
<collection-meta collection-type="conf-proceedings-series">
<title-group>
<title>OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics Series</title></title-group>
<volume-in-collection>
<volume-number>14</volume-number>
<volume-title>TOPS Volume XIV</volume-title></volume-in-collection></collection-meta>
<book-meta>
<book-title-group>
<book-title>Spatial Light Modulators</book-title></book-title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Burdge</surname><given-names>Geoffrey</given-names></name></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="editor">
<name><surname>Esener</surname><given-names>Sadik C.</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group>
<pub-date publication-format="electronic">
<day>17</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>1997</year></pub-date></book-meta>
<book-part book-part-type="conf-paper">
<book-part-meta>
<title-group>
<title>Phase modulated liquid crystal spatial light modulator with VGA resolution</title></title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Sonehara</surname><given-names>Tomio</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref><xref rid="cor1" ref-type="corresp"><sup>*</sup></xref></contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name><surname>Amako</surname><given-names>Jun</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib>
<aff id="aff1">
<label>1</label>Corporate R&amp;D, Seiko Epson Corporation 3-3-5 Owa, Suwa, Nagano, 
<country country="JP">Japan</country> 392</aff></contrib-group>
<author-notes>
<corresp id="cor1">
<label>*</label>Tel: +81-266-52-3131, Fax: +81-266-58-9848, E-mail: <email>Sonehara.Tomio@exc.epson.co.jp</email></corresp></author-notes>
<elocation-id>165</elocation-id>
<permissions>
<copyright-statement>&#x000A9; 1997 Optical Society of America</copyright-statement>
<copyright-year>1997</copyright-year>
<copyright-holder>Optical Society of America</copyright-holder>
<license license-type="open-access">
<license-p>closed</license-p></license></permissions>
<abstract>
<p>A phase type VGA resolution LC-SLM was developed. The SLM is capable of easy operation with ordinay PCs and phase modulation more than 2&#x003C0;.</p></abstract>
<counts>
<book-page-count count="4"/></counts></book-part-meta>
<body>
<p>Introduction Phase type SLMs with real time operation are required for various kinds of applications. We have been developing liquid crystal SLMs and their applications for a decade. For examples are kinoform reconstruction &#x0005B;1&#x0005D;, complex amplitude modulators, which are called spatial wavefront modulators (SWMs) &#x0005B;2&#x0005D; and light valves for projection displays &#x0005B;3&#x0005D;. Following projector market expansion, poly- Silicon thin film transistor liquid crystal displays (poly-Si TFT-LCDs) have rapidly progressed with their resolution, VGA, SVGA and more, and pixel density. Even' fundamental SLM investigation, however, has been carried out with specialized SLMs and driving interface circuits. This is a barrier to the prevalence of the phase type SLMs to widely applicable fields. In this paper, we report a newly designed phase type SLM with VGA resolution, which accepts ordinary PC video outputs.</p>
<p>Device structure Figure 1 depicts the SLM appearance. It incorporates liquid crystal modulating pixels with poly-Si TFTs active matrix as switching elements, and integrated poly-Si TFT drivers on the same glass substrate. The poly-Si TFT technology has been developed for liquid crystal projectors, and then they are very reliable devices under strong illumination. A cross-section view of a pixel area is shown in Figure 2. Viewed from the bottom up, there is a quartz substrate and a TFT for a switching element, whose drain and source are fabricated on the substrate and gate is on the gate oxide, Fig. 1 Phase TFT-SLM with VGA resolution whose structure is called a co-planar structure. After that there is a non-doped Silicate glass (NSG) formation, and Aluminum source electrodes, X electrodes, are photo- patterned. Then a Phospho-Silicate glass (PSG) layer is deposited, and finally Indium Tin Oxide (ITO) of pixel is photo-patterned. Fig. 2 Typical cross-section view Figure 3 shows a typical plane view of a light shielding pattern. TFT. even when fabricated with poly-Silicon. will leak photo-current under UV light irradiation. To avoid leakage. the light shielding is usually employed on the counter substrate. In the case of strong light illumination. the light should enter from the side of the counter substrate. The shielding pattern decides aperture ratio and the diffraction characteristics, particularly efficiency. Usually- it is made of metal or pigment. in this case, we employed Chromium. Fig. 3 Typical light shielding pattern Although Smectic LC is usuall\ used for high speed switching. we incorporated Nematic LC due to its stability and reliability. This is because LCs for active matrix require high resistivity. They show. however. low birefringence. Considering the ability for low driving voltage. we selected a relatively high birefringence LC mixture. whose value is An=O.166. In a simple theoretical calculation. 2t modulation requires more than 3.8gm LC thickness. and therefore we fabricated the panel with 4.5 im thickness. For the alignment of liquid crystal. homogeneous alignment has been used for electrically controlled birefringence. ECB. mode. Both substrates of the SLM in Figure 1 are rubbed in parallel along Y direction. The homogeneous LC alignment in Y direction is obtained accordingly.</p>
<p>Driving circuit Figure 4 is a newly designed driving circuit. The interface allows easy connection with PCs. To obtain accurate horizontal pixel alignments between data and actual positions. a phased lock loop (PLL) circuit is used. In Fig. 4. the polarity alternation circuit generatesa alternating driving waveform to avoid electro-chemical degradation of LC. "6 Video" means the video signals expanded into 6 phases to reduce clock frequency of the TFT drivers. In the level shift circuit. video signals are corrected according to gray level linearity. This treatment is called y-correction. Fig. 4 Driving circuit Phase modulation characteristics Figure 5 (a). (b). (c) shows phase modulation characteristics including the dependency on LC materials and wavelength. Video voltage indicates actual voltage applied to an individual LC pixel through a TFT element. Due to the high resistivity of LC material, the voltage may represent the effective voltage applied to LC layer. The modulation characteristics show birefringence as an uniaxial crystal under less than 1.5v. Application of over 5v. still does not saturate modulation. Since 5v is the limitation of the driving circuit. we can not utilize all the birefringence of LC. Modulation of more than 27 is attained in the cases of An=O.166 and wavelength less than 550nm. and wavelength less than 450nm for An=0.139 and 0.129. In addition. using the TFT driving method with analog video signals. continuos phase modulation. in other words "blazed grating". is easily obtained, and it can provide high diffraction efficiency. Fig.5(a)Phasemodulationcharacteristics Fig. 5(b) Phase modulation characteristics An=.139 at589nm Fig. 5 (c) Phase modulation characteristics An=0.126 at 589nm Calculations of phase modulation are carried out by transmissivitv measurements with cross Nicole configuration, whose setup is shown in Fig. 6. Fig. 6 Transmissivity measurement setup Transmissivity is given by T=Tsin(6/2) where 6=27 And/X. The calculation steps are explained in Fig. 7. Fig. 7 Phase calculation</p>
<p>Kinoform reconstruction we triedtomake kinoformreconstruction.\Wecombined the same basic 12 kinofori patterns reported beforel l &#x0005D; as shown in Figure 8. The basic pattern is computed using the iterative method. Thereby. 348x512 dots were used in this experiment. where VGA resolution was not utilized entirely. Fig. 8 Kinoforin pattern By using a He-Ne laser and a 800mm convex imaging lens. the images shown in Figure 9 are reconstructed. Speckle noise is well-suppressed and minus-order image is hardly observed. In this experiments. because we did not adopt the conjugation of lens function on the kinoform pattern. a residual zero-order spot remains- whose spot can be diminished with lens function. Fig. 9 Reconstructed images Diffraction efficiency is assumed to be a value close to the square of the SLM's aperture ratio. because phase distribution can be displayed with high fidelity. Hence. diffraction efficiency of about 40&#x00025; for the aperture ratio of 64&#x00025; is prospected. In this paper. we measured the phase modulation characteristics through transmissivity measurements to obtain accurate values corresponding to phase modulation. Direct fringe measurements with the interferometer presented previousl&#x0005B;11 show a good agreement with the transmissivitv method. We observed the improved kinoform image quality. whose clear lines and high contrast compared favorably to the previous results. This is because interference between pixels. e.g. speckle noise. is well suppressed due to an increase of modulating points and reduction of sampling errors on X scanning.</p>
<p>Current specifications and future prospects Specifications of the SLM are summarized in Table 1. The right row in Table I shows specifications for next generation 0.9" VGA. Pixel density of 42sm pitch for 1.3" and 23tm pitch for 0.9" has been realized. Deducing the specifications according to TFT-LCDs developments speed. wve may forecast a 10 im-order pixel pitch in the near future.</p>
<p>Conclusion LC-SLMs are essentially not capable of high speed switching compared to semiconductor base SLMs and optical cNstals. The LC-SLMs. hiowever, are easy to operate. reliable and capable of large pixel capacity based on LC technologies. e.g. active matrix. LC materials and fabricating technologies. On the basis of these technologies. we developed new ly designed SLM with VGA resolution that is east to operate through standard PC video outputs. The interface for the SLM is newly designed for accurate pixel alignments between data and actual positions. As for LC. by selecting an LC material and suitable panel configuration. phase modulation of more than 2x is obtained, and thereby kinoform images with high fidelity are reconstructed for the confirmation of accurate phase modulation. Acknowledgments The authors acknowledge H. Sakata and H. Horiguchi for their cooperation and the TFT division of Seiko Epson Corporation.</p></body>
<back>
<ref-list>
<ref id="r1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Amako</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sonehara</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Kinoform using ECB liquid crystal SLM</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Appl Opt</source> <volume>30</volume>, <fpage>4622</fpage>, (<year>1991</year>)<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/AO.30.004622</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Sonehara</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Miura</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Amako</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>Moving 3D CGH reconstruction using LC SWM</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>Japan Display</source> <volume>92</volume> <fpage>315</fpage> <year>1992</year></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="r3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Morozumi</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sonehara</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kamakura</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ono</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Aruga</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name></person-group>, &#x0201C;<article-title>LCD full-color video projector</article-title>,&#x0201D; <source>SID&#x02019;86</source>. <fpage>375</fpage> <year>1986</year></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></book-part></book-part-wrapper>
